[
    {
        "QuestionID": 1,
        "Question": "Your company intends to subscribe to an Azure support plan. \nThe support plan must allow for new support requests to be opened. \nWhich of the following are support plans that will allow this?\nA. Basic\nB. Developer\nC. Standard\nD. Professional Direct\nE. Premier",
        "Answer": "BCD",
        "Explanation": "All Azure support plans except for the Basic and the Premier plan allow for the opening of new support requests. The Basic plan offers only limited support for billing and subscription management issues and does not include technical support for services. Premier support plans are being phased out and are no longer available for new customers",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 2,
        "Question": "Your company has datacenters in Los Angeles and New York. The company has a Microsoft Azure subscription.\nYou are configuring the two datacenters as geo-clustered sites for site resiliency.\nYou need to recommend an Azure storage redundancy option.\nYou have the following data storage requirements:\n- Data must be stored on multiple nodes.\n- Data must be stored on nodes in separate geographic locations.\n- Data can be read from the secondary location as well as from the primary location\nWhich of the following Azure stored redundancy options should you recommend?\nA. Geo-redundant storage\nB. Read-only geo-redundant storage\nC. Zone-redundant storage\nD. Locally redundant storage",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Geo-redundant storage (with GRS or GZRS) replicates your data to another physical location in the secondary region to protect against regional outages.However, that data is available to be read only if the customer or Microsoft initiates a failover from the primary to secondary region. When you enable read access to the secondary region, your data is available to be read at all times, including in a situation where the primary region becomes unavailable. For read access to the secondary region, enable read-access geo-redundant storage (RA-GRS) or read-access geo-zone-redundant storage (RA-GZRS).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 3,
        "Question": "Your company's Azure subscription includes a Basic support plan. \nThey would like to request an assessment of an Azure environment's design from Microsoft. \nThis is, however, not supported by the existing plan. \nYou want to make sure that the company subscribes to a support plan that allows this functionality, while keeping expenses to a minimum. \nSolution: You recommend that the company subscribes to the Professional Direct support plan. Does the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal of keeping expenses to a minimum. The Professional Direct support plan is a higher-tier support plan that incurs additional costs compared to the Basic support plan. While the Professional Direct support plan does provide access to design assessments from Microsoft, it may not be the most cost-effective option for the company. It would be more appropriate to recommend a support plan that includes design assessments but still keeps expenses low, such as the Developer or Standard support plans.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 4,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Software as a Service (SaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal. Software as a Service (SaaS) is a cloud computing model where software applications are delivered over the internet. It typically refers to using web-based applications provided by a third-party vendor. However, in this scenario, the goal is to deploy Azure virtual machines, which is an Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) offering. With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. Therefore, the appropriate cloud deployment solution in this case would be Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), not Software as a Service (SaaS).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 5,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Platform as a Service (PaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Platform as a service refers to cloud computing services that supply an on-demand environment for developing, testing, delivering, and managing software applications. PaaS is designed to make it easier for developers to quickly create web or mobile apps, without worrying about setting up or managing the underlying infrastructure of servers, storage, network, and databases needed for development. However, in this scenario, the goal is to deploy Azure virtual machines, which is an Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) offering. With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 6,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 7,
        "Question": "Your developers have created 10 web applications that must be host on Azure.\nYou need to determine which Azure web tier plan to host the web apps. The web tier plan must meet the following requirements:\n- The web apps will use custom domains.\n- The web apps each require 10 GB of storage.\n- The web apps must each run in dedicated compute instances.\n- Load balancing between instances must be included.\n- Costs must be minimized.\nWhich web tier plan should you use?\nA. Standard\nB. Basic\nC. Free\nD. Shared",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Standard tier support Custom Domains, Disk Space of 50GB wich is more than enough for the requested plan, and as long as they want to run each web app in a dedicated instance, that means we need 10 dedicated instances for the 10 web apps with a load-balancing service between them, the basic plan only support up to 3 dedicated instances. Finally the Standard plan has the lowest cost compared to Premuim and Isolated pricing tiers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 8,
        "Question": "You are planning to migrate a company to Azure. Each of the company's numerous divisions will have an administrator in place to manage the Azure resources used by their respective division.\nYou want to make sure that the Azure deployment you employ allows for Azure to be segmented for the divisions, while keeping administrative effort to a minimum.\nSolution: You plan to make use of several Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) directories.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Active Directory (AAD) is Microsoft's cloud-based identity and access management service, helping organizations manage and secure access to applications and resources. Using multiple Azure Active Directory (AAD) instances increases complexity due to separate management, inconsistent security policies, difficulty in collaboration, and challenges in implementing single sign-on across directories.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 9,
        "Question": "Your developers have created a portal web app for users in the Miami branch office. The web app will be publicly accessible and used by the Miami users to retrieve customer and product information. The web app is currently running in an on-premises test environment.\nYou plan to host the web app on Azure.\nYou need to determine which Azure web tier plan to host the web app. The web tier plan must meet the following requirements:\n- The website will use the miami.weyland.com URL.\n- The website will be deployed to two instances.\n- SSL support must be included.\n- The website requires 12 GB of storage.\n- Costs must be minimized.\nWhich web tier plan should you use?\nA. Standard\nB. Basic\nC. Free\nD. Shared",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Free = 1 GB\nShared = 1 GB \nBasic = 10 GB \nStandard = 50 GB",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 10,
        "Question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the elastic expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal. There is no specific expenditure model called the \"elastic expenditure model\" in Azure. When migrating virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription, the appropriate expenditure model to consider is the \"pay-as-you-go\" or \"consumption-based\" model. This means that you will be billed based on the actual usage of Azure resources, such as virtual machines, storage, and networking, on an hourly or per-minute basis. Therefore, the correct solution would be to recommend the use of the \"pay-as-you-go\" expenditure model, not the \"elastic expenditure model.\"",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 11,
        "Question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the scalable expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "There is no such thing as a \"scalable expenditure model\" in Azure. The two expenditure models in Azure are pay-as-you-go and reserved instances. Pay-as-you-go is the default and most common expenditure model in Azure. It means you pay for resources you consume on an hourly or per-minute basis. It offers flexibility to scale resources up and down as needed. Reserved instances is an expenditure model where you commit to a one- or three-year term for a particular virtual machine instance type, size, and region. This commitment provides you with a discount compared to pay-as-you-go pricing. Since the question states that the company is planning to migrate all of their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription, the correct expenditure model is pay-as-you-go. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 12,
        "Question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the operational expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Operating expenditures are ongoing costs of doing business. Consuming cloud services in a pay-as-you-go model could qualify as an operating expenditure. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 13,
        "Question": "You are required to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nYou want to make sure that you are able to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics for the solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Azure Cosmos DB.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB is a globally distributed, multi-model database service optimized for managing schema-less data at a global scale, offering high availability and low latency. For deploying an AI solution that involves building, testing, and deploying predictive analytics, services like Azure Machine Learning or Azure Cognitive Services are more appropriate, as they are specifically designed for AI workloads, including predictive analytics.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 14,
        "Question": "Your company's Active Directory forest includes thousands of user accounts.\nYou have been informed that all network resources will be migrated to Azure. Thereafter, the on-premises data center will be retired.\nYou are required to employ a strategy that reduces the effect on users, once the planned migration has been completed.\nSolution: You plan to sync all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Syncing all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a common strategy to ensure a smooth migration to the cloud while minimizing the impact on users. This approach is often referred to as implementing a hybrid identity model. By syncing the user accounts to Azure AD using tools like Azure AD Connect, users can continue using their existing credentials to access cloud resources after the migration. This provides a seamless experience for users and reduces the disruption typically associated with migrations. Therefore, the solution of syncing Active Directory user accounts to Azure AD meets the goal of reducing the impact on users during the migration to Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 15,
        "Question": "You are required to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nYou want to make sure that you are able to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics for the solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Azure Machine Learning Studio.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Machine Learning Studio (classic) is a drag-and-drop tool you can use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 16,
        "Question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that the Azure API Management service be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure API Management is a service that helps create consistent and modern API gateways for existing back-end services. It does not provide a direct means to automate the creation of Azure resources. For automating resource creation, services like Azure Resource Manager templates, Azure Automation, or Azure DevOps would be more appropriate as they are designed to handle deployment and automation of resources on Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 17,
        "Question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that management groups be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Management groups are used to organize resources and manage access, policy, and compliance across multiple subscriptions, but they are not specifically designed for automatically creating Azure resources. Instead, consider using Azure Resource Manager templates (ARM templates) or Azure Blueprints for automating the creation and management of Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 18,
        "Question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that the Azure Resource Manager templates be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Using Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates is a highly effective strategy for automatically creating and managing Azure resources, especially when you have identical requirements for multiple business units. ARM templates allow you to define your infrastructure as code, specifying the resources, configurations, and relationships in a declarative manner. By creating ARM templates that represent the required resources, you can deploy them consistently across different business units while ensuring that the configurations are identical. This approach is efficient, repeatable, and scalable, making it a suitable solution for automating resource deployment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 19,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include two virtual machines and one availability zone in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure's SLA for Virtual Machines with a single instance is 99.5% availability. To achieve a guaranteed availability of 99.99%, you would need to deploy the application in an architecture that takes advantage of Azure's higher availability options, such as Availability Zones. For an SLA of 99.99%, deploying the application in at least two Availability Zones would be recommended. This would ensure that your application is highly available across separate physical locations, each with its own power, cooling, and networking, reducing the risk of a single point of failure. Simply deploying two virtual machines in a single Availability Zone would not achieve the desired level of availability.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 20,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include one virtual machine and two availability zones in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Deploying one virtual machine and two availability zones does not meet the goal of achieving a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. To achieve such a high level of availability, you typically need to distribute your application across multiple instances in multiple availability zones or sets.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 21,
        "Question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include two virtual machines and two availability zones in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Deploying one virtual machine and two availability zones does not meet the goal of achieving a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. To achieve such a high level of availability, you typically need to distribute your application across multiple instances in multiple availability zones or sets.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 22,
        "Question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Microsoft Managed Desktop.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Managed Desktop is not an appropriate solution for deploying and managing a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. Microsoft Managed Desktop is a service that provides managed Windows 10 devices for organizations, and it's not designed for managing virtual machines, especially with the frequency and diversity described in your scenario. For managing virtual machines in Azure, a more suitable solution would be to use Azure Automation or Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. These tools allow you to automate the deployment and management of virtual machines, including the creation, configuration, and deletion of resources. You can define your desired state in code, and these tools will handle the provisioning and management tasks, reducing administrative effort.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 23,
        "Question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Reserved Virtual Machines (VM) Instances.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Reserved Virtual Machine (VM) Instances are not the most suitable solution for deploying and managing a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis that are also removed during the same week. Reserved VM Instances are used to save costs by committing to a specific VM instance type for a one- or three-year term, which is not aligned with the short-term and frequent deployment and removal pattern described in your scenario. To reduce administrative effort for your specific use case, you might consider using Azure DevTest Labs. Azure DevTest Labs allows you to quickly create environments in Azure while managing costs by setting up policies for resource usage. You can create a lab that aligns with your requirements, including Windows Server and Ubuntu Linux VMs, and allow your developers to deploy and remove VMs easily in a controlled environment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 24,
        "Question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure DevTest Labs.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure DevTest Labs is a suitable Azure service for managing the deployment and lifecycle of custom virtual machines, especially when they need to be created and removed frequently, as in your scenario. With Azure DevTest Labs, you can create a lab environment where developers can quickly create and manage virtual machines for development and testing purposes. The lab management capabilities allow you to set up policies, quotas, and schedules, which can help reduce administrative effort and manage costs. By using Azure DevTest Labs, developers can easily deploy custom virtual machines with Windows Server 2016 and Ubuntu Linux as needed, and these VMs can be automatically cleaned up or removed at the end of the week. This approach streamlines the deployment and management process, ensuring that administrative effort is reduced while meeting the dynamic requirements of your developers. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 25,
        "Question": "Your company has virtual machines (VMs) hosted in Microsoft Azure. The VMs are located in a single Azure virtual network named VNet1.\nThe company has users that work remotely. The remote workers require access to the VMs on VNet1.\nYou need to provide access for the remote workers.\nWhat should you do?\nA. Configure a Site-to-Site (S2S) VPN.\nB. Configure a VNet-toVNet VPN.\nC. Configure a Point-to-Site (P2S) VPN.\nD. Configure DirectAccess on a Windows Server 2012 server VM.\nE. Configure a Multi-Site VPN",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "To provide remote workers with access to the virtual machines (VMs) in the Azure virtual network (VNet), you should configure a Point-to-Site (P2S) VPN. P2S VPN allows individual remote clients to securely connect to the Azure VNet over the internet using a VPN client installed on their computer. This enables the remote workers to access the resources within VNet as if they were connected directly to the virtual network.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 26,
        "Question": "You have been informed by your superiors of the company's intentions to automate server deployment to Azure. There is, however, some concern that administrative credentials could be uncovered during this process.\nYou are required to make sure that during the deployment, the administrative credentials are encrypted using a suitable Azure solution.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Information Protection.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Information Protection is primarily used for classifying, labeling, and protecting documents and emails containing sensitive information. It's not designed for encrypting administrative credentials during server deployment processes. For encrypting administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure, a more suitable solution would be to use Azure Key Vault. Azure Key Vault is a cloud service that allows you to safeguard cryptographic keys, certificates, and secrets used by cloud applications and services. You can store the administrative credentials securely in Azure Key Vault and retrieve them when needed during the deployment process. This ensures that the credentials are properly protected and managed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 27,
        "Question": "You have been informed by your superiors of the company's intentions to automate server deployment to Azure. There is, however, some concern that administrative credentials could be uncovered during this process.\nYou are required to make sure that during the deployment, the administrative credentials are encrypted using a suitable Azure solution.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "No, the recommended solution of Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) does not encrypt administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure. MFA is a solution that adds an additional layer of authentication to the login process, and it can help prevent unauthorized access to resources. To encrypt administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure, a better solution would be to use Azure Key Vault. Azure Key Vault is a cloud-based service that provides secure storage of keys, secrets, and certificates. By storing the administrative credentials in Azure Key Vault, they can be encrypted and protected from unauthorized access.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 28,
        "Question": "The company would like to develop a cloud solution by making use of Azure Government. \nAzure Government can only be used by certain types of clients to develop cloud solutions.\nWhich of the following are the types of customers that can make use of Azure Government in this situation? \nA. A government contractor from any country\nB. A government entity from any country\nC. A European government contractor\nD. A European government entity\nE. A US government contractor\nF. A US government entity",
        "Answer": "EF",
        "Explanation": "Azure Government is the mission-critical cloud, delivering breakthrough innovation to US government customers and their partners. Only US federal, state, local, and tribal governments and their partners have access to this dedicated instance.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEF"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 29,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) environment. Users occasionally connect to Azure AD via the Internet.\nYou have been tasked with making sure that users who connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address, are automatically encouraged to change passwords.\nSolution: You configure the use of Azure AD Identity Protection.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure AD Identity Protection is a comprehensive solution that helps you protect your organization's identities and detect and respond to potential identity-related risks. One of its features is the ability to configure risk-based policies. In this case, you can set up a risk-based policy that triggers a password change prompt for users when they connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address. This helps enhance security by encouraging users to change their passwords in case of suspicious activity.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 30,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) environment. Users occasionally connect to Azure AD via the Internet.\nYou have been tasked with making sure that users who connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address, are automatically encouraged to change passwords.\nSolution: You configure the use of Azure AD Privileged Identity Management.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure AD Privileged Identity Management (PIM) manages, controls, and monitors access within Azure AD, Azure, and other Microsoft Online Services. It's used for managing privileged accounts and doesn't directly handle password policies or enforce password changes based on IP address recognition. Instead, to meet the goal, you should consider using Azure AD Identity Protection, which can enforce risk-based conditional access policies that might prompt users for password changes if an unfamiliar sign-in is detected.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 31,
        "Question": "You are planning a strategy to deploy numerous web servers and database servers to Azure.\nThis strategy should allow for connection types between the web servers and database servers to be controlled.\nSolution: You include network security groups (NSGs) in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "You can use an Azure network security group to filter network traffic between Azure resources in an Azure virtual network. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources. For each rule, you can specify source and destination, port, and protocol",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 32,
        "Question": "You are planning a strategy to deploy numerous web servers and database servers to Azure.\nThis strategy should allow for connection types between the web servers and database servers to be controlled.\nSolution: You include a local network gateway in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "A local network gateway in Azure is typically used when you want to establish a connection between your Azure virtual network and an on-premises network or another network outside of Azure. It's not directly related to controlling connection types between web servers and database servers within the same Azure virtual network. To control the connection types between web servers and database servers in Azure, you would typically use Network Security Groups (NSGs), which allow you to define inbound and outbound traffic rules to control the flow of traffic between resources in a virtual network. You might also consider using Azure Firewall or Azure Application Gateway depending on your specific requirements.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 33,
        "Question": "Your company's Active Directory forest includes thousands of user accounts.\nYou have been informed that all network resources will be migrated to Azure. Thereafter, the on-premises data center will be retired.\nYou are required to employ a strategy that reduces the effect on users, once the planned migration has been completed.\nSolution: You plan to require Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Multi-factor authentication doesn't reduce the effect or have any kind of effect on this issue. MFA is used to verify the reinforce the security to identify a user, but it doesn't help at all in arranging the user's accounts",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 34,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides full control of the operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides the ability to scale the platform automatically. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides professional development services to continuously add features to custom applications. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "A PaaS solution does not provide access to the operating system. \nThe Azure Web Apps service provides an environment for you to host your web applications.\nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS.\n However, you have no direct access to the virtual machine, the operating system or IIS.\n\nA PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure does provide the ability to scale the platform automatically. This is known as autoscaling. \nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. \nAutoscaling means adding more load balanced virtual machines to host the web apps.\n\nPaaS provides a framework that developers can build upon to develop or customize cloud-based applications. \nPaaS development tools can cut the time it takes to code new apps with pre-coded application components built into the platform, such as workflow, directory services, security features, search and so on.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 35,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure provides flexibility between capital expenditure (CapEx) and operational expenditure (OpEx). (Y/N)\n- If you create two Azure VM that use the B2S size, each VM will always generate the same monthly costs. (Y/N)\n- When an Azure VM is stopped, you continue to pay storage costs associated to the VM. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Storage cost are separate. In Azure stopping VM and de-allocating / deleting VM is different. If you stop VM still you need storage space to store VM image and which will cost you. Cost is Azure have different meters so VM costly will be possibly different at end of month.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 36,
        "Question": "When you are implementing a SaaS solution, you are responsible for :\nA. configuring high availability\nB. defining scalability rules\nC. installing the SaaS solution\nD. configuring the SaaS solution",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "When implementing a SaaS solution, the provider of the SaaS solution is responsible for configuring high availability and defining scalability rules. The customer is responsible for configuring and using the SaaS solution, but not for installing it.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 37,
        "Question": "You have an on-premises network that contains several servers.\nYou plan to migrate all the servers to Azure.\nYou need to recommend a solution to ensure that some of the servers are available if a single Azure data center goes offline for an extended period.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. fault tolerance\nB. elasticity\nC. scalability\nD. low latency",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Fault tolerance is the ability of a system to continue to function in the event of a failure of some of its components.\nIn this question, you could have servers that are replicated across datacenters.\nAvailability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there are a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures.\nWith Availability Zones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your applications and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.\nReferences:",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 38,
        "Question": "An organisation that hosts its infrastructure [...] no longer requires a data center.\nA. in a private cloud\nB. in a hybrid cloud\nC. in the public cloud\nD. on a Hyper-V host",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "A private cloud is hosted in your datacenter. Therefore, you cannot close your datacenter if you are using a private cloud.\nA public cloud is hosted externally, for example, in Microsoft Azure. An organization that hosts its infrastructure in a public cloud can close its data center.\nPublic cloud is the most common deployment model. In this case, you have no local hardware to manage or \"keep up-to-date\" everything runs on your cloud provider's hardware.\nMicrosoft Azure is an example of a public cloud provider.\nIn a private cloud, you create a cloud environment in your own datacenter and provide self-service access to compute resources to users in your organization.\nThis offers a simulation of a public cloud to your users, but you remain completely responsible for the purchase and maintenance of the hardware and software services you provide.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 39,
        "Question": "What are two characteristics of the public cloud? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. dedicated hardware\nB. unsecured connections\nC. limited storage\nD. metered pricing\nE. self-service management",
        "Answer": "DE",
        "Explanation": "With the public cloud, you get pay-as-you-go pricing \u05d2\u20ac\" you pay only for what you use, no CapEx costs.\nWith the public cloud, you have self-service management. You are responsible for the deployment and configuration of the cloud resources such as virtual machines or web sites. The underlying hardware that hosts the cloud resources is managed by the cloud provider.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: You don't have dedicated hardware. The underlying hardware is shared so you could have multiple customers using cloud resources hosted on the same physical hardware.\nB: Connections to the public cloud are secure.\nC: Storage is not limited. You can have as much storage as you like.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 40,
        "Question": "When planning to migrate a public website to Azure, you must plan to :\nA. deploy a VPN\nB. pay monthly usage costs\nC. pay to transfer all the website data to Azure\nD. reduce the number of connections to the website",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "When migrating a public website to Azure, you need to plan for the pricing model that Azure provides. Azure charges for the usage of resources such as virtual machines, storage, and data transfer. Therefore, you need to plan to pay monthly usage costs for hosting the website on Azure. Deploying a VPN, paying to transfer all the website data to Azure, or reducing the number of connections to the website are not necessarily required for migrating a public website to Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 41,
        "Question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases are examples of Azure PaaS solutions. Therefore, this solution does meet the goal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 42,
        "Question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure virtual machines that have Microsoft SQL Server installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "VM installed with Azure SQL fall under IaaS user will have OS access.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 43,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYour company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure Storage accounts.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure App Service is a PaaS but Azure Storage accounts is not a service.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 44,
        "Question": "Your company hosts an accounting application named App1 that is used by all the customers of the company.\nApp1 has low usage during the first three weeks of each month and very high usage during the last week of each month.\nWhich benefit of Azure Cloud Services supports cost management for this type of usage pattern?\nA. high availability\nB. high latency\nC. elasticity\nD. load balancing",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Elasticity in this case is the ability to provide additional compute resource when needed and reduce the compute resource when not needed to reduce costs.\nAutoscaling is an example of elasticity.\nElastic computing is the ability to quickly expand or decrease computer processing, memory and storage resources to meet changing demands without worrying about capacity planning and engineering for peak usage. Typically controlled by system monitoring tools, elastic computing matches the amount of resources allocated to the amount of resources actually needed without disrupting operations. With cloud elasticity, a company avoids paying for unused capacity or idle resources and doesn't have to worry about investing in the purchase or maintenance of additional resources and equipment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 45,
        "Question": "You plan to migrate a web application to Azure. The web application is accessed by external users.\nYou need to recommend a cloud deployment solution to minimize the amount of administrative effort used to manage the web application.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. Software as a Service (SaaS)\nB. Platform as a Service (PaaS)\nC. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)\nD. Database as a Service (DaaS)",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The best option would be B. Platform as a Service (PaaS).\nPaaS provides a platform with a runtime environment for applications. It includes infrastructure, middleware, development tools, business intelligence (BI) services, database management systems, etc. The advantage of PaaS is that it allows developers to focus on coding the application without worrying about infrastructure management. This can significantly reduce the administrative effort needed to manage the web application.\nPlease note that while SaaS, IaaS, and DaaS also provide cloud services, they don\u2019t offer the same level of management ease for a web application as PaaS does. SaaS is typically end-user applications run by third-party providers. IaaS provides only the base infrastructure, and DaaS is specifically for databases.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 46,
        "Question": "Azure VM :\nA. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n\nAzure SQL Database :\nD. IaaS\nE. PaaS\nF. SaaS",
        "Answer": "AE",
        "Explanation": "Azure virtual machines are Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nInfrastructure as a Service is the most flexible category of cloud services. It aims to give you complete control over the hardware that runs your application (IT infrastructure servers and virtual machines (VMs), storage, networks, and operating systems). Instead of buying hardware, with IaaS, you rent it.\n\nAzure SQL databases are Platform as a Service (Paas).\nAzure SQL Database is a fully managed Platform as a Service (PaaS) Database Engine that handles most of the database management functions such as upgrading, patching, backups, and monitoring without user involvement. Azure SQL Database is always running on the latest stable version of SQL Server\nDatabase Engine and patched OS with 99.99% availability. PaaS capabilities that are built-in into Azure SQL database enable you to focus on the domain specific database administration and optimization activities that are critical for your business.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEF"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 47,
        "Question": "You have an on-premises network that contains 100 servers.\nYou need to recommend a solution that provides additional resources to your users. The solution must minimize capital and operational expenditure costs.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. a complete migration to the public cloud\nB. an additional data center\nC. a private cloud\nD. a hybrid cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Hybrid Cloud. \"additional resources\" is the keyword. The investment (capital expenditure) for the on-premises datacenter is already made. So continue to take advantage of it. But for additional resources it is interesting to dynamically scale in the public cloud.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 48,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- To achieve a hybrid cloud model, a company must always migrate from a private cloud model. (Y/N)\n- A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- In a public cloud model, only guest users at your company can access the resources in the cloud. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "No - It is not true that a company must always migrate from a private cloud model to implement a hybrid cloud. You could start with a public cloud and then combine that with an on-premise infrastructure to implement a hybrid cloud.\n\nYes - A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the public cloud. This is very common. When you need more capacity, rather than pay out for new on-premises infrastructure, you can configure a cloud environment and connect your on-premises network to the cloud environment by using a VPN.\n\nNo - It is not true that only guest users can access cloud resources. You can give anyone with an account in Azure Active Directory access to the cloud resources.\nThere are many authentication scenarios but a common one is to replicate your on-premises Active Directory accounts to Azure Active Directory and provide access to the Azure Active Directory accounts. Another commonly used authentication method is 'Federation' where authentication for access to cloud resources is passed to",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 49,
        "Question": "You plan to migrate several servers from an on-premises network to Azure.\nWhat is an advantage of using a public cloud service for the servers over an on-premises network?\nA. The public cloud is owned by the public, NOT a private corporation\nB. The public cloud is a crowd-sourcing solution that provides corporations with the ability to enhance the cloud\nC. All public cloud resources can be freely accessed by every member of the public\nD. The public cloud is a shared entity whereby multiple corporations each use a portion of the resources in the cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "The public cloud is a shared entity whereby multiple corporations each use a portion of the resources in the cloud. The hardware resources (servers, infrastructure etc.) are managed by the cloud provider. Multiple companies create resources such as virtual machines and virtual networks on the hardware resources.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: The public cloud is not owned by the public. In the case of Microsoft Azure, the cloud is owned by Microsoft.\nB: The public cloud is a not crowd-sourcing solution. In the case of Microsoft Azure, the cloud is owned by Microsoft.\nC: It is not true that public cloud resources can be freely accessed by every member of the public. You pay for a cloud subscription and create accounts for your users to access your cloud resources. No one can access your cloud resources until you create user accounts and provide the appropriate access permissions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 50,
        "Question": "Azure Site Recovery provides [\u2026] for virtual machines.\nA. fault tolerance\nB. disaster recovery\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Site Recovery helps ensure business continuity by keeping business apps and workloads running during outages. Site Recovery replicates workloads running on physical and virtual machines (VMs) from a primary site to a secondary location.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 51,
        "Question": "In which type of cloud model are all the hardware resources owned by a third-party and shared between multiple tenants?\nA. private\nB. hybrid\nC. public",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services and Google Cloud are three examples of public cloud services.\nMicrosoft, Amazon and Google own the hardware. The tenants are the customers who use the public cloud services.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 52,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is a desktop and application virtualization service that enables the use of a cloud-hosted version of Windows fron any location.\nA. An availability set\nB. Azure Spot Virtual Machines\nC. Azure Virtual Desktop \nD. Azure VM scale sets",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Virtual Desktop, formerly known as Windows Virtual Desktop, is a Microsoft Azure-based system for virtualizing its Windows operating systems, providing virtualized desktops and applications securely in the cloud. It is aimed at enterprise customers rather than at individual users.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 53,
        "Question": "You have 1,000 virtual machines hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou plan to migrate all the virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription.\nYou need to identify which expenditure model to use for the planned Azure solution.\nWhich expenditure model should you identify?\nA. operational\nB. elastic\nC. capital\nD. scalable",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The expenditure models are either CapEx or OpEx (Capital or Operational). CapEx is what you pay upfront, on prem, for servers, racks, cooling, security, the Datacenter itself. OpEx is what you pay to keep your infrastructure operational, like IT staff. In this case, when you move to the Cloud, what you identify in this case is the OpEx or Operational model. This is because you actually don't have CapEx on the Cloud (or at least you look to minimize CapEx) as you pay for the resources you use and not for the underlying hardware, security, cooling, etc that you will pay for in an On-Prem solution. That is why the right answer is (A) Operational. Elastic and Scalable are not expenditure models.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 54,
        "Question": "Match the Azure services benefits to the correct descriptions.\nA. Disaster recovery \nB. Fault tolerance\nC. Low latency\nD. Dynamic scalability\n1. A cloud service that remains available after a failure occurs\n2. A cloud service that can be recovered after a failure occurs \n3. A cloud service that performs quickly when demand increases\n4. A cloud service that can be accessed quickly from the internet",
        "Answer": "A2B1C4D3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Fault tolerance is the ability of a service to remain available after a failure of one of the components of the service. For example, a service running on multiple servers can withstand the failure of one of the servers.\nBox 2: Disaster recovery is the recovery of a service after a failure. For example, restoring a virtual machine from backup after a virtual machine failure.\nBox 3: Dynamic scalability is the ability for compute resources to be added to a service when the service is under heavy load. For example, in a virtual machine scale set, additional instances of the virtual machine are added when the existing virtual machines are under heavy load.\nBox 4: Latency is the time a service to respond to requests. For example, the time it takes for a web page to be returned from a web server. Low latency means low response time which means a quicker response.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 55,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- To implement a hybrid cloud model, a company must have an internal network. (Y/N)\n- A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the hybrid cloud. (Y/N)\n- In a public cloud model, only guest users at your company can access the resources in the cloud. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "A hybrid cloud could combine a public cloud and a private cloud running on-premises or on the edge. It could also combine a public cloud with another public cloud (a.k.a., multicloud).\nHybrid models are meant to allow an organization to mix and match environments and to choose what works best for the specific applications and data. For instance, hybrid solutions are popular with companies in highly regulated industries that have strict data privacy requirements for how they store, process, and interact with their data.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 56,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS provides full control of operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS provides additional memory to apps by changing pricing tiers. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS can automatically scale the number of instances. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "In Azure, increasing the memory allocated to a Platform as a Service (PaaS) solution, such as an Azure App Service, is typically not achieved by changing the pricing tier. Pricing tiers for PaaS services like Azure App Service primarily affect the CPU, storage, and other resource allocations, but not the memory.\nTo adjust the memory allocated to an Azure PaaS service, you typically need to choose a different service plan or instance size within the same pricing tier. Azure App Service plans, for example, come in various sizes, each with a specific combination of CPU, memory, and other resources. By selecting a different service plan or instance size, you can increase or decrease the memory available to your application.\nSo, while changing the pricing tier can affect the overall performance and resource allocation for a PaaS solution, including CPU and storage, adjusting the memory allocation typically involves selecting the right App Service Plan or instance size within the chosen tier.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 57,
        "Question": "Your company has an on-premises network that contains multiple servers.\nThe company plans to reduce the following administrative responsibilities:\n- Backing up application data\n- Replacing failed server hardware\n- Managing physical server security\n- Updating server operating systems\n- Managing permissions to shared documents\nThe company plans to migrate servers to Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to identify which administrative responsibilities will be eliminated after the planned migration.\nWhich two responsibilities should you identify? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Replacing failed server hardware\nB. Backing up application data\nC. Managing physical server security\nD. Updating server operating systems\nE. Managing permissions to shared documents",
        "Answer": "AC",
        "Explanation": "Azure virtual machines run on Hyper-V physical servers. The physical servers are owned and managed by Microsoft. As an Azure customer, you have no access to the physical servers. Microsoft manage the replacement of failed server hardware and the security of the physical servers so you don't need to.\nIncorrect Answers:\nB: Microsoft have no control over the applications you run on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that application data is backed up.\nD: Microsoft do not manage the operating systems you run on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that the operating systems are updated.\nE: Microsoft have no control over the shared folders you host on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that folder permissions are configured appropriately.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 58,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Pay-As-You-Go is an example of CapEx. (Y/N)\n- Paying electricity for your datacenter is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Deploying your own datacenter is an example of CapEx. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Azure Pay-As-You-Go is considered an operational expense (OpEx) because it's a variable cost depending on the services used. \nPaying for electricity is indeed an operating expense since it's a regular, ongoing cost of running your datacenter. \nDeploying your own datacenter involves substantial upfront investment in physical assets, making it a capital expenditure (CapEx).\nOpEx (Operating Expenses): Expenses related to the day-to-day functioning of a business, such as rent, utilities, and maintenance costs.\nCapEx (Capital Expenditures): Large investments in goods that will be used over the long term, such as purchasing machinery, buildings, or hardware.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 59,
        "Question": "You plan to provision Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) resources in Azure.\nWhich resource is an example of IaaS?\nA. an Azure web app\nB. an Azure virtual machine\nC. an Azure logic app\nD. an Azure SQL database",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "An Azure virtual machine is an example of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nAzure web app, Azure logic app and Azure SQL database are all examples of Platform as a Service (Paas).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 60,
        "Question": "To which cloud models can you deploy physical servers?\nA. private cloud and hybrid cloud only\nB. private cloud only\nC. private cloud, hybrid cloud and public cloud\nD. hybrid cloud only",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A private cloud is on-premises so you can deploy physical servers.\nA hybrid cloud is a mix of on-premise and public cloud resources. You can deploy physical servers on-premises.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 61,
        "Question": "Match the cloud model to the correct advantage.\nA. Hybrid Cloud\nB. Private Cloud\nC. Public Cloud\n1. No required capital expenditure\n2. Provides complete control over security\n3. Provides a choice to use on-premises or cloud-based resources",
        "Answer": "A3B2C1",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Public Cloud -\nWith a public cloud, there is no capital expenditure on server hardware etc. You only pay for cloud resources that you use as you use them.\n\nBox 2: Private Cloud -\nA private cloud exists on premises, so you have complete control over security.\n\nBox 3: Hybrid Cloud -\nA hybrid cloud is a mix of public cloud resources and on-premises resources. Therefore, you have a choice to use either.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 62,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A company can extend a private cloud by adding its own physical servers to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- To build a hybrid cloud, you must deploy resources to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- A private cloud must be disconnected from the internet. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou cannot add physical servers to the public cloud. You can only deploy virtual servers in the public cloud. You can extend a private cloud by deploying virtual servers in a public cloud. This would create a hybrid cloud.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nA hybrid cloud is a combination of a private cloud and public cloud. Therefore, to create a hybrid cloud, you must deploy resources to a public cloud.\n\nBox 3: No.\nIt is not true that a private cloud must be disconnected from the Internet. Private clouds can be and most commonly are connected to the Internet. \u05d2\u20acPrivate cloud\u05d2\u20ac means that the physical servers are managed by you. It does not mean that it is disconnected from the Internet.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 63,
        "Question": "You have 50 virtual machines hosted on-premises and 50 virtual machines hosted in Azure. The on-premises virtual machines and the Azure virtual machines connect to each other.\nWhich type of cloud model is this?\nA. hybrid\nB. private\nC. public",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A hybrid cloud is a mix of public cloud resources and on-premises resources. Therefore, you have a choice to use either.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 64,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azure provides full control of the operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azure can be provided with additionnal memory by changing the pricing tier. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azurecan be configured to automatically scale the number of instances based on demand. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nA PaaS solution does not provide access to the operating system. The Azure Web Apps service provides an environment for you to host your web applications.\nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. However, you have no direct access to the virtual machine, the operating system or IIS.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure does provide the ability to scale the platform automatically. This is known as autoscaling. Behind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. Autoscaling means adding more load balanced virtual machines to host the web apps.\nReferences:",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 65,
        "Question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create Azure virtual machines, Azure SQL databases, and Azure Storage accounts.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "N",
        "Explanation": "Remember, they want ONLY PaaS. As soon as you see VM, it's an IaaS, meaning the answer to this is no. Storage account is currently still debatable but since VM is included in the suggestions, the answer is immediately No",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 66,
        "Question": "Your company plans to deploy several custom applications to Azure. The applications will provide invoicing services to the customers of the company. Each application will have several prerequisite applications and services installed.\nYou need to recommend a cloud deployment solution for all the applications.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Software as a Service (SaaS)\nB. Platform as a Service (PaaS)\nC. Infrastructure as a Service (laaS)",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "I would recommend using Platform as a Service (PaaS) for deploying the custom applications to Azure. PaaS provides a platform for developers to build, test, and deploy custom applications without having to worry about managing the underlying infrastructure. This allows developers to focus on building and deploying their applications while Azure takes care of the infrastructure management.\n\n(SaaS) \u2013 These applications are delivered over the internet and you can start using them right away.\n(PaaS) \u2013 This service provides the platform needed to build your custom app and deploy them in your infrastructure.\n(IaaS) \u2013 In this service, you rent all the infrastructure required by your organization such as virtual servers, storage, operating systems, and more.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 67,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Building a data center infrastructure is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Monthly salaries for technical personnel are an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Leasing software is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nBuilding a data center infrastructure is capital expenditure, not operation expenditure.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nOpEx is ongoing costs (costs of operations) such as staff salaries.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nOpEx is ongoing costs (costs of operations) such as leasing software. If you purchased software as a one-off purchase, that would be CapEx, but leasing software is ongoing so it's OpEx.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 68,
        "Question": "Azure Cosmos DB is an example of a [\u2026] offering.\nA. PaaS\nB. IaaS\nC. serverless\nD. SaaS",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB falls under PaaS.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 69,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- With SaaS, you must apply software updates. (Y/N)\n- With IaaS, you must install the software that you want to use. (Y/N)\n- Azure Backup is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Azure Backup is considered a part of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS). It's a tool that provides backup services for data in Azure. While it does provide a service, it doesn't provide a platform for developing, running, or managing applications like Platform as a Service (PaaS) does. Instead, it provides infrastructure-level capabilities, which is characteristic of IaaS. So, Azure Backup is more accurately classified as IaaS.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 70,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can create a resource group inside of another resource group. (Y/N)\n- An Azure VM can be multiple resource group. (Y/N)\n- A resource group can contain resources from multiple Azure regions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Nested Resource Groups are not allowed\nOnly One Resource Group is Necessary\nA Resource Group can contain any Region Resources",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 71,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- SQL Server 2019 installed on an Azure VM is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Azure SQL DB is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Azure Cosmo DB is an example of SaaS. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "AVM - Iaas \nAzure Cosmos DB - Paas \nAzure SQL Database - Pass",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 72,
        "Question": "You can assign a [\u2026] to every Azure resource.\nA. blueprint\nB. lock\nC. policy\nD. service endpoint",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can assign a policy to any scope that you have access to, such as a management group, subscription, or resource group. However, you cannot assign a policy directly to an individual resource.\nYou can assign a lock on every Azure resource that you have access to. You can apply a lock at different levels of scope: subscription, resource group, or individual resource.\nSo, the right answer is \"Lock\"!",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 73,
        "Question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company's migration plan.\nWhat should you create?\nA. Azure virtual machines, Azure SQL databases, and Azure Storage accounts.\nB. an Azure App Service and Azure virtual machines that have Microsoft SQL Server installed.\nC. an Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases.\nD. Azure storage accounts and web server in Azure virtual machines.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "IaaS -> Azure Virtual Machine, Azure Storage Account\nPaaS -> Azure App service, Azure SQL Database, Azure Cosmos DB, Azure Synapse Analytics\nSaaS -> Outlook email, Calendar, Microsoft Office 365",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 74,
        "Question": "What does a customer provide in a software as a service (SaaS) model?\nA. application data\nB. data storage\nC. compute resources\nD. application software",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A. application data- Customer provide\nB. data storage- Third party provided\nC. compute resources- Third party provided\nD. application software- Third party provided",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 75,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Files is an example of IaaS. (Y/N)\n- A DNS server that runs on a VM is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Microsoft Intune is an example of SaaS. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Azure Files is a managed file storage service, which is typically considered a Platform as a Service (PaaS) offering. A DNS server running on a VM is closer to Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), as you manage the VM itself. Microsoft Intune, a cloud-based service in the enterprise mobility management (EMM) space, is indeed Software as a Service (SaaS), where customers use the software without managing the underlying infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 76,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Cloud Computing provides elastic scalability. (Y/N)\n- Customers can minimize CapEx by using a public cloud. (Y/N)\n- Cloud computing leverages virtualization to provide services to multiple customers simultaneously. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is YYY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 77,
        "Question": "What is the first stage in the Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework for Azure?\nA. Adopt the cloud.\nB. Make a plan.\nC. Ready your organization.\nD. Define your strategy.",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Remember SPRAGM : Strategy - Plan - Ready - Adopt - Govern - Manage ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 78,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A company can extend an internal network by adding its own physical servers to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- A private cloud must be disconnected from the internet. (Y/N)\n- Part of a hybrid cloud is the public cloud. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 79,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You must have physical servers to use cloud computing. (Y/N)\n- You must have internet connectivity to use cloud computing. (Y/N)\n- The costs to increase cloud computing capacity are less than the costs to increase the computing capacity of an on-premises datacenter. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NYY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 80,
        "Question": "Match the cloud model to the correct advantage.\nA. Agility\nB. Geo-Distribution\nC. Scalability\n1. Resources can be provisioned dynamically to meet demands.\n2. Applications and data can be deployed to multiple regions.\n3. Applications can be developed, tested, and launched rapidly.",
        "Answer": "A3B2C1",
        "Explanation": "Answer is A3B2C1.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 81,
        "Question": "Azure Recovery provides [\u2026] for VM.\nA. fault tolerance\nB. disaster recovery\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 82,
        "Question": "You plan to use Azure to host two apps named App1 and App2. The apps must meet the following requirements:\n- You must be able to modify the code of App1.\n- Administrative effort to manage the operating system of App1 must be minimized.\n- App2 must run interactively with the operating system of the server.\n\nA. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n\nApp1 and App2 ?",
        "Answer": "BA",
        "Explanation": "App1: You must be able to modify the code of App1, which implies a need for control over the operating system and software stack. Administrative effort to manage the operating system of App1 must be minimized, indicating a desire for platform management. Therefore, for App1, you should use Platform as a Service (PaaS). PaaS allows you to focus on your application code while abstracting away the underlying operating system management. \n\nApp2: App2 must run interactively with the operating system of the server, which implies that you need direct access to and control over the operating system. In this case, you should use Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS). IaaS provides virtual machines (VMs) where you have full control over the operating system and can run applications interactively with it.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 83,
        "Question": "You have an accounting application named App1 that uses a legacy database.\nYou plan to move App1 to the cloud.\nWhich service model should you use?\nA. platform as a service (PaaS)\nB. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nC. software as a service (SaaS)",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "App1 to the cloud is infrastructure as a service (IaaS). The reason for this is that IaaS allows you to have greater control over the operating system, networking, and other infrastructure components, which is important when you're working with legacy applications. With IaaS, you can still use your legacy database and other existing components, while taking advantage of the scalability and cost savings offered by cloud infrastructure. Platform as a service (PaaS) and software as a service (SaaS) are not ideal for legacy applications as they may require extensive modifications to the code or may not be compatible with the existing infrastructure. PaaS may be suitable if the application can be easily refactored or modernized to work on a new platform, while SaaS is most appropriate for applications where you don't have control over the underlying infrastructure or code.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 84,
        "Question": "When you are implementing a SaaS solution, you are responsible for :\nA. configuring high availability\nB. defining scalability rules\nC. installing the SaaS solution\nD. configuring the SaaS solution",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Software as a service (or SaaS) is a way of delivering applications over the Internet\u05d2\u20ac\"as a service. Instead of installing and maintaining software, you simply access it via the Internet, freeing yourself from complex software and hardware management.\nSaaS applications are sometimes called Web-based software, on-demand software, or hosted software. Whatever the name, SaaS applications run on a SaaS provider's servers. The provider manages access to the application, including security, availability, and performance.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 85,
        "Question": "An Azure web app that queries an on-premises Microsoft SQL server is an example of [\u2026] cloud.\nA. hybrid\nB. multi-vendor\nC. private\nD. public",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 86,
        "Question": "A Microsoft SQL Server database that is hosted in the cloud and has software updates managed by Azure in an example of [\u2026].\nA. DRaaS\nB. IaaS\nC. PaaS\nD. SaaS",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Platform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications. You purchase the resources you need from a cloud service provider on a pay- as-you-go basis and access them over a secure Internet connection.\nLike IaaS, PaaS includes infrastructure \"servers, storage, and networking\"but also middleware, development tools, business intelligence (BI) services, database management systems, and more.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 87,
        "Question": "Which cloud computing model includes on-premises and cloud-based resources?\nA. hybrid\nB. public\nC. private",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 88,
        "Question": "Autoscaling is an example of [\u2026].\nA. agility\nB. elasticity\nC. geo-distribution\nD. predictability",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Autoscaling takes advantage of the elasticity of cloud-hosted environments while easing management overhead. It reduces the need for an operator to continually monitor the performance of a system and make decisions about adding or removing resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 89,
        "Question": "[\u2026] supports synchronization between on-premises storage and Azure Storage.\nA. Azure Blob Storage\nB. Azure Files\nC. Azure Queue Storage\nD. Azure Table Storage",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 90,
        "Question": "Which term represents the ability to increase the computing capacity of a virtual machine by adding memory or CPUs?\nA. agility\nB. vertical scaling\nC. horizontal scaling\nD. elasticity",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Vertical scaling, also known as scale up and scale down, means increasing or decreasing virtual machine (VM) sizes in response to a workload. Compare this behavior with horizontal scaling, also referred to as scale out and scale in, where the number of VMs is altered depending on the workload.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 91,
        "Question": "What are two benefits of cloud computing? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. enables the rapid provisioning of resources\nB. has increased administrative complexity\nC. has the same configuration options as on-premises\nD. shifts capital expenditures (CAPEX) to operating expenditures (OPEX)",
        "Answer": "AD",
        "Explanation": "Azure allows you to build, deploy, and manage apps more quickly and easily without having to buy and/or maintain the underlying infrastructure.\nAzure provides flexibility between CapEx and OpEx\nCapital expenditures generate benefits over a long period. These expenditures are generally nonrecurring and result in the acquisition of permanent assets.\nBuilding an application could qualify as a capital expenditure. Example, Azure Reserved Instances (Azure RI) help Azure's most active customers save on long- term VM usage reserving VMs in advance at a discounted price by committing to a one or three-year benefits.\nOperating expenditures are ongoing costs of doing business. Consuming cloud services in a pay-as-you-go model could qualify as an operating expenditure.\nExample, you pay for a service or product as you use it i.e. pay-as-you-go pricing.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 92,
        "Question": "What is a feature of an Azure virtual network?\nA. resource cost analysis\nB. packet inspection\nC. geo-redundancy\nD. isolation and segmentation",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Virtual Network (VNet) is the fundamental building block for your private network in Azure. VNet enables many types of Azure resources, such as Azure Virtual Machines (VM), to securely communicate with each other, the internet, and on-premises networks. VNet is similar to a traditional network that you'd operate in your own data center, but brings with it additional benefits of Azure's infrastructure such as scale, availability, and isolation.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 93,
        "Question": "[\u2026] enables Azure resources to be deployed close to users.\nA. Elasticity\nB. Geo-distribution\nC. High-Availability\nD. Scalability",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Geo-distribution makes you deploy apps and data to regional datacenters around the globe that is close to your customer to ensure best performance.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 94,
        "Question": "A. Disaster recovery\nB. Geo-Distribution\nC. High Availability\nD. Scalability \n1. Increase the compute capacity of apps in the cloud\n2. Provide a continuous user experience with no apparent downtime\n3. Ensures that users always have the best experience by deploying apps to all the regions where there are users",
        "Answer": "B3C2D1",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B3C2D1.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 95,
        "Question": "Which cloud computing benefit provides continuous user access to a cloud-based application with minimal downtime?\nA. agility\nB. scalability\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Answer is D.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 96,
        "Question": "You need to identify the type of failure for which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure services.\nWhat should you identify?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "It seems that in these questions designed by Microsoft it always follows this thinking pattern:\nRegions > Zones > Data Center.\nWhen you see a question like this with the keyword Zone AUTOMATICALLY you think protecting or managing data centers!",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 97,
        "Question": "You plan to extend your company's network to Azure.\nThe network contains a VPN appliance that uses an IP address of 131.107.200.1.\nYou need to create an Azure resource that defines the VPN appliance in Azure.\nWhich Azure resource should you create?\nA. NAT gateways\nB. Application gateways\nC. Local network gateways\nD. Virtual network gateways\nE. On-premises Data Gateways\nF. Azure Data Box Gateway\nG. Azure Stack Edge / Data Box Gateway\nH. Web Application Firewall policies",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "A Local Network Gateway is an object in Azure that represents your on-premise VPN device. A Virtual Network Gateway is the VPN object at the Azure end of the VPN. A 'connection' is what connects the Local Network Gateway and the Virtual Network Gateway to bring up the VPN.\nThe local network gateway typically refers to your on-premises location. You give the site a name by which Azure can refer to it, then specify the IP address of the on-premises VPN device to which you will create a connection. You also specify the IP address prefixes that will be routed through the VPN gateway to the VPN device. The address prefixes you specify are the prefixes located on your on-premises network. If your on-premises network changes or you need to change the public IP address for the VPN device, you can easily update the values later.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFGH"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 98,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more resource groups.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Resource groups has never been a fault tolerance approach, resource groups are used to easy manage a group of resources.\nIt is a logical container for Azure resources. When you create a resource group, you specify which location to create the resource group in.\nHowever, when you create a virtual machine and place it in the resource group, the virtual machine can still be in a different location (different datacenter).\nTherefore, creating multiple resource groups, even if they are in separate datacenters does not ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 99,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to a scale set.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "This answer does not specify that the scale set will be configured across multiple data centers so this solution does not meet the goal.\nAzure virtual machine scale sets let you create and manage a group of load balanced VMs. The number of VM instances can automatically increase or decrease in response to demand or a defined schedule. Scale sets provide high availability to your applications, and allow you to centrally manage, configure, and update many VMs.\nVirtual machines in a scale set can be deployed across multiple update domains and fault domains to maximize availability and resilience to outages due to data center outages, and planned or unplanned maintenance events.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 100,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure subscription can be associated to multiple Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenants.. (Y/N)\n- You can change the Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant to which an Azure subscription is associated. (Y/N)\n- When an Azure subscription expires, the associated Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant is deleted automatically. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "An Azure AD tenant can have multiple subscriptions but an Azure subscription can only be associated with one Azure AD tenant.\n\nIf your subscription expires, you lose access to all the other resources associated with the subscription. However, the Azure AD directory remains in Azure. You can associate and manage the directory using a different Azure subscription.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 101,
        "Question": "Resource groups provide organizations with the ability to manage the compliance of Azure resources across multiple subscriptions.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. Management groups\nC. Azure policies\nD. Azure App Service plans",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "If your organization has many Azure subscriptions, you may need a way to efficiently manage access, policies, and compliance for those subscriptions. Management groups provide a governance scope above subscriptions. You organize subscriptions into management groups; the governance conditions you apply cascade by inheritance to all associated subscriptions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 102,
        "Question": "The company has several departments. All the Azure resources used by each department will be managed by a department administrator.\nWhat are two possible techniques to segment Azure for the departments? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. multiple subscriptions\nB. multiple Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) directories\nC. multiple regions\nD. multiple resource groups",
        "Answer": "AD",
        "Explanation": "An Azure subscription is a container for Azure resources. It is also a boundary for permissions to resources and for billing. You are charged monthly for all resources in a subscription. A single Azure tenant (Azure Active Directory) can contain multiple Azure subscriptions.\nA resource group is a container that holds related resources for an Azure solution. The resource group can include all the resources for the solution, or only those resources that you want to manage as a group.\nTo enable each department administrator to manage the Azure resources used by that department, you will need to create a separate subscription per department. You can then assign each department administrator as an administrator for the subscription to enable them to manage all resources in that subscription.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 103,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A single Microsoft account can be used to manage Azure multiple subscriptions. (Y/N)\n- Two Azure subscriptions can be merged into a single subscription. (Y/N)\n- A company can use resources from multiple subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nYou can use the same account to manage multiple subscriptions. You can create an additional subscription for your account in the Azure portal. You may want an additional subscription to avoid hitting subscription limits, to create separate environments for security, or to isolate data for compliance reasons.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou cannot merge two subscriptions into a single subscription. However, you can move some Azure resources from one subscription to another. You can also transfer ownership of a subscription and change the billing type for a subscription.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA company can have multiple subscriptions and store resources in the different subscriptions. However, a resource instance can exist in only one subscription.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 104,
        "Question": "You have several VM in an Azure subscription. You create a new subscription :\nA. The VM cannot be moved to the new subscription.\nB. The VM can be moved to the new subscription.\nC. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run all in the same resource group.\nD. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run Windows Server 2016.\n",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can move a VM and its associated resources to a different subscription by using the Azure portal.\nMoving between subscriptions can be handy if you originally created a VM in a personal subscription and now want to move it to your company's subscription to continue your work. You do not need to start the VM in order to move it and it should continue to run during the move.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 105,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment that contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou plan to implement a solution that enables the client computers on your on-premises network to communicate to the Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to recommend which Azure resources must be created for the planned solution.\nWhich two Azure resources should you include in the recommendation? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a virtual network gateway\nB. a load balancer\nC. an application gateway\nD. a virtual network\nE. a gateway subnet",
        "Answer": "AE",
        "Explanation": "Having a virtual network is necessary but not sufficient; You need a subnet to host you VPN Gateway which is called a gateway subnet.\nA gateway subnet is necessary AND sufficient, because if you want to create a gateway subnet you need to a VNet which is implied. so AE.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 106,
        "Question": "You attempt to create several managed Microsoft SQL Server instances in an Azure environment and receive a message that you must increase your Azure subscription limits.\nWhat should you do to increase the limits?\nA. Create a service health alert\nB. Upgrade your support plan\nC. Modify an Azure policy\nD. Create a new support request",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Many Azure resource have quote limits. The purpose of the quota limits is to help you control your Azure costs. However, it is common to require an increase to the default quota.\nYou can request a quota limit increase by opening a support request. In the support request, select 'Service and subscription limits (quotas)' for the Issue type, select your subscription and the service you want to increase the quota for. For this question, you would select 'SQL Database Managed Instance' as the quote type.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 107,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Each Azure subscription can contain multiple account administrators. (Y/N)\n- Each Azure subscription can be managed by using a Microsoft account only. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource group contains multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou can assign service administrators and co-administrators in the Azure Portal but there can only be one account administrator.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou need an Azure Active Directory account to manage a subscription, not a Microsoft account.\nAn account is created in the Azure Active Directory when you create the subscription. Further accounts can be created in the Azure Active Directory to manage the subscription.\n\nBox 3: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. However, resource groups do not contain subscriptions. Subscriptions contain resource groups.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 108,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Availability zones can be implemented in all Azure regions. (Y/N)\n- Only VM that run Windows Server can be created in availability zones. (Y/N)\n- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications to multiple regions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nNot all Azure regions support availability zones.\n\nBox 2: No -\nAvailability zones can be used with many Azure services, not just VMs.\n\nBox 3: No -\nAvailability Zones are unique physical locations within a single Azure region.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 109,
        "Question": "You plan to create an Azure virtual machine.\nYou need to identify which storage service must be used to store the unmanaged data disks of the virtual machine.\nA. Containers : Scalable, cost-effective for unstructured data.\nB. File shares : Serverless SMB files shares.\nC. Tables : Tabular data storage.\nD. Queues : Effectively scale apps according to traffic.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure containers are the backbone of the virtual disks platform for Azure IaaS. Both Azure OS and data disks are implemented as virtual disks where data is durably persisted in the Azure Storage platform and then delivered to the virtual machines for maximum performance. Azure Disks are persisted in Hyper-V VHD format and stored as a page blob in Azure Storage.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 110,
        "Question": "Your company plans to move several servers to Azure.\nThe company's compliance policy states that a server named FinServer must be on a separate network segment.\nYou are evaluating which Azure services can be used to meet the compliance policy requirements.\nWhich Azure solution should you recommend?\nA. a resource group for FinServer and another resource group for all the other servers\nB. a virtual network for FinServer and another virtual network for all the other servers\nC. a VPN for FinServer and a virtual network gateway for each other server\nD. one resource group for all the servers and a resource lock for FinServer",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure virtual networks provide the 'Isolation and segmentation' networking capability.\nNetworks in Azure are known as virtual networks. A virtual network can have multiple IP address spaces and multiple subnets. Azure automatically routes traffic between different subnets within a virtual network.\nThe question states that FinServer must be on a separate network segment. The only way to separate FinServer from the other servers in networking terms is to place the server in a different virtual network to the other servers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 111,
        "Question": "You plan to map a network drive from several computers that run Windows 10 to Azure Storage.\nYou need to create a storage solution in Azure for the planned mapped drive.\nWhat should you create?\nA. an Azure SQL database\nB. a virtual machine data disk\nC. a File service in a storage account\nD. a Blob service in a storage account",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Files is Microsoft's easy-to-use cloud file system. Azure file shares can be seamlessly used in Windows and Windows Server.\nTo use an Azure file share with Windows, you must either mount it, which means assigning it a drive letter or mount point path, or access it via its UNC path.\nUnlike other SMB shares you may have interacted with, such as those hosted on a Windows Server, Linux Samba server, or NAS device, Azure file shares do not currently support Kerberos authentication with your Active Directory (AD) or Azure Active Directory (AAD) identity, although this is a feature we are working on.\nInstead, you must access your Azure file share with the storage account key for the storage account containing your Azure file share. A storage account key is an administrator key for a storage account, including administrator permissions to all files and folders within the file share you're accessing, and for all file shares and other storage resources (blobs, queues, tables, etc) contained within your storage account.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 112,
        "Question": "You plan to implement an Azure database solution.\nYou need to implement a database solution that meets the following requirements:\n- Can add data concurrently from multiple regions\n- Can store JSON documents\nWhich database service should you deploy? To answer, select the appropriate service in the answer area.\nA. Azure Cosmos DB\nB. Azure Database for MySQL servers\nC. Azure Database for MariaDB servers\nD. SQL Data warehouses\nE. Azure Cache for Redis\nF. Data factories\nG. Virtual Clusters\nH. Elastic Job agents\nI. SQL databases\nJ. Azure Database for PostgreSQL servers\nK. SQL servers\nL. Azure Database Migration Services\nM. SQL Server stretch databases\nN. SQL elastic pools\nO. Managed databases\nP. SQL managed instances",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft's globally distributed, multi-model database service. With a click of a button, Cosmos DB enables you to elastically and independently scale throughput and storage across any number of Azure regions worldwide.\nAzure Cosmos DB is a great way to store unstructured and JSON data. Combined with Azure Functions, Cosmos DB makes storing data quick and easy with much less code than required for storing data in a relational database.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOP"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 113,
        "Question": "Your company plans to start using Azure and will migrate all its network resources to Azure.\nYou need to start the planning process by exploring Azure.\nWhat should you create first?\nA. a subscription\nB. a resource group\nC. a virtual network\nD. a management group",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The first thing you create in Azure is a subscription. You can think of an Azure subscription as an 'Azure account'. You get billed per subscription.\nA subscription is an agreement with Microsoft to use one or more Microsoft cloud platforms or services, for which charges accrue based on either a per-user license fee or on cloud-based resource consumption.\n- Microsoft's Software as a Service (SaaS)-based cloud offerings (Office 365, Intune/EMS, and Dynamics 365) charge per-user license fees.\n- Microsoft's Platform as a Service (PaaS) and Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) cloud offerings (Azure) charge based on cloud resource consumption.\nYou can also use a trial subscription, but the subscription expires after a specific amount of time or consumption charges. You can convert a trial subscription to a paid subscription.\nOrganizations can have multiple subscriptions for Microsoft's cloud offerings.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 114,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- All the Azure resources deployed to a resource group must use the same Azure region. (Y/N)\n- If you assign a tag to a resource group, all the Azure resources in that resource group are assigned to the same tag. (Y/N)\n- If you assign permissions for a user to manage a resource group, the user can manage all the Azure resources in that resource group. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure resources deployed to a single resource group can be located in different regions. The resource group only contains metadata about the resources it contains.\nWhen creating a resource group, you need to provide a location for that resource group. You may be wondering, \"Why does a resource group need a location?\nAnd, if the resources can have different locations than the resource group, why does the resource group location matter at all?\" The resource group stores metadata about the resources. When you specify a location for the resource group, you're specifying where that metadata is stored. For compliance reasons, you may need to ensure that your data is stored in a particular region.\n\nBox 2: No -\nTags for Resources are not inherited by default from their Resource Group\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA resource group can be used to scope access control for administrative actions. By default, permissions set at the resource level are inherited by the resources in the resource group.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 115,
        "Question": "Data that is stored in the Archive access tier of an Azure Storage account [\u2026].\nA. can be accessed at any time by using azcopy.exe.\nB. can only be read by using Azure Backup.\nC. must be restored before the data can be accessed.\nD. must be rehydrated before the data can be accessed.",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure storage offers different access tiers: hot, cool and archive.\nThe archive access tier has the lowest storage cost. But it has higher data retrieval costs compared to the hot and cool tiers. Data in the archive tier can take several hours to retrieve.\nWhile a blob is in archive storage, the blob data is offline and can't be read, overwritten, or modified. To read or download a blob in archive, you must first rehydrate it to an online tier.\nExample usage scenarios for the archive access tier include:\n- Long-term backup, secondary backup, and archival datasets\n- Original (raw) data that must be preserved, even after it has been processed into final usable form.\n- Compliance and archival data that needs to be stored for a long time and is hardly ever accessed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 116,
        "Question": "The application will run on an Azure virtual machine.\nYou need to recommend a deployment solution for the application. The solution must provide a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent.\nWhat is the minimum number of virtual machines and the minimum number of availability zones you should recommend for the deployment?\n- Minimum number of VM ? A. 1 B.2 C.3\n- Minimum number of availability zones ? A. 1 B.2 C.3",
        "Answer": "BB",
        "Explanation": "You need a minimum of two virtual machines with each one located in a different availability zone.\nAvailability Zones is a high-availability offering that protects your applications and data from datacenter failures. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there's a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures. Zone-redundant services replicate your applications and data across Availability Zones to protect from single-points-of-failure. With Availability\nZones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "AA"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 117,
        "Question": "Which Azure service should you use to collect events from multiple resources into a centralized repository?\nA. Azure Event Hubs\nB. Azure Analysis Services\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Stream Analytics",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Correlate events = Azure Log Analytics\nCollect events = Azure Event Hubs\n\nThe Azure service you should use to collect events from multiple resources into a centralized repository is A. Azure Event Hubs.\nAzure Event Hubs is specifically designed as a high-throughput, real-time event ingestion service that can collect events from multiple sources. It's built to handle massive streams of data sent by application or infrastructure components in real-time. This data can then be processed by analytics services or stored for later analysis.\nOn the other hand, C. Azure Monitor is more focused on collecting operational telemetry, such as performance metrics, activity logs, and diagnostics data, to monitor the health and performance of Azure services. While Azure Monitor does collect events in the form of logs and metrics, its PRIMARY USE is NOT as an event ingestion service but as a monitoring and alerting service. Azure Event Hubs is the better choice when the goal is to set up a large-scale, event-driven data pipeline\u200b\u200b.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 118,
        "Question": "An Availability Zone in Azure has physically separate locations [\u2026].\nA. accross two continents.\nB. within a single Azure region.\nC. within multiple Azure regions.\nD. within a single Azure datacenter.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Availability Zones is a high-availability offering that protects your applications and data from datacenter failures. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 119,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Data that is stored in an Azure Storage account automatically has at least three copies. (Y/N)\n- All data that is copied to an Azure Storage account is backed up automatically to another Azure data center. (Y/N)\n- An Azure Storage account can contain up to 2 TB of data and up to one million files. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nThere are different replication options available with a storage account. The 'minimum' replication option is Locally Redundant Storage (LRS). With LRS, data is replicated synchronously three times within the primary region.\n\nBox 2: No -\nData is not backed up automatically to another Azure Data Center although it can be depending on the replication option configured for the account. Locally\nRedundant Storage (LRS) is the default which maintains three copies of the data in the data center.\nGeo-redundant storage (GRS) has cross-regional replication to protect against regional outages. Data is replicated synchronously three times in the primary region, then replicated asynchronously to the secondary region.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThe limits are much higher than that. The current storage limit is 2 PB for US and Europe, and 500 TB for all other regions (including the UK) with no limit on the number of files.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 120,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- If you have Azure resources deployed to every region, you can implement availability zones in all the regions. (Y/N)\n- Only virtual machines that run Windows Server can be created in availability zones. (Y/N)\n- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications to multiple regions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "1- Not every region has multiple Availability Zone. Some regions may have only one Availability Zone.\n2- One can run both Linux and Windows virtual machines created in the availability zone.\n3- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications in the same region.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 121,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- North America is represented by a single Azure region. (Y/N)\n- Every Azure region has multiple datacenters. (Y/N)\n- Data transfers between Azure services located in different Azure regions are always free. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nNorth America has several Azure regions, including West US, Central US, South Central US, East Us, and Canada East.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nA region is a set of datacenters deployed within a latency-defined perimeter and connected through a dedicated regional low-latency network.\n\nBox 3: No -\nOutbound data transfer is charged at the normal rate and inbound data transfer is free.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 122,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more scale sets.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "N",
        "Explanation": "This answer does not specify that the scale set will be configured across multiple data centers so this solution does not meet the goal.\nAzure virtual machine scale sets let you create and manage a group of load balanced VMs. The number of VM instances can automatically increase or decrease in response to demand or a defined schedule. Scale sets provide high availability to your applications, and allow you to centrally manage, configure, and update many VMs.\nVirtual machines in a scale set can be deployed across multiple update domains and fault domains to maximize availability and resilience to outages due to data center outages, and planned or unplanned maintenance events.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 123,
        "Question": "You need to be notified when Microsoft plans to perform maintenance that can affect the resources deployed to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Monitor\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Azure Advisor\nD. Microsoft Trust Center",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Service Health provides a personalized view of the health of the Azure services and regions you're using. This is the best place to look for service impacting communications about outages, planned maintenance activities, and other health advisories because the authenticated Service Health experience knows which services and resources you currently use.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 124,
        "Question": "A. Azure Sphere\nB. IoT Central\nC. IoT Hub\n1. A software and hardware solution that provides communication and security features for IoT devices\n2. A fully managed software as a service (SaaS) solution to connect, monitor, and manage IoT devices at scale\n3. A managed service that provides bidirectional communication between IoT devices and Azure\n\n\n\n\n",
        "Answer": "A3B2C1",
        "Explanation": "hu(b) = (b)iderectional\n(c)entral = (c)onnect\n(s)phere = (s)ecurity",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 125,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A Windows Virtual Desktop session host can run Windows 10 only. (Y/N)\n- A Windows Virtual Desktop host pool that includes 20 session hosts supports a maximum of 20 simultaneous user connections. (Y/N)\n- Windows Virtual Desktop supports desktop and app virtualization. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "1. NO - Supported O/Ses are Windows 10 Enterprise multi-session or Windows 10 Enterprise, Windows 7 Enterprise, Windows Server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019.\n2. NO - For Max session limit, enter the maximum number of users you want load-balanced to a single session host\n3. YES- Via RemoteApps",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 126,
        "Question": "[\u2026] can calculate cost savibgs due to reduced electricity consumption as a result of migrating on-premises Microsoft SQL servers to Azure.\nA. The Azure Migrate: Server Assessment tool\nB. The Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator\nC. The Database Migrating Assistant\nD. The pricing calculator in Azure",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator is a free online tool that allows you to estimate the cost savings you can achieve by migrating your application workloads to Microsoft Azure. It helps you to evaluate potential cost savings if you migrate on-premises application workloads to Microsoft Azure by specifying the details of your existing infrastructure and various cost assumptions you want the tool to work with. You can then receive a report that shows on-premises costs compared to Microsoft Azure costs.\n\nHere are the reasons why the other options are incorrect:\nThe pricing calculator in Azure: It is an online tool that provides estimates of the cost of Azure products and services 5. While it can help you estimate the costs for Azure products and services, it is not specifically designed to calculate cost savings due to reduced electricity consumption as a result of migrating on-premises Microsoft SQL servers to Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 127,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure virtual machines from a datacenter failure. (Y/N)\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure virtual machines from a region failure. (Y/N)\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure managed disks from a datacenter failure. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there are a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures.\nWith Availability Zones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your applications and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 128,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure subscription can have multiple account administrators. (Y/N)\n- An Azure subscription can be managed by using a Microsoft account only. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource group can contain multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou can assign service administrators and co-administrators in the Azure Portal but there can only be one account administrator.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou need an Azure Active Directory account to manage a subscription, not a Microsoft account.\nAn account is created in the Azure Active Directory when you create the subscription. Further accounts can be created in the Azure Active Directory to manage the subscription.\n\nBox 3: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. However, resource groups do not contain subscriptions. Subscriptions contain resource groups.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 129,
        "Question": "A cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances is more [\u2026] than a service that supports a maximum of five instances.\nA. distributed\nB. scalable\nC. secure",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The correct answer is scalable.\nA cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances is more scalable than a service that supports a maximum of five instances. Scalability refers to the ability of a system to handle increased workload by adding resources to the system. In this case, a cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances can handle more workload than a service that supports a maximum of five instances, making it more scalable.\nHere are the reasons why the other options are incorrect:\nDistributed: A distributed system is one in which components are located on different networked computers and communicate and coordinate their actions by passing messages. While a cloud service can be distributed, the number of instances it supports does not determine whether it is distributed or not.\nSecure: Security refers to the measures taken to protect a system from unauthorized access or attack. While security is an important aspect of cloud services, the number of instances it supports does not determine whether it is secure or not.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 130,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- To use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD. (Y/N)\n- Users in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) are organized by using resource groups. (Y/N)\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) groups support dynamic membership rules. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "To use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD. Yes, this statement is true. To use Azure AD credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD.\nUsers in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) are organized by using resource groups. No, this statement is incorrect. Users in Azure AD is organized by using directories, domains, and organizational units (OUs).\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) groups support dynamic membership rules. Yes, this statement is true. Azure AD groups support dynamic membership rules that allow you to add or remove members based on user or device attributes.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 131,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines remain available if a single data center fails.\nWhat are two possible solutions? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nA. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more availability zones.\nB. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more resource groups.\nC. Deploy the virtual machines to a scale set.\nD. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more regions.",
        "Answer": "AD",
        "Explanation": "Answer is AD.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 132,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy 20 VM to an Azure environment. To ensure that a VM named VM1 cannot connect to the other VM, VM1 must [\u2026].\nA. be deployed to a separate VM\nB. run a different operating system than the other VMs\nC. be deployed to a separate resource group\nD. have 2 network interfaces",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure automatically routes traffic between subnets in a virtual network. Therefore, all virtual machines in a virtual network can connect to the other virtual machines in the same virtual network. Even if the virtual machines are on separate subnets within the virtual network, they can still communicate with each other.\nTo ensure that a virtual machine cannot connect to the other virtual machines, the virtual machine must be deployed to a separate virtual network.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 133,
        "Question": "A. Azure Cosmos DB\nB. Azure HDInsight\nC. Azure Synapse Analytics\n1. A fully managed data warehouse that has integral security at every level of scale at no extra cost.\n2. A globally distributed database that supports NoSQL.\n3. Managed Apache Hadoop clusters in the cloud that enable you to process massive amounts of data.",
        "Answer": "A2B3C1",
        "Explanation": "Azure synapse analytics = Warehouse\nAzure cosmos = even larger than the globe (global) : cosmos\nAzure HDInsight = HaDoop",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 134,
        "Question": "What is the most severe failure from which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure service?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 135,
        "Question": "What is the most severe failure from which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure service?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 136,
        "Question": "You need to purchase a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure subscriptions\nB. Azure Security Center\nC. Azure Marketplace\nD. Microsoft Store",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Marketplace is a digital marketplace that offers a wide range of third-party virtual appliances, including security appliances, that can be deployed to an Azure subscription.\nAzure subscriptions (option A) are used to manage access to Azure services and resources, and do not provide virtual appliances.\nAzure Security Center (option B) is a unified infrastructure security management system that provides advanced threat protection across hybrid cloud workloads. While it can help you identify and mitigate security risks, it does not offer third-party virtual appliances.\nMicrosoft Store (option D) is an online store that offers software applications, games, and other digital content for Windows devices. It does not offer third-party virtual appliances for Azure subscriptions.\nTherefore, the best option for purchasing a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription is C. Azure Marketplace.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 137,
        "Question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure Logic Apps\n1. Executes code and is always stateful\n2. Runs only in the cloud",
        "Answer": "A1B2",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Azure Functions -\nAzure Functions allows you to implement your system's logic into readily available blocks of code called \"functions\". Different functions can run anytime you need to respond to critical events.\nAzure Logic Apps can have multiple stateful and stateless workflows.\n\nBox 2: Azure Logic Apps -\nAzure Logic Apps is a cloud-based platform for creating and running automated workflows that integrate your apps, data, services, and systems.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "AB12"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 138,
        "Question": "A. Azure Blueprints\nB. Azure Policy\nC. Azure resource group\nD. Azure tags\n1. Restrict which VM types can be created in a subscrption\n2. Identify Azure resources that are associated with specific cost centers\n3. Deploy a complete Azure application environment including resources configuration and role assigments",
        "Answer": "A3D2B1",
        "Explanation": "Policy = Restrict\nTag = Identify\nBP = Deploy",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 139,
        "Question": "An Availability Zone in Azure has physically separate locations [\u2026].\nA. accross two continents.\nB. within a single Azure region.\nC. within multiple Azure regions.\nD. within a single Azure datacenter.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Box: within a single Azure region\nAzure availability zones are physically separate locations within each Azure region that are tolerant to local failures.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 140,
        "Question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure App Service\nC. Azure Virtual Machines\nD. Azure Container Instances\n1. Provide operating system virtualization\n2. Provide portable environment for virtualized applications\n3. Used to build, deploy, and scale web apps\n4. Provide a platform for serverless code",
        "Answer": "A4B3C1D2",
        "Explanation": "Easy to memorize, VM, CONTAINER = PART OF VM OS, APP = APP SERVICE , CODE = FUNCTION\n\nBox 1: Azure virtual machines -\nBox 2: Azure Container instances\nAzure Container Instances (ACI) is a managed service that allows you to run containers directly on the Microsoft Azure public cloud, without requiring the use of virtual machines (VMs).\nDevelop apps fast without managing virtual machines or having to learn new tools\u05d2\u20ac\"it's just your application, in a container, running in the cloud.\n\nBox 3: Azure App Service -\nAzure App Service is a fully managed platform for building web applications.\nApplications run and scale with ease on both Windows and Linux-based environments.\n\nBox 4: Azure Functions -\nAzure Functions (from Microsoft Azure) is a cloud-based serverless service that allows running event-triggered code in a scalable way without providing or managing infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 141,
        "Question": "You have several VM in an Azure subscription. You create a new subscription :\nA. The VM cannot be moved to the new subscription.\nB. The VM can be moved to the new subscription.\nC. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run all in the same resource group\nD. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run Windows Server 2019",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Box: The virtual machines can be moved to the new subscription.\nYou can move a VM and its associated resources to a different subscription by using the Azure portal.\nNote: Repeat the process below for each Resource Group containing the VMs.\n1. Go to the Azure portal to manage the resource group containing the VM to move. Search for and select Resource groups.\n2. Choose the resource group containing the VM that you would like to move.\n3. At the top of the page for the resource group, select Move and then select Move to another subscription. The Move resources page opens.\n4. Select each of the resources to move. In most cases, you should move all of the related resources that are listed.\n5. Select the Subscription where you want the VM to be moved.\n6. Select an existing Resource group, or enter a name to have a new resource group created.\n7. When you are done, select that you understand that new resource IDs will be created and that the new IDs will need to be used with the VM after it is moved, and",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 142,
        "Question": "You need to purchase a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure subscriptions\nB. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nC. Azure Marketplace\nD. Microsoft Store",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "You can access these enhanced network security features by using an Azure partner solution. You can find the most current Azure partner network security solutions by visiting the Azure Marketplace, and searching for \"security\" and \"network security.\"",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 143,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is a highly secure IoT solution that includes a microcontroller unit (MCU) and a customized operatring system.\nA. Azure Arc\nB. Azure IoT Central\nC. Azure IoT Hub\nD. Azure Sphere",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Arc is a hybrid cloud management solution that enables you to manage your servers, Kubernetes clusters, and applications across on-premises, multi-cloud, and edge environments from a single control plane.\nAzure IoT Central is an IoT application platform that simplifies the creation of IoT solutions. It enables you to connect, monitor, and manage your IoT devices at scale.\nAzure IoT Hub is a fully managed service that enables reliable and secure bidirectional communications between millions of IoT devices and an application back end.\nTherefore, the correct answer is Azure Sphere because it is the only option that includes a microcontroller unit (MCU) and a customized Linux operating system.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 144,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy a service to Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the service will be available if a datacenter fails.\nWhat should you use as part of the virtual machine deployment?\nA. availability sets\nB. proximity placement groups\nC. host groups\nD. availability zones",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure availability zones are physically separate locations within each Azure region that are tolerant to local failures. Failures can range from software and hardware failures to events such as earthquakes, floods, and fires. Tolerance to failures is achieved because of redundancy and logical isolation of Azure services. To ensure resiliency, a minimum of three separate availability zones are present in all availability zone-enabled regions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 145,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains resources in several regions.\nYou need to ensure that administrators can only create resources in those regions.\nWhat should you use?\nA. a read-only lock\nB. an Azure policy\nC. a management group\nD. a reservation",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Explanation: Azure Policy evaluates resources and actions in Azure by comparing the properties of those resources to business rules. These business rules, described in JSON format, are known as policy definitions. To simplify management, several business rules can be grouped together to form a policy initiative (sometimes called a policySet). Once your business rules have been formed, the policy definition or initiative is assigned to any scope of resources that Azure supports, such as management groups, subscriptions, resource groups, or individual resources. The assignment applies to all resources within the Resource Manager scope of that assignment. Subscopes can be excluded, if necessary. For more information, see Scope in Azure Policy.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 146,
        "Question": "An Azure region [\u2026].\nA. contains one or more data centers that are connected by using a low-latency network\nB. is found in each country where Microsoft has a subsidiary office\nC. can be found in every country in Europe and the Americas only\nD. contains one or more data center that are connected by using a high-latency network",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Box: contains one or more data centers that are connected by using a low-latency network.\nEach Azure region features datacenters deployed within a latency-defined perimeter. They're connected through a dedicated regional low-latency network. This design ensures that Azure services within any region offer the best possible performance and security.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 147,
        "Question": "You can use the Azure File Sync agent to sync on-premises data to an Azure [\u2026].\nA. blob container\nB. Data Lake Storage container\nC. file share\nD. queue",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The Azure File Sync agent enables data on a Windows Server to be synchronized with an Azure File share.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 148,
        "Question": "What is the function of a Site-to-Site VPN?\nA. provides a secure connection between a computer on a public network and the corporate network\nB. provides a dedicated private connection to Azure that does NOT travel over the internet\nC. provides a connection from an on-premises VPN device to an Azure VPN gateway",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "A Site-to-Site VPN gateway connection is used to connect your on-premises network to an Azure virtual network over an IPsec/IKE (IKEv1 or IKEv2) VPN tunnel.\nThis type of connection requires a VPN device located on-premises that has an externally facing public IP address assigned to it.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 149,
        "Question": "A. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n1. Azure App Service\n2. Azure VM\n3. Microsoft Dynamic 365",
        "Answer": "A2B1C3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Platform as a service (PaaS)\nAzure App Service is a fully managed platform for building web applications.\nPlatform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications.\nBox 2: Infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nWindows Azure Virtual Machines, an Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) offering in Windows Azure, was released back in 2012.\nBox 3: Software as a service (SaaS)\nDynamics 365 is a set of interconnected, modular Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) applications and services designed to both transform and enable your core customers, employees, and business activities.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 150,
        "Question": "A. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n1. A cloud-based file server\n2. A cloud-based accounting system\n3. A cloud-based service for custom apps",
        "Answer": "A1B3C2",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nAzure Files is a simple, secure, and serverless enterprise-grade cloud file shares.\nInfrastructure as a service (IaaS) is a type of cloud computing service that offers essential compute, storage, and networking resources on demand, on a pay-as- you-go basis.\nBox 2: Software as a service (SaaS)\nDynamics 365 is a set of interconnected, modular Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) applications and services designed to both transform and enable your core customers, employees, and business activities. It includes Dynamics 365 Finance: use the guided, rules-based chart of accounts and no-code configuration service to simplify regulatory reporting, electronic invoicing, and global payments.\nBox 3: Platform as a service (PaaS)\nPlatform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 151,
        "Question": "Which two services can you use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure Virtual Desktop\nB. Azure virtual machines\nC. Azure Functions\nD. Azure Container Instances\nE. Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)",
        "Answer": "DE",
        "Explanation": "Run Docker containers on-demand in a managed, serverless Azure environment. Azure Container Instances is a solution for any scenario that can operate in isolated containers, without orchestration. Run event-driven applications, quickly deploy from your container development pipelines, and run data processing and build jobs.\nYou can manage containers at scale with a fully managed Kubernetes container management and orchestration service that integrates with Azure Active\nDirectory.\nAzure Kubernetes Service is a robust and cost-effective container orchestration service that helps you to deploy and manage containerized applications in seconds where additional resources are assigned automatically without the headache of managing additional servers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 152,
        "Question": "When you need to delegate permissions to several Azure VM simultaneously, you must deploy the Azure VM [\u2026].\nA. to the same Azure region\nB. by using the same Azure Resource Manager template\nC. to the same resource group\nD. to the same availability zone\n",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "C. to the same resource group.\n\nThis is the correct answer because you can manage access control and permissions more efficiently by deploying Azure virtual machines to the same resource group. Azure allows you to apply RBAC (Role-Based Access Control) to resource groups, which means you can grant the same permissions to multiple virtual machines in the same resource group simultaneously. It simplifies the process of delegating permissions across multiple VMs.\n\nA. Deploying VMs to the same Azure region does not have any direct impact on the ability to delegate permissions. Regions define the physical location of data centers, not access control.\n\nB. Using the same Azure Resource Manager template is a method for deploying VMs with similar configurations but doesn't directly relate to managing permissions or access control.\n\nD. Deploying VMs to the same availability zone is a strategy for improving high availability and fault tolerance but doesn't inherently affect the delegation of permissions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 153,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more availability zones.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 154,
        "Question": "This question requires that you evaluate the underlined text to determine if it is correct.\nOne of the benefits of Azure SQL Data Warehouse is that high availability is built into the platform.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. automatic scaling\nC. data compression\nD. versioning",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Data Warehouse (now known as Azure Synapse Analytics) is a PaaS offering from Microsoft. As with all PaaS services from Microsoft, SQL Data\nWarehouse offers an availability SLA of 99.9%. Microsoft can offer 99.9% availability because it has high availability features built into the platform.\nReferences:",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 155,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more regions.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "2 or more AZ\n2 or more Region",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 156,
        "Question": "An Azure container instance is an example of an Azure [\u2026].\nA. compute service\nB. identify service\nC. networking service\nD. storage service",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The term compute refers to the hosting model for the computing resources that your application runs on. For Azure this include:\nAzure Container Instances. The fastest and simplest way to run a container in Azure, without having to provision any virtual machines and without having to adopt a higher-level service.\nNote, and also the following:\nAzure App Service. A managed service for hosting web apps, mobile app back ends, RESTful APIs, or automated business processes.\nAzure Spring Cloud. A managed service designed and optimized for hosting Spring Boot apps.\nAzure Kubernetes Service (AKS). A managed Kubernetes service for running containerized applications.\nAzure Batch. A managed service for running large-scale parallel and high-performance computing (HPC) applications\nAzure Functions. A managed FaaS service.\nAzure Service Fabric. A distributed systems platform that can run in many environments, including Azure or on premises.\nAzure Virtual machines. Deploy and manage VMs inside an Azure virtual network.\nAzure Container Apps. Deploy and manage VMs inside an Azure virtual network.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 157,
        "Question": "At which OSI layer does ExpressRoute operate?\nA. Layer 2\nB. Layer 3\nC. Layer 5\nD. Layer 7",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure ExpressRoute operates at Layer 3, the Network Layer, of the OSI model. \nThis layer is responsible for routing data packets across different networks, and ExpressRoute provides a dedicated, private connection between on-premises networks and Microsoft Azure data centers, bypassing the public internet. It facilitates enhanced network performance, reliability, and security for data transmission.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 158,
        "Question": "Application Insights is a feature of [\u2026].\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Application Gateway\nC. Azure Arc\nD. Azure Monitor",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Application Insights is a feature of Azure Monitor that provides extensible application performance management (APM) and monitoring for live web apps.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 159,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure resources can only access other resources in the same resource group. (Y/N)\n- If you delete a resource group, all the resources in the resource group will be deleted. (Y/N)\n- A resource group can contain resources from multiple Azure regions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nA resource can interact with resources in other resource groups.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nDeleting the resource group will remove the resource group as well as all the resources in that resource group. This can be useful for the management of resources. For example, a virtual machine has several components (the VM itself, virtual disks, network adapter etc.). By placing the VM in its own resource group, you can delete the VM along with all its associated components by deleting the resource group.\nAnother example is when creating a test environment. You could place the entire test environment (Network components, virtual machines etc.) in one resource group. You can then delete the entire test environment by deleting the resource group.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nResources from multiple different regions can be placed in a resource group. The resource group only contains metadata about the resources it contains.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 160,
        "Question": "You plan to store 20 TB of data in Azure. The data will be accessed infrequently and visualized by using Microsoft Power BI.\nYou need to recommend a storage solution for the data.\nWhich two solutions should you recommend? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure Data Lake\nB. Azure Cosmos DB\nC. Azure SQL Data Warehouse\nD. Azure SQL Database\nE. Azure Database for PostgreSQL",
        "Answer": "AC",
        "Explanation": "You can use Power BI to analyze and visualize data stored in Azure Data Lake and Azure SQL Data Warehouse.\nAzure Data Lake includes all of the capabilities required to make it easy for developers, data scientists and analysts to store data of any size and shape and at any speed, and do all types of processing and analytics across platforms and languages. It removes the complexities of ingesting and storing all your data while making it faster to get up and running with batch, streaming and interactive analytics. It also integrates seamlessly with operational stores and data warehouses so that you can extend current data applications.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 161,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment that contains 10 web apps. To which URL should you connect to manage all the Azure resources?\nHttps://[\u2026][\u2026].com\nA. admin.\nB. portal.\nC. www.\n1. azure.\n2. azurewebsites.\n3. microsoft.",
        "Answer": "B1",
        "Explanation": "The Azure portal is a web-based management interface where you can view and manage all your Azure resources in one unified hub, including web apps, databases, virtual machines, virtual networks, storage and Visual Studio team projects.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 162,
        "Question": "Arrange the storage account redundancy options from the least redundant to the most redundant. To answer, move all options from the list of options to the answer area and arrange them in the correct order.\nA. Zone-redundant storage (ZRS)\nB. Geo-redundant storage (GRS)\nC. Locally-redundant storage (LRS)",
        "Answer": "CAB",
        "Explanation": "Think\nLRS = datacenter\nZRS = Zone\nGRS = Geographical Region",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 163,
        "Question": "Azure Blob Storage [\u2026].\nA. data store for queuing and reliably delivering messages between applications\nB. file share that can be mapped as a network drive\nC. key/attribute store for non-relational, structured data\nD. storage service optimized for very large objects, such as video files and bitmaps",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "BLOB = Binary Large Object",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 164,
        "Question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure CLI tools installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nPowerShell can now be installed on Linux. However, the question states that the computer has Azure CLI tools, not PowerShell installed. Therefore, this solution does not meet the goal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 165,
        "Question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Chrome OS and uses Azure Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nWith the Azure Cloud Shell, you can run PowerShell cmdlets and scripts in a Web browser. You log in to the Azure Portal and select the Azure Cloud Shell option.\nThis will open a PowerShell session in the Web browser. The Azure Cloud Shell has the necessary Azure PowerShell module installed.\nNote: to run a PowerShell script in the Azure Cloud Shell, you need to change to the directory where the PowerShell script is stored.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 166,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can view the health of all the services in an Azure environment. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can create a rule to be alerted if an Azure service fails. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can prevent a service failure. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nAzure Service Health consists of three components: Azure Status, Azure Service Heath and Azure Resource Health.\nAzure service health provides a personalized view of the health of the Azure services and regions you're using. This is the best place to look for service impacting communications about outages, planned maintenance activities, and other health advisories because the authenticated Azure Service Health experience knows which services and resources you currently use.\nTo view the health of all other services available in Azure, you would use the Azure Status component of Azure Service Health. Azure status informs you of service outages in Azure on the Azure Status page. The page is a global view of the health of all Azure services across all Azure regions.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nThe best way to use Service Health is to set up Service Health alerts to notify you via your preferred communication channels when service issues, planned maintenance, or other changes may affect the Azure services and regions you use.\n\nBox 3: No -\nYou can use Resource Health to view the health of a virtual machine. However, you cannot use Resource Health to prevent a service failure affecting the virtual machine.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 167,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nAn Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs macOS and has PowerShell Core 6.0 installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 168,
        "Question": "You need to view a list of planned maintenance events that can affect the availability of an Azure subscription.\nA. Dashboard>Help+Support> Service Health",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "A"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 169,
        "Question": "A. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Cognitive Services\nC. Azure Application Insights\nD. Azure DevOps\n1. An integrated solution for the deployment of code\n2. A tool that provides guidance and recommandations to improve an Azure environment\n3. A simplified tool to build intelligent Artificial Intelligence applications\n4. Monitors web applications",
        "Answer": "A2B3C4D1",
        "Explanation": "DevOps = code deploy\nAdvisor = guidance\nCognitive = Intelligence\nInsight = Monitor\n\nBox 1: Azure DevOps.\nAzure DevOps is Microsoft's primary software development and deployment platform.\nDevOps influences the application lifecycle throughout its plan, develop, deliver and operate phases.\nBox 2: Azure Advisor.\nAdvisor is a personalized cloud consultant that helps you follow best practices to optimize your Azure deployments. It analyzes your resource configuration and usage telemetry and then recommends solutions that can help you improve the cost effectiveness, performance, high availability, and security of your Azure resources.\nBox 3: Azure Cognitive Services.\nAzure Cognitive Services are APIs, SDKs, and services available to help developers build intelligent applications without having direct AI or data science skills or knowledge. Azure Cognitive Services enable developers to easily add cognitive features into their applications. The goal of Azure Cognitive Services is to help developers create applications that can see, hear, speak, understand, and even begin to reason. The catalog of services within Azure Cognitive Services can be categorized into five main pillars - Vision, Speech, Language, Web Search, and Decision.\nBox 4. Azure Application Insights.\nAzure Application Insights detects and diagnoses anomalies in web apps.\nApplication Insights, a feature of Azure Monitor, is an extensible Application Performance Management (APM) service for developers and DevOps professionals.\nUse it to monitor your live applications. It will automatically detect performance anomalies, and includes powerful analytics tools to help you diagnose issues and to understand what users actually do with your app.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 170,
        "Question": "A. Azure HDInsight\nB. Azure Data Lake Analytics\nC. Azure SQL Synapse Analytics\nD. Azure SQL Database\n1. Azure HDInsight is an open-source framework for distributed processing and analysis of big data sets in clusters\n2. A cloud-based service that leverages massively parallel processing (MPP) to quickly run complex queries across petabytes of data in a relational database.\n3. Can run massively parallel data transformation and processing programs across petabytes of data.\n4. A managed relational cloud database service.",
        "Answer": "A4B3C2D1",
        "Explanation": "Relational: Sql\nMassive: Synapse\nMessive PetaByte: Lake\nOPenshource: Insight",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 171,
        "Question": "You need to identify which blades in the Azure portal must be used to perform the following tasks:\n- View security recommendations.\n- Monitor the health of Azure services.\n- Browse available virtual machine images.\nWhich blade should you identify for each task?\n\nA. Monitor\nB. Subscriptions\nC. Marketplace\nD. Advisor\n1. Monitor the health of Azure services.\n2. Browse available VM images.\n3. View security recommandations.",
        "Answer": "A1C2D3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure Monitor is used to monitor the health of Azure services.\nAzure Monitor maximizes the availability and performance of your applications and services by delivering a comprehensive solution for collecting, analyzing, and acting on telemetry from your cloud and on-premises environments. It helps you understand how your applications are performing and proactively identifies issues affecting them and the resources they depend on.\nBox 2:\nYou can browse available virtual machine images in the Azure Marketplace.\nAzure Marketplace provides access and information on solutions and services available from Microsoft and their partners. Customers can discover, try, or buy cloud software solutions built on or for Azure. The catalog of 8,000+ listings provides Azure building blocks, such as Virtual Machines (VMs), APIs, Azure apps,\nSolution Templates and managed applications, SaaS apps, containers, and consulting services.\nBox 3.\nAzure Advisor displays security recommendations.\nAzure Advisor provides you with a consistent, consolidated view of recommendations for all your Azure resources. It integrates with Azure Security Center to bring you security recommendations. You can get security recommendations from the Security tab on the Advisor dashboard.\nSecurity Center helps you prevent, detect, and respond to threats with increased visibility into and control over the security of your Azure resources. It periodically analyzes the security state of your Azure resources. When Security Center identifies potential security vulnerabilities, it creates recommendations. The recommendations guide you through the process of configuring the controls you need.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 172,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou have an Azure environment. You need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nSolution: You use Bash in Azure Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "With Azure Cloud Shell, you can create virtual machines using Bash or PowerShell.\nAzure Cloud Shell is an interactive, authenticated, browser-accessible shell for managing Azure resources. It provides the flexibility of choosing the shell experience that best suits the way you work, either Bash or PowerShell.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 173,
        "Question": "You have an on-premises application that sends email notifications automatically based on a rule.\nYou plan to migrate the application to Azure.\nYou need to recommend a serverless computing solution for the application.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. a web app\nB. a server image in Azure Marketplace\nC. a logic app\nD. an API app",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Logic Apps is a cloud service that helps you schedule, automate, and orchestrate tasks, business processes, and workflows when you need to integrate apps, data, systems, and services across enterprises or organizations. Logic Apps simplifies how you design and build scalable solutions for app integration, data integration, system integration, enterprise application integration (EAI), and business-to-business (B2B) communication, whether in the cloud, on premises, or both.\nFor example, here are just a few workloads you can automate with logic apps:\n- Process and route orders across on-premises systems and cloud services.\n- Send email notifications with Office 365 when events happen in various systems, apps, and services.\n- Move uploaded files from an SFTP or FTP server to Azure Storage.\n- Monitor tweets for a specific subject, analyze the sentiment, and create alerts or tasks for items that need review.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 174,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy a website to Azure. The website will be accessed by users worldwide and will host large video files.\nYou need to recommend which Azure feature must be used to provide the best video playback experience.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. an application gateway\nB. an Azure ExpressRoute circuit\nC. a content delivery network (CDN)\nD. an Azure Traffic Manager profile",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The question states that users are located worldwide and will be downloading large video files. The video playback experience would be improved if they can download the video from servers in the same region as the users. We can achieve this by using a content deliver network.\nA content delivery network (CDN) is a distributed network of servers that can efficiently deliver web content to users. CDNs store cached content on edge servers in point-of-presence (POP) locations that are close to end users, to minimize latency.\nAzure Content Delivery Network (CDN) offers developers a global solution for rapidly delivering high-bandwidth content to users by caching their content at strategically placed physical nodes across the world. Azure CDN can also accelerate dynamic content, which cannot be cached, by leveraging various network optimizations using CDN POPs. For example, route optimization to bypass Border Gateway Protocol (BGP).\nThe benefits of using Azure CDN to deliver web site assets include:\n- Better performance and improved user experience for end users, especially when using applications in which multiple round-trips are required to load content.\n- Large scaling to better handle instantaneous high loads, such as the start of a product launch event.\n- Distribution of user requests and serving of content directly from edge servers so that less traffic is sent to the origin server.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 175,
        "Question": "Your company plans to deploy several million sensors that will upload data to Azure.\nYou need to identify which Azure resources must be created to support the planned solution.\nWhich two Azure resources should you identify? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nA. Azure Data Lake\nB. Azure Queue storage\nC. Azure File Storage\nD. Azure IoT Hub\nE. Azure Notification Hubs",
        "Answer": "AD",
        "Explanation": "IoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.\nThere are two storage services IoT Hub can route messages to -- Azure Blob Storage and Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 (ADLS Gen2) accounts. Azure Data\nLake Storage accounts are hierarchical namespace-enabled storage accounts built on top of blob storage. Both of these use blobs for their storage.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 176,
        "Question": "You have an Azure web app.\nYou need to manage the settings of the web app from an iPhone.\nWhat are two Azure management tools that you can use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure CLI\nB. the Azure portal\nC. Azure Cloud Shell\nD. Windows PowerShell\nE. Azure Storage Explorer",
        "Answer": "BC",
        "Explanation": "The Azure portal is the web-based portal for managing Azure. Being web-based, you can use the Azure portal on an iPhone.\nAzure Cloud Shell is a web-based command line for managing Azure. You access the Azure Cloud Shell from the Azure portal. Being web-based, you can use the\nAzure Cloud Shell on an iPhone.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: Azure CLI can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.\nD: Windows PowerShell can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.\nE: Azure Storage Explorer is not used to manage Azure web apps.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 177,
        "Question": "Your company plans to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nWhat should the company use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions?\nA. Azure Logic Apps\nB. Azure Machine Learning Designer\nC. Azure Batch\nD. Azure Cosmos DB",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Machine Learning designer lets you visually connect datasets and modules on an interactive canvas to create machine learning models.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 178,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor can generate a list of Azure virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup. (Y/N)\n- If you implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor, your company's secure score will decrease. (Y/N)\n- To maintain Microsoft support, you must implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor within a period of 30 days. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Advisor does not generate a list of virtual machines that ARE protected by Azure Backup. Azure Advisor does however, generate a list of virtual that ARE\nNOT protected by Azure Backup. You can view a list of virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup by viewing the Protected Items in the Azure Recovery\nServices Vault.\n\nBox 2: No -\nIf you implement the security recommendations, you company's score will increase, not decrease.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThere is no requirement to implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor. The recommendations are just that, 'recommendations'. They are not 'requirements'.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 179,
        "Question": "What can you use to automatically send an alert if an administrator stops an Azure virtual machine?\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Network Watcher",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Monitor is correct answer.\n\nAzure Service Health provides the health/status of Azure service.\n\nAzure Monitor - Provides Health/Status of your application using insights and logs",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 180,
        "Question": "A. Azure Machine Learning\nB. Azure Synapse Analytics\nC. Azure IoT Hub\nD. Azure Functions\n1. Provides a cloud-based Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW)\n2. Uses past training  to provide predictions that have high probability\n3. Provides serverless computing functionalities\n4. Processes data from millions of sensors",
        "Answer": "A2B1C4D3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Azure SQL Synapse Analytics\nAzure SQL Synapse Analytics (previously called Data Warehouse) is a cloud-based Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) offering from Microsoft. It is a large-scale, distributed, MPP (massively parallel processing) relational database technology in the same class of competitors as Amazon Redshift or Snowflake. Azure SQL\nSynapse Analytics is an important component of the Modern Data Warehouse multi-platform architecture. Because Azure SQL Synapse Analytics is an MPP system with a shared-nothing architecture across distributions, it is meant for large-scale analytical workloads which can take advantage of parallelism.\nBox 2:\nAzure Machine Learning uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\nMachine learning is a data science technique that allows computers to use existing data to forecast future behaviors, outcomes, and trends. By using machine learning, computers learn without being explicitly programmed.\nForecasts or predictions from machine learning can make apps and devices smarter. For example, when you shop online, machine learning helps recommend other products you might want based on what you've bought.\nBox 3:\nAzure Functions provides serverless computing functionalities.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.\nBox 4:\nIoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 181,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment.\nYou need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nWhat are three possible solutions? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Use Bash in Azure Cloud Shell.\nB. Use PowerShell in Azure Cloud Shell.\nC. Use the PowerApps portal.\nD. Use the Security & Compliance admin center.\nE. Use the Azure portal.",
        "Answer": "ABE",
        "Explanation": "The Android tablet device will have a web browser (Chrome). That's enough to connect to the Azure portal.\nThe Azure portal offers three ways to create a VM:\n- Using the graphical portal.\n- Using the Azure Cloud Shell using Bash.\n- Using the Azure Cloud Shell using PowerShell.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 182,
        "Question": "A team of developers at your company plans to deploy, and then remove, 50 virtual machines each week. All the virtual machines are configured by using Azure\nResource Manager templates.\nYou need to recommend which Azure service will minimize the administrative effort required to deploy and remove the virtual machines.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Azure Reserved Virtual Machine (VM) Instances\nB. Azure DevTest Labs\nC. Azure virtual machine scale sets\nD. Azure Virtual Desktop",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "DevTest Labs creates labs consisting of pre-configured bases or Azure Resource Manager templates.\nBy using DevTest Labs, you can test the latest versions of your applications by doing the following tasks:\n- Quickly provision Windows and Linux environments by using reusable templates and artifacts.\n- Easily integrate your deployment pipeline with DevTest Labs to provision on-demand environments.\n- Scale up your load testing by provisioning multiple test agents and create pre-provisioned environments for training and demos.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 183,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor can generate a list of Azure virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup. (Y/N)\n- If you implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor, your company's secure score will decrease. (Y/N)\n- To maintain Microsoft support, you must implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor within a period of 30 days. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Advisor provides you with a consistent, consolidated view of recommendations for all your Azure resources. It integrates with Azure Security Center to bring you security recommendations. You can get security recommendations from the Security tab on the Advisor dashboard. Examples of recommendations include restricting access to virtual machines by configuring Network Security Groups, enabling storage encryption, installing vulnerability assessment solutions.\nHowever, Azure Advisor does not provide recommendations on how to improve the security of an Azure AD environment.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAdvisor helps you optimize and reduce your overall Azure spend by identifying idle and underutilized resources. You can get cost recommendations from the Cost tab on the Advisor dashboard.\nBox 3: No.\nAzure Advisor does not provide recommendations on how to configure network settings on Azure virtual machines.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 184,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS --generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From the Azure portal, launch Azure Cloud Shell and select PowerShell. Run the command in Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The command can be run in the Azure Cloud Shell. Although this question says you select PowerShell rather than Bash, the Az commands will work in\nPowerShell.\nThe Azure Cloud Shell is a free interactive shell. It has common Azure tools preinstalled and configured to use with your account.\nTo open the Cloud Shell, just select Try it from the upper right corner of a code block. You can also launch Cloud Shell in a separate browser tab by going to",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 185,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS\n--generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From a computer that runs Windows 10, install Azure CLI. From PowerShell, sign in to Azure and then run the command.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The command can be run from PowerShell or the command prompt if you have the Azure CLI installed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 186,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS\n--generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From a computer that runs Windows 10, install Azure CLI. From a command prompt, sign in to Azure and then run the command.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The command can be run from PowerShell or the command prompt if you have the Azure CLI installed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 187,
        "Question": "Several support engineers plan to manage Azure by using the computers shown in the following table.\nYou need to identify which Azure management tools can be used from each computer.\nWhat should you identify for each computer? To answer, select the appropriate options in the answer area.\n- Computer1 : Windows 10\n- Computer2: Ubuntu\n- Computer3: MacOS Mojave\nA. The Azure CLI and the Azure portal\nB. The Azure portal and Azure Powershell\nC. The Azure CLI and Azure Powershell\nD. The Azure CLI, the Azure portal and Azure Powershell\n\n",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Previously, the Azure CLI (or x-plat CLI) was the only option for managing Azure subscriptions and resources from the command-line on Linux and macOS. Now with the open source and cross-platform release of PowerShell, you'll be able to manage all your Azure resources from Windows, Linux and macOS using your tool of choice, either the Azure CLI or Azure PowerShell cmdlets.\nThe Azure portal runs in a web browser so can be used in either operating system.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 188,
        "Question": "You can access Compliance Manager from the [\u2026].\nA. Azure Active Directory admin center\nB. Azure portal\nC. Microsoft 365 admin center\nD. Microsoft Service Trust portal",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Go to the Microsoft Purview compliance portal and sign in with your Microsoft 365 global administrator account.\nSelect Compliance Manager on the left navigation pane. You'll arrive at your Compliance Manager dashboard.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 189,
        "Question": "[\u2026] a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the Azure environment.\nA. Azure policy provide\nB. Resource groups provide\nC. Azure Resource Manager templates\nD. Management groups provide",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Resource Manager templates provides a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the\nAzure environment.\nAzure policies are used to define rules for what can be deployed and how it should be deployed. Whilst this can help in ensuring consistency, Azure policies do not provide the common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 190,
        "Question": "A. Azure Machine Learning\nB. Azure IoT Hub\nC. Azure Bot Services\nD. Azure Functions\n1.Provides a digital online assistant that provides speech support.\n2.Uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\n3.Provides serverless computing functionalities.\n4. Processes data from millions of sensors.",
        "Answer": "A2B4C1D3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure Bot Services provides a digital online assistant that provides speech support.\nBots provide an experience that feels less like using a computer and more like dealing with a person - or at least an intelligent robot. They can be used to shift simple, repetitive tasks, such as taking a dinner reservation or gathering profile information, on to automated systems that may no longer require direct human intervention. Users converse with a bot using text, interactive cards, and speech. A bot interaction can be a quick question and answer, or it can be a sophisticated conversation that intelligently provides access to services.\nBox 2:\nAzure Machine Learning uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\nMachine learning is a data science technique that allows computers to use existing data to forecast future behaviors, outcomes, and trends. By using machine learning, computers learn without being explicitly programmed.\nForecasts or predictions from machine learning can make apps and devices smarter. For example, when you shop online, machine learning helps recommend other products you might want based on what you've bought.\nBox 3:\nAzure Functions provides serverless computing functionalities.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.\nBox 4:\nIoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD4"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 191,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nAn Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Windows 10 and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nIn this question, the computer has the Azure PowerShell module installed. Therefore, this solution does meet the goal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 192,
        "Question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure App Service\nC. Azure Virtual Machines\nD. Azure Container Instances\n1. Provide operating system virtualization\n2. Provide portable environment for virtualized applications\n3. Used to build, deploy, and scale web apps\n4. Provide a platform for serverless code",
        "Answer": "A4B3C1D2",
        "Explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure virtual machines provide operation system virtualization.\nAzure Virtual Machines (VM) is one of several types of on-demand, scalable computing resources that Azure offers. Typically, you choose a VM when you need more control over the computing environment than the other choices offer.\nBox 2:\nAzure Container Instances provide portable environments for virtualized applications.\nContainers are becoming the preferred way to package, deploy, and manage cloud applications. Azure Container Instances offers the fastest and simplest way to run a container in Azure, without having to manage any virtual machines and without having to adopt a higher-level service.\nContainers offer significant startup benefits over virtual machines (VMs). Azure Container Instances can start containers in Azure in seconds, without the need to provision and manage VMs.\nBox 3:\nAzure App Service is used to build, deploy and scale web apps.\nAzure App Service is a platform-as-a-service (PaaS) offering that lets you create web and mobile apps for any platform or device and connect to data anywhere, in the cloud or on-premises. App Service includes the web and mobile capabilities that were previously delivered separately as Azure Websites and Azure Mobile\nServices.\nBox 4:\nAzure Functions provide a platform for serverless code.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 193,
        "Question": "Which service provides serverless computing in Azure?\nA. Azure Virtual Machines\nB. Azure Functions\nC. Azure storage account\nD. Azure dedicated hosts",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Functions provide a platform for serverless code.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 194,
        "Question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nWhich three computers can run the script? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a computer that runs macOS and has PowerShell Core 6.0 installed.\nB. a computer that runs Windows 10 and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nC. a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nD. a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure CLI tools installed.\nE. a computer that runs Chrome OS and uses Azure Cloud Shell.",
        "Answer": "BCE",
        "Explanation": "A: wrong, you need Azure Powershell Module, Powershell only isn't enoght\nB: correct, you have Powershell and the module to create Azure resources\nC: correct, you have Powershell and the module to create Azure resources\nD: wrong, with Azure CLI you don't execute Powershell script\nE: correct, from a browser you can connect to Azure Portal and execute Azure Powershell comdlet",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 195,
        "Question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS --generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From the Azure portal, launch Azure Cloud Shell and select Bash. Run the command in Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The answer is correct, the given command is a bash one, and Azure CLI accessed from the Azure cloud shell is the right approach to writing and running it.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 196,
        "Question": "Your company has several business units.\nEach business unit requires 20 different Azure resources for daily operation. All the business units require the same type of Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend a solution to automate the creation of the Azure resources.\nWhat should you include in the recommendations?\nA. Azure Resource Manager templates\nB. virtual machine scale sets\nC. the Azure API Management service\nD. management groups",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "You can use Azure Resource Manager templates to automate the creation of the Azure resources. Deploying resource through templates is known as\n'Infrastructure as code'.\nTo implement infrastructure as code for your Azure solutions, use Azure Resource Manager templates. The template is a JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) file that defines the infrastructure and configuration for your project. The template uses declarative syntax, which lets you state what you intend to deploy without having to write the sequence of programming commands to create it. In the template, you specify the resources to deploy and the properties for those resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 197,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view costs associated to management groups. (Y/N)\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view costs associated to resource groups. (Y/N)\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view the usage of virtual machines during the last three months. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Management groups also allow grouping subscriptions together, but offer a few key differences:\nManagement group access is inherited down to the subscriptions and resources.\nManagement groups can be layered into multiple levels and subscriptions can be placed at any level.\nManagement groups aren't included in cost details.\nAll historical costs are returned for management groups based on the subscriptions currently within that hierarchy. When a subscription moves, all historical cost moves.\nManagement groups are supported by Azure Policy and can have rules assigned to automate compliance reporting for your cost governance strategy.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 198,
        "Question": "What can you use to identify underutilized or unused Azure virtual machines?\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Cost Management + Billing\nC. Azure reservations\nD. Azure Policy",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Advisor helps you optimize and reduce your overall Azure spend by identifying idle and underutilized resources. You can get cost recommendations from the Cost tab on the Advisor dashboard.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 199,
        "Question": "Which node in the Azure portal should you use to assign a user the Reader role for a resource group? To answer, select the node in the answer area.\nA. Overview\nB. Activity log\nC. Access control (IAM)\nD. Tags\nE. Resource visualizer\nF. Events\nG. Resource costs\nH. Deployments\nI. Security\nJ. Policies\nK. Properties",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Identity Acces amnagement is the answer (IAM)",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFGHIJK"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 200,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is an Apache Spark-based analytics service.\nA. Azure Databricks\nB. Azure Data Factory\nC. Azure DevOps\nD. Azure Synapse Analytics",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based big data analytics service designed for data science and data engineering.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 201,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You must have internet connectivity to manage cloud services. (Y/N)\n- You must install a management app to manage cloud services. (Y/N)\n- You can manage cloud services from any modern web browser. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\n\nBox 2: No -\nCloud services can be managed through https://portal.azure.com/\nIn the Cloud Services area of the Azure portal, you can:\nUpdate a service role or a deployment.\nPromote a staged deployment to production.\nLink resources to your cloud service so that you can see the resource dependencies and scale the resources together.\nDelete a cloud service or a deployment.\n\nBox 3: Yes -",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 202,
        "Question": "A. Azure Databricks\nB. Azure Functions\nC. Azure App Service\nD. Azure Application Insights\n1. Provides the platform for serverless code\n2. A big data analysis service for machine learning\n3. Detects and diagnoses anomalies in web apps\n4. Hosts web apps",
        "Answer": "A2B1C4D3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure Functions provides the platform for serverless code.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.\nBox 2:\nAzure Databricks is a big analysis service for machine learning.\nAzure Databricks is an Apache Spark-based analytics platform. The platform consists of several components including 'MLib'. Mlib is a Machine Learning library consisting of common learning algorithms and utilities, including classification, regression, clustering, collaborative filtering, dimensionality reduction, as well as underlying optimization primitives.\nBox 3:\nAzure Application Insights detects and diagnoses anomalies in web apps.\nApplication Insights, a feature of Azure Monitor, is an extensible Application Performance Management (APM) service for developers and DevOps professionals.\nUse it to monitor your live applications. It will automatically detect performance anomalies, and includes powerful analytics tools to help you diagnose issues and to understand what users actually do with your app.\nBox 4:\nAzure App Service hosts web apps.\nAzure App Service is an HTTP-based service for hosting web applications, REST APIs, and mobile back ends. You can develop in your favorite language, be it\n.NET, .NET Core, Java, Ruby, Node.js, PHP, or Python. Applications run and scale with ease on both Windows and Linux-based environments.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 203,
        "Question": "A team of developers at your company plans to deploy, and then remove, 50 customized virtual machines each week. Thirty of the virtual machines run Windows\nServer 2016 and 20 of the virtual machines run Ubuntu Linux.\nYou need to recommend which Azure service will minimize the administrative effort required to deploy and remove the virtual machines.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Azure Reserved Virtual Machines (VM) Instances\nB. Azure virtual machine scale sets\nC. Azure DevTest Labs\nD. Microsoft Managed Desktop",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "DevTest Labs creates labs consisting of pre-configured bases or Azure Resource Manager templates.\nBy using DevTest Labs, you can test the latest versions of your applications by doing the following tasks:\n- Quickly provision Windows and Linux environments by using reusable templates and artifacts.\n- Easily integrate your deployment pipeline with DevTest Labs to provision on-demand environments.\n- Scale up your load testing by provisioning multiple test agents and create pre-provisioned environments for training and demos.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 204,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure PowerShell modules can be installed on macOS. (Y/N)\n- Azure Cloud Shell can be accessed from a web browser on a Linux computer. (Y/N)\n- The Azure portal can only be accessed from a Windows device. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "You can install the Az PowerShell module locally on Windows, macOS, and Linux. It can also be used from a browser through Azure Cloud Shell or inside a\nDocker container.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 205,
        "Question": "A support engineer plans to perform several Azure management tasks by using the Azure CLI.\nYou install the CLI on a computer.\nYou need to tell the support engineer which tools to use to run the CLI.\nWhich two tools should you instruct the support engineer to use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Command Prompt\nB. Azure Resource Explorer\nC. Windows PowerShell\nD. Windows Defender Firewall\nE. Network and Sharing Center",
        "Answer": "AC",
        "Explanation": "For Windows the Azure CLI is installed via an MSI, which gives you access to the CLI through the Windows Command Prompt (CMD) or PowerShell.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 206,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment. You need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nSolution: You use PowerShell in Azure Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Cloud Shell is a browser-based shell experience to manage and develop Azure resources.\nCloud Shell offers a browser-accessible, pre-configured shell experience for managing Azure resources without the overhead of installing, versioning, and maintaining a machine yourself.\nBeing browser-based, Azure Cloud Shell can be run on a browser from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 207,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment. You need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nSolution: You use the PowerApps portal.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "PowerApps lets you quickly build business applications with little or no code. It is not used to create Azure virtual machines. Therefore, this solution does not meet the goal.\nPowerApps Portals allow organizations to create websites which can be shared with users external to their organization either anonymously or through the login provider of their choice like LinkedIn, Microsoft Account, other commercial login providers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 208,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment. You need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nSolution: You use the Azure portal.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Azure portal is a web-based, unified console that provides an alternative to command-line tools. With the Azure portal, you can manage your Azure subscription using a graphical user interface. You can build, manage, and monitor everything from simple web apps to complex cloud deployments. Create custom dashboards for an organized view of resources. Configure accessibility options for an optimal experience.\nBeing web-based, the Azure portal can be run on a browser from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 209,
        "Question": "[\u2026] provides in-depth information about security, privacy, compliance offerings, policies, and features across Microsoft cloud products.\nA. The Microsoft 365 Compliance admin center\nB. The Microsoft 365 Defender portal\nC. Microsoft Defender for Cloud in the Azure portal\nD. Microsoft Trust Center",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft 365 compliance is now called Microsoft Purview and the solutions within the compliance area have been rebranded.\nWhen you first visit the compliance portal, the card section on the home page shows you at a glance how your organization is doing with data compliance, what solutions are available for your organization, and a summary of any active alerts.\nFrom here, you can:\n* Review the Microsoft Purview Compliance Manager card, which leads you to the Compliance Manager solution. Compliance Manager helps simplify the way you manage compliance.\n* Review the new Solution catalog card, which links to collections of integrated solutions you can use to help you manage end-to-end compliance scenarios. A solution's capabilities and tools might include a combination of policies, alerts, reports, and more.\n* Review the Active alerts card, which includes a summary of the most active alerts and includes a link where you can view more detailed information, such as\nSeverity, Status, Category, and more.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 210,
        "Question": "You can manage on-premises Windows server as an Azure resource by using [...].\nA. Azure Ad Connect\nB. Azure Arc\nC. an Azure Pipelines agent\nD. Azure VPN Gateway",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Arc simplifies governance and management by delivering a consistent multi-cloud and on-premises management platform.\nAzure Arc provides a centralized, unified way to:\nManage your entire environment together by projecting your existing non-Azure and/or on-premises resources into Azure Resource Manager.\nManage virtual machines, Kubernetes clusters, and databases as if they are running in Azure.\nEtc.\nIncorrect:\n* Why use Azure AD Connect?\nIntegrating your on-premises directories with Azure AD makes your users more productive by providing a common identity for accessing both cloud and on- premises resources. Users and organizations can take advantage of:\nUsers can use a single identity to access on-premises applications and cloud services such as Microsoft 365.\nSingle tool to provide an easy deployment experience for synchronization and sign-in.\nProvides the newest capabilities for your scenarios. Azure AD Connect replaces older versions of identity integration tools such as DirSync and Azure AD Sync.\n* VPN Gateway sends encrypted traffic between an Azure virtual network and an on-premises location over the public Internet. You can also use VPN Gateway to send encrypted traffic between Azure virtual networks over the Microsoft network. A VPN gateway is a specific type of virtual network gateway.\n* Pipeline agent is machine where your build is performed. An agent is installable software that runs one job at a time. Agent job is a set of steps which is recognized as execution boundary. Each job runs on an agent. All of the steps run together on the same agent.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 211,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can only manage cloud services from Windows devices. (Y/N)\n- You can manage cloud services from the command line. (Y/N)\n- You can manage cloud services by using a web browser. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nEasily manage your Azure storage accounts in the cloud, from Windows, macOS, or Linux, using Azure Storage Explorer.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAzure cloud services can be managed in Azure Automation by using the PowerShell cmdlets that are available in the Azure PowerShell tools.\n\nBox 3: Yes -",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 212,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is an Apache Spark-based analytics service.\nA. Azure Databricks\nB. Azure Data Factory\nC. Azure DevOps\nD. Azure Synapse Analytics",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based big data analytics service designed for data science and data engineering.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 213,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Monitor can monitor the performance of on-premises computers. (Y/N)\n- Azure Monitor can send alerts to Azure Active Directory security groups. (Y/N)\n- Azure Monitor can trigger alerts based on data in an Azure Log Analytics workspace. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nAzure Monitor maximizes the availability and performance of your applications and services by delivering a comprehensive solution for collecting, analyzing, and acting on telemetry from your cloud and on-premises environments.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAlerts in Azure Monitor proactively notify you of critical conditions and potentially attempt to take corrective action.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nAzure Monitor uses Target Resource, which is the scope and signals available for alerting. A target can be any Azure resource. Example targets: a virtual machine, a storage account, a virtual machine scale set, a Log Analytics workspace, or an Application Insights resource.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 214,
        "Question": "Which Azure service provides a set of version control tools to manage code?\nA. Azure Repos\nB. Azure DevTest Labs\nC. Azure Storage\nD. Azure Cosmos DB",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Repos is a set of version control tools that you can use to manage your code.\nIncorrect Answers:\nB: Azure DevTest Labs creates labs consisting of pre-configured bases or Azure Resource Manager templates. These have all the necessary tools and software that you can use to create environments.\nD: Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft's globally distributed, multi-model database service.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 215,
        "Question": "You need to manage Azure by using Azure Cloud Shell.\nWhich Azure portal icon should you select?\nA. >>_\nB. >_\nC. <_\nD. ><_",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can access Azure Cloud Shell in the Azure portal by clicking the icon.\nAzure Cloud Shell is an interactive, authenticated, browser-accessible shell for managing Azure resources. It provides the flexibility of choosing the shell experience that best suits the way you work, either Bash or PowerShell.\nCloud Shell enables access to a browser-based command-line experience built with Azure management tasks in mind.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 216,
        "Question": "You have a virtual machine named VM1 that runs Windows Server 2016. VM1 is in the East US Azure region.\nWhich Azure service should you use from the Azure portal to view service failure notifications that can affect the availability of VM1?\nA. Azure Service Fabric\nB. Azure Monitor\nC. Azure virtual machines\nD. Azure Advisor",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Virtual Machines (VMs) are primarily used for creating and hosting virtualized instances of Windows or Linux operating systems. They provide the infrastructure for running applications, services, and workloads in the Azure cloud. When you use Azure VMs, you are essentially provisioning and managing virtualized compute resources.\nOn the other hand, Azure Monitor is the Azure service focused on monitoring and managing the performance and health of your Azure resources, including Azure VMs. Azure Monitor provides various tools and features for collecting and analyzing telemetry data, setting up alerts, and gaining insights into the performance of your applications and infrastructure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 217,
        "Question": "Your Azure environment contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP.\nSolution: You modify an Azure Traffic Manager profile.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Traffic Manager is a DNS-based load balancing solution. It is not used to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over\nHTTP.\nTo ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP, you need to modify a network security group or Azure Firewall.\nIn this question, we need to add a rule to a network security group or Azure Firewall to allow the connection to the virtual machine on port 80 (HTTP).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 218,
        "Question": "Your company plans to deploy several web servers and several database servers to Azure.\nYou need to recommend an Azure solution to limit the types of connections from the web servers to the database servers.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. network security groups (NSGs)\nB. Azure Service Bus\nC. a local network gateway\nD. a route filter",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A network security group works like a firewall. You can attach a network security group to a virtual network and/or individual subnets within the virtual network.\nYou can also attach a network security group to a network interface assigned to a virtual machine. You can use multiple network security groups within a virtual network to restrict traffic between resources such as virtual machines and subnets.\nYou can filter network traffic to and from Azure resources in an Azure virtual network with a network security group. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 219,
        "Question": "[\u2026] you can view which user turned off a specific VM during the last 14 days.\nA. Azure Access Control IAM\nB. Azure Event Hub\nC. Azure Activity Log\nD. Azure Service Health",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "You would use the Azure Activity Log, not Access Control to view which user turned off a specific virtual machine during the last 14 days.\nActivity logs are kept for 90 days. You can query for any range of dates, as long as the starting date isn't more than 90 days in the past.\nIn this question, we would create a filter to display shutdown operations on the virtual machine in the last 14 days.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 220,
        "Question": "Which service provides network traffic filtering across multiple Azure subscriptions and virtual networks?\nA. Azure Firewall\nB. an application security group\nC. Azure DDoS protection\nD. a network security group (NSG)",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "You can restrict traffic to multiple virtual networks in multiple subscriptions with a single Azure firewall.\nAzure Firewall is a managed, cloud-based network security service that protects your Azure Virtual Network resources. It's a fully stateful firewall as a service with built-in high availability and unrestricted cloud scalability.\nYou can centrally create, enforce, and log application and network connectivity policies across subscriptions and virtual networks. Azure Firewall uses a static public IP address for your virtual network resources allowing outside firewalls to identify traffic originating from your virtual network.\nReferences:",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 221,
        "Question": "Which Azure service should you use to store certificates?\nA. Azure Security Center\nB. an Azure Storage account\nC. Azure Key Vault\nD. Azure Information Protection",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Key Vault is a secure store for storage various types of sensitive information including passwords and certificates.\nAzure Key Vault can be used to Securely store and tightly control access to tokens, passwords, certificates, API keys, and other secrets.\nSecrets and keys are safeguarded by Azure, using industry-standard algorithms, key lengths, and hardware security modules (HSMs). The HSMs used are\nFederal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 140-2 Level 2 validated.\nAccess to a key vault requires proper authentication and authorization before a caller (user or application) can get access. Authentication establishes the identity of the caller, while authorization determines the operations that they are allowed to perform.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 222,
        "Question": "Which Azure service can you use as a security information and event management (SIEM) solution?\nA. Azure Analysis Services\nB. Azure Sentinel\nC. Azure Information Protection\nD. Azure Cognitive Services",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Can be remembered as \"SIEMtinel\" ;)",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 223,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Sentinel stores collected events in an Azure Storage account. (Y/N)\n- Azure Sentinel can remediate incidents automatically. (Y/N)\n- Azure Sentinel can collect Windows Defender Firewall logs from Azure virtual machines. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Yes, Azure Sentinel can store collected events in an Azure Storage account. Azure Sentinel is a cloud-native security information and event management (SIEM) solution provided by Microsoft. It enables organizations to collect, analyze, and respond to security events and incidents across their environment.\nAzure Sentinel can ingest data from various sources, including logs and events from Azure services, on-premises infrastructure, and third-party systems. The collected events can be stored in an Azure Storage account, which provides a scalable and durable storage solution for the data. This allows organizations to retain and analyze security event data over a longer period of time, as required by their compliance or investigative needs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 224,
        "Question": "A. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nB. Azure Key Vault\nC. Azure Lighthouse\nD. Azure Security Center\nE. Azure Sentinel\n1. Analyse security log from Azure VM\n2. Display the secure score for an Azure Subscription\n3. Store passwords for use by Azure Function applications",
        "Answer": "E1D2B3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Azure Sentinel -\n\nBox 2: Azure Security Center -\n\nBox 3: Azure Key Vault -\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nAzure AD is an identity and access management service, which helps your employees sign in and access resources\n- Azure Lighthouse\nAzure Lighthouse is used for cross- and multi-tenant management.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCDE123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 225,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Firewall will encrypt all the network traffic sent from Azure to the Internet. (Y/N)\n- A network security group (NSG) will encrypt all the network traffic sent from Azure to the Internet. (Y/N)\n- Azure virtual machines that run Windows Server 2016 can encrypt network traffic sent to the Internet. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure firewall does not encrypt network traffic. It is used to block or allow traffic based on source/destination IP address, source/destination ports and protocol.\n\nBox 2: No -\nA network security group does not encrypt network traffic. It works in a similar way to a firewall in that it is used to block or allow traffic based on source/ destination IP address, source/destination ports and protocol.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThe question is rather vague as it would depend on the configuration of the host on the Internet. Windows Server does come with a VPN client and it also supports other encryption methods such IPSec encryption or SSL/TLS so it could encrypt the traffic if the Internet host was configured to require or accept the encryption.\nHowever, the VM could not encrypt the traffic to an Internet host that is not configured to require the encryption.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 226,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Security Center can monitor Azure resources and on-premises resources. (Y/N)\n- All Azure Security Center features are free. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Security Center, you can download a Regulatory Compliance report. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nAzure Security Center is a unified infrastructure security management system that strengthens the security posture of your data centers, and provides advanced threat protection across your hybrid workloads in the cloud - whether they're in Azure or not - as well as on premises.\n\nBox 2: No -\nOnly two features: Continuous assessment and security recommendations, and Azure secure score, are free.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nThe advanced monitoring capabilities in Security Center also let you track and manage compliance and governance over time. The overall compliance provides you with a measure of how much your subscriptions are compliant with policies associated with your workload.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 227,
        "Question": "Layers :\nA. Perimeter\nB. Application\nC. Physical Security\n\n[\u2026]\nIdentity and Access\n[\u2026]\nNetwork\nCompute\n[\u2026]\nData",
        "Answer": "CAB",
        "Explanation": "* Data\n- In almost all cases attackers are after data.\n- Data can be in database, stored on disk inside VMs, on a SaaS application such as Office 365 or in cloud storage.\n- Those storing and controlling access to data to ensures that it's properly secured\n- Often regulatory requirements dictates controls & processes\n- to ensure confidentiality, integrity, and availability.\n\n* Application\n- Ensure applications are secure and free of vulnerabilities.\n- Store sensitive application secrets in a secure storage medium.\n- Make security a design requirement for all application development.\n- Integrate security into the application development life cycle.\n\n* Compute\n- Secure access to virtual machines.\n- Implement endpoint protection and keep systems patched and current.\n- Malware, unpatched systems, and improperly secured systems open your environment to attacks.\n\n* Networking\n- Limit communication between resources.\n- Deny by default.\n- Allow only what is required\n- Restrict inbound internet access and limit outbound, where appropriate.\n- Implement secure connectivity to on-premises networks.\n\n* Perimeter\n- Use distributed denial of service (DDoS) protection to filter large-scale attacks before they can cause a denial of service for end users.\n- Use perimeter firewalls to identify and alert on malicious attacks against your network\n\n* Identity and access\n- Control access to infrastructure and change control.\n- Access granted is only what is needed\n- Use single sign-on and multi-factor authentication.\n- Audit events and changes.\n\n* Physical security\n- Building security & controlling access to computing hardware.\n- First line of defense.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 228,
        "Question": "You have an Azure virtual machine named VM1.\nYou plan to encrypt VM1 by using Azure Disk Encryption.\nWhich Azure resource must you create first?\nA. an Azure Storage account\nB. an Azure Key Vault\nC. an Azure Information Protection policy\nD. an Encryption key",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Disk Encryption requires an Azure Key Vault to control and manage disk encryption keys and secrets.\n\nAzure Disk Encryption uses Azure Key Vault to manage the disk encryption keys and secrets. You must create an Azure Key Vault before you can encrypt an Azure virtual machine using Azure Disk Encryption. The Key Vault is used to store the encryption keys and secrets, and it provides a central location for managing and securing these keys. Once you have created the Key Vault, you can then enable disk encryption on the virtual machine and specify the Key Vault as the location for the encryption keys.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 229,
        "Question": "Which resources can be used as a source for a Network security group inbound security rule?\nA. Service Tags only\nB. IP Addresses, Service tags and Application security groups\nC. Application security groups only\nD. IP Addresses only",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Any, or an individual IP address, classless inter-domain routing (CIDR) block (10.0.0.0/24, for example), service tag, or application security group.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 230,
        "Question": "Azure Sentinel uses playbooks to [\u2026].\nA. automatically respond to threats.\nB. collect data from Azure services.\nC. specify how long data is retained.\nD. store passwords and certificates.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A playbook is a collection of these remediation actions that can be run from Microsoft Sentinel as a routine. A playbook can help automate and orchestrate your threat response; it can be run manually on-demand on entities (in preview - see below) and alerts, or set to run automatically in response to specific alerts or incidents, when triggered by an automation rule.\n\nFor example, if an account and machine are compromised, a playbook can isolate the machine from the network and block the account by the time the SOC team is notified of the incident.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 231,
        "Question": "[\u2026] in Azure Firewall enables users on the internet to access a server on a virtual network.\nA. Application rules\nB. Network Address Translation (NAT) rules\nC. Network rules\nD. Service tags",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Virtual Network NAT is a network address translation service running in Azure. With Azure Virtual Network NAT, you can provide secure outbound connectivity to virtual instances in a private subnet so they can connect outside your virtual network.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 232,
        "Question": "Azure distributed denial of service (DDoS) protection is an example of protection that is implemented at the [\u2026].\nA. application layer.\nB. compute layer.\nC. networking layer.\nD. perimeter layer.",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Use DDoS protection to filter large-scale attacks before they can affect the availability of a system for users.\nUse perimeter firewalls to identify and alert on malicious attacks against your network.\nAt the network perimeter, it's about protecting from network-based attacks against your resources. Identifying these attacks, eliminating their impact, and alerting you when they happen are important ways to keep your network secure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 233,
        "Question": "You have an Azure Sentinel workspace.\nYou need to automate responses to threats detected by Azure Sentinel.\nWhat should you use?\nA. adaptive network hardening in Azure Security Center\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Azure Monitor workbooks\nD. adaptive application controls in Azure Security Center",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Once you have connected your data sources to Microsoft Sentinel, you can visualize and monitor the data using the Microsoft Sentinel adoption of Azure Monitor Workbooks, which provides versatility in creating custom dashboards. While the Workbooks are displayed differently in Microsoft Sentinel, it may be useful for you to see how to create interactive reports with Azure Monitor Workbooks. Microsoft Sentinel allows you to create custom workbooks across your data, and also comes with built-in workbook templates to allow you to quickly gain insights across your data as soon as you connect a data source.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 234,
        "Question": "A. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nB. Azure Key Vault\nC. Azure Lighthouse\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nE. Microsoft Sentinel\n1. Provide security information event management (SIEM) functionnality \n2. Display the secure score for an Azure subsciption\n3. Store passwords for use by Azure Function applications",
        "Answer": "E1D2B3",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Microsoft Sentinel -\nMicrosoft Sentinel is a scalable, cloud-native, security information and event management (SIEM) and security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) solution. Microsoft Sentinel delivers intelligent security analytics and threat intelligence across the enterprise, providing a single solution for attack detection, threat visibility, proactive hunting, and threat response.\n\nBox 2: Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nYou can find your overall secure score, as well as your score per subscription, through the Azure portal. Defender for Cloud displays your secure score prominently in the portal.\n\nBox 3: Azure Key Vault -\nA favored approach to store the credentials or keys in the Azure Key Vault as secrets and reference the secrets as environment variables in our Azure functions apps.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCDE123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 235,
        "Question": "Which Azure service can you use as a security information and event management (SIEM) solution?\nA. Azure Analysis Services\nB. Microsoft Sentinel\nC. Azure Information Protection\nD. Azure Cognitive Services",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Can be remembered as \"SIEMtinel\" ;)",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 236,
        "Question": "An Azure Policy initiative definition is a [\u2026].\nA. collection of policy definitions.\nB. collection of Azure Policy definition assignments.\nC. group of Azure Blueprints definitions.\nD. group of role-based access control (RBAC) role assignments.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "An initiative definition is a collection of policy definitions that are grouped towards achieving a singular overarching goal. Initiative definitions simplify managing and assigning policy definitions by grouping them as a single assignable object",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 237,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription.\nYou need to review your secure score.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Monitor\nB. Azure Advisor\nC. Help + support\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "The central feature in Defender for Cloud that enables you to achieve those goals is secure score.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 238,
        "Question": "You can enable just in time (JIT) VM access by using [\u2026].\nA. Azure Bastion\nB. Azure Firewall\nC. Azure Front Door\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "The central feature in Defender for Cloud that enables you to achieve those goals is secure score.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 239,
        "Question": "You can view your company's regulatory compliance report from [\u2026]\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Analysis Services\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Defender for Cloud helps streamline the process for meeting regulatory compliance requirements, using the regulatory compliance dashboard. Defender for Cloud continuously assesses your hybrid cloud environment to analyze the risk factors according to the controls and best practices in the standards that you've applied to your subscriptions. The dashboard reflects the status of your compliance with these standards.\n\nWhen you enable Defender for Cloud on an Azure subscription, the Microsoft cloud security benchmark is automatically assigned to that subscription. This widely respected benchmark builds on the controls from the Center for Internet Security (CIS), PCI-DSS and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) with a focus on cloud-centric security.\n\nThe regulatory compliance dashboard shows the status of all the assessments within your environment for your chosen standards and regulations. As you act on the recommendations and reduce risk factors in your environment, your compliance posture improves.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 240,
        "Question": "You need to collect and automatically analyze security events from Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\nWhat should you use?\nA. Microsoft Sentinel\nB. Azure Synapse Analytics\nC. Azure AD Connect\nD. Azure Key Vault",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Sentinel is a scalable, cloud-native, security information and event management (SIEM) and security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) solution.\nMicrosoft Sentinel delivers intelligent security analytics and threat intelligence across the enterprise, providing a single solution for attack detection, threat visibility, proactive hunting, and threat response.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 241,
        "Question": " [\u2026] enables users to authentificate to multiple applications by using sigle sign-on (SSO).\nA. Application security groups in Azure\nB. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nC. Azure Key Vault\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can enable single sign-on for an enterprise application through Azure Active Directory (Azure AD.\nIncorrect:\nApplication security groups enable you to configure network security as a natural extension of an application's structure, allowing you to group virtual machines and define network security policies based on those groups.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 242,
        "Question": "\nFor each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\nA network security group (NSG) will block all network traffic by default. (Y/N)\nApplication security groups can be specified as part of network security group (NSG) rules. (Y/N)\nNetwork security groups (NSGs) always include inbound security rules and outbound security rules. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure creates the default rules in each network security group that you create. These rules allow some traffic.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nA network security group contains zero, or as many rules as desired. These rules can refer to application security groups.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nAzure creates the Inbound and OutBound default rules in each network security group that you create.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 243,
        "Question": "A. authorization\nB. multi-factor authentication (MFA)\nC. single sign-on (SSO)\n1. The ability to use the same credentials to access multiple resources and applications from different providers.\n2. The process of identifying the access level of a user or service.\n3. Requires several elements to identify a user or a service.",
        "Answer": "C1B3A2",
        "Explanation": "Single sign-on (SSO) enables a user to sign in one time and use that credential to access multiple resources and applications from different providers. For SSO to work, the different applications and providers must trust the initial authenticator.\n\nMultifactor authentication is the process of prompting a user for an extra form (or factor) of identification during the sign-in process. MFA helps protect against a password compromise in situations where the password was compromised but the second factor wasn't.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 244,
        "Question": "Your company plans to automate the deployment of servers to Azure.\nYour manager is concerned that you may expose administrative credentials during the deployment.\nYou need to recommend an Azure solution that encrypts the administrative credentials during the deployment.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. Azure Key Vault\nB. Azure Information Protection\nC. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nD. Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA)",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Key Vault protects cryptographic keys, certificates (and the private keys associated with the certificates), and secrets (such as connection strings and passwords) in the cloud.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 245,
        "Question": "After you create a VM, you need to modify the allow connections to TCP port 8080 on the VM [\u2026].\nA. network security group (NSG)\nB. virtual network gateway\nC. virtual network\nD. route table",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "You can use an Azure network security group to filter network traffic to and from Azure resources in an Azure virtual network. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources. For each rule, you can specify source and destination, port, and protocol.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 246,
        "Question": "Azure distributed denial of service (DDoS) protection is an example of protection that is implemented at the [\u2026].\nA. application layer.\nB. compute layer.\nC. networking layer.\nD. perimeter layer.",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Use DDoS protection to filter large-scale attacks before they can affect the availability of a system for users.\nUse perimeter firewalls to identify and alert on malicious attacks against your network.\nAt the network perimeter, it's about protecting from network-based attacks against your resources. Identifying these attacks, eliminating their impact, and alerting you when they happen are important ways to keep your network secure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 247,
        "Question": "Azure Sentinel uses playbooks to [\u2026].\nA. automatically respond to threats.\nB. collect data from Azure services.\nC. specify how long data is retained.\nD. store passwords and certificates.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A playbook is a collection of these remediation actions that can be run from Microsoft Sentinel as a routine. A playbook can help automate and orchestrate your threat response; it can be run manually on-demand on entities (in preview - see below) and alerts, or set to run automatically in response to specific alerts or incidents, when triggered by an automation rule.\n\nFor example, if an account and machine are compromised, a playbook can isolate the machine from the network and block the account by the time the SOC team is notified of the incident.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 248,
        "Question": "You need to configure an Azure solution that meets the following requirements:\n- Secures websites from attacks\n- Generates reports that contain details of attempted attacks\nWhat should you include in the solution?\nA. Azure Firewall\nB. a network security group (NSG)\nC. Azure Information Protection\nD. DDoS protection",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "DDoS is a type of attack that tries to exhaust application resources. The goal is to affect the application's availability and its ability to handle legitimate requests.\nDDoS attacks can be targeted at any endpoint that is publicly reachable through the internet.\nAzure has two DDoS service offerings that provide protection from network attacks: DDoS Protection Basic and DDoS Protection Standard.\nDDoS Basic protection is integrated into the Azure platform by default and at no extra cost.\nYou have the option of paying for DDoS Standard. It has several advantages over the basic service, including logging, alerting, and telemetry. DDoS Standard can generate reports that contain details of attempted attacks as required in this question.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 249,
        "Question": "You plan to implement several security services for an Azure environment. You need to identify which Azure services must be used to meet the following security requirements:\n- Monitor threats by using sensors\n- Enforce Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) based on a condition\nWhich Azure service should you identify for each requirement? To answer, select the appropriate options in the answer area.\n\nA. Azure Monitor\nB. Azure Security Center\nC. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) Identity Protection\nD. Azure Advanced Threat Protection (ATP)\n1. Monitor threats by using sensors\n2. Enforce Azure MFA based on a condition\n",
        "Answer": "C2D1",
        "Explanation": "Box 1:\nTo monitor threats by using sensors, you would use Azure Advanced Threat Protection (ATP).\nAzure Advanced Threat Protection (ATP) is a cloud-based security solution that leverages your on-premises Active Directory signals to identify, detect, and investigate advanced threats, compromised identities, and malicious insider actions directed at your organization.\nSensors are software packages you install on your servers to upload information to Azure ATP.\nBox 2:\nTo enforce MFA based on a condition, you would use Azure Active Directory Identity Protection.\nAzure AD Identity Protection helps you manage the roll-out of Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) registration by configuring a Conditional Access policy to require MFA registration no matter what modern authentication app you are signing in to.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD12"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 250,
        "Question": "Your Azure environment contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP.\nWhat are two possible solutions? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Modify an Azure Traffic Manager profile\nB. Modify a network security group (NSG)\nC. Modify a DDoS protection plan\nD. Modify an Azure firewall",
        "Answer": "BD",
        "Explanation": "B. Modify a network security group (NSG): An NSG is a fundamental Azure resource that allows or denies network traffic to and from Azure resources, such as virtual machines. By default, incoming traffic to a virtual machine is blocked. To allow incoming HTTP traffic (port 80), you need to create an NSG rule that permits inbound traffic on port 80 for the specific virtual machine (VM1).\n\nD. Modify an Azure firewall: Azure Firewall is a cloud-based network security service that provides stateful firewall capabilities. If you are using Azure Firewall to protect your virtual network, you need to create a rule that allows HTTP traffic (port 80) from the Internet to the specific virtual machine (VM1).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 251,
        "Question": "You can enable just in time (JIT) VM access by using [\u2026].\nA. Azure Bastion\nB. Azure Firewall\nC. Azure Front Door\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "The central feature in Defender for Cloud that enables you to achieve those goals is secure score.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 252,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can associate a network security group (NSG) to a virtual network subnet. (Y/N)\n- You can associate a network security group (NSG) to a virtual network. (Y/N)\n- You can associate a network security group (NSG) to a network interface. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "You can deploy resources from several Azure services into an Azure virtual network. For a complete list, see Services that can be deployed into a virtual network. You can associate zero, or one, network security group to each virtual network subnet and network interface in a virtual machine. The same network security group can be associated to as many subnets and network interfaces as you choose.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 253,
        "Question": "You have an Azure environment that contains 10 virtual networks and 100 virtual machines.\nYou need to limit the amount of inbound traffic to all the Azure virtual networks.\nWhat should you create?\nA. one application security group (ASG)\nB. 10 virtual network gateways\nC. 10 Azure ExpressRoute circuits\nD. one Azure firewall",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "You can restrict traffic to multiple virtual networks with a single Azure firewall.\nAzure Firewall is a managed, cloud-based network security service that protects your Azure Virtual Network resources. It's a fully stateful firewall as a service with built-in high availability and unrestricted cloud scalability.\nYou can centrally create, enforce, and log application and network connectivity policies across subscriptions and virtual networks. Azure Firewall uses a static public IP address for your virtual network resources allowing outside firewalls to identify traffic originating from your virtual network.\nBoth NSG and Firewall can perform this function. I believe the key is in the number of virtual networks involved. You will use an NSG for a single VN and a Firewall for multiple.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 254,
        "Question": "Azure Key Vault is used to store secrets for Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) user accounts.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) administrative accounts\nC. Personally Identifiable Information (PII)\nD. server applications",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "In Azure, you can use Azure Key Vault to store secrets for Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) user accounts. Azure Key Vault is a cloud-based service that provides a secure location to store and manage cryptographic keys, secrets, and certificates.\n\nTo use Azure Key Vault to store secrets for Azure AD user accounts, you can follow these high-level steps:\n\n1. Create an Azure Key Vault instance.\n2. Define access policies to control who can access the secrets in the vault.\n3. Store the secrets for your Azure AD user accounts in the vault.\n4. Integrate Azure Active Directory with Azure Key Vault to enable your applications to access the secrets securely.\n\nBy storing secrets for Azure AD user accounts in Azure Key Vault, you can help to ensure that sensitive information is protected and that only authorized users and applications have access to it.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 255,
        "Question": "Your company plans to automate the deployment of servers to Azure.\nYour manager is concerned that you may expose administrative credentials during the deployment.\nYou need to recommend an Azure solution that encrypts the administrative credentials during the deployment.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. Azure Key Vault\nB. Azure Information Protection\nC. Azure Security Center\nD. Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA)",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Key Vault is a secure store for storage various types of sensitive information. In this question, we would store the administrative credentials in the Key Vault.\nWith this solution, there is no need to store the administrative credentials as plain text in the deployment scripts.\nAll information stored in the Key Vault is encrypted.\nAzure Key Vault can be used to Securely store and tightly control access to tokens, passwords, certificates, API keys, and other secrets.\nSecrets and keys are safeguarded by Azure, using industry-standard algorithms, key lengths, and hardware security modules (HSMs). The HSMs used are\nFederal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 140-2 Level 2 validated.\nAccess to a key vault requires proper authentication and authorization before a caller (user or application) can get access. Authentication establishes the identity of the caller, while authorization determines the operations that they are allowed to perform.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 256,
        "Question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to control the ports that devices on the Internet can use to access the virtual machines.\nWhat should you use?\nA. a network security group (NSG)\nB. an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) role\nC. an Azure Active Directory group\nD. an Azure key vault",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A network security group works like a firewall. You can attach a network security group to a virtual network and/or individual subnets within the virtual network.\nYou can also attach a network security group to a network interface assigned to a virtual machine. You can use multiple network security groups within a virtual network to restrict traffic between resources such as virtual machines and subnets.\nYou can filter network traffic to and from Azure resources in an Azure virtual network with a network security group. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 257,
        "Question": "After you create a VM, you need to modify the allow connections to TCP port 8080 on the VM [\u2026].\nA. network security group (NSG)\nB. virtual network gateway\nC. virtual network\nD. route table",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "When you create a virtual machine, the default setting is to create a Network Security Group attached to the network interface assigned to a virtual machine.\nA network security group works like a firewall. You can attach a network security group to a virtual network and/or individual subnets within the virtual network.\nYou can also attach a network security group to a network interface assigned to a virtual machine. You can use multiple network security groups within a virtual network to restrict traffic between resources such as virtual machines and subnets.\nYou can filter network traffic to and from Azure resources in an Azure virtual network with a network security group. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources.\nIn this question, we need to add a rule to the network security group to allow the connection to the virtual machine on port 8080.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 258,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can create custom Azure roles to control access to resources. (Y/N)\n- A user account can be assigned to multiple Azure roles. (Y/N)\n- A resource group can have the Owner role assigned to multiple users. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Yes, in Azure, a resource group can have the Owner role assigned to multiple users. The Owner role is a built-in role in Azure that provides full access to all resources in a resource group, including the ability to create, modify, and delete resources.\n\nWhen you assign the Owner role to a user or group, it grants them full access to all resources within the resource group. Multiple users or groups can be assigned the Owner role for a resource group, which allows for collaboration and delegation of responsibilities among different teams or individuals.\n\nIt's important to note that assigning the Owner role to multiple users or groups can increase the risk of accidental or intentional changes to resources within the resource group. Therefore, it's recommended to carefully consider the access needs of each user or group and assign roles accordingly to minimize the risk of unauthorized access or accidental changes.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 259,
        "Question": "Your Azure environment contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP.\nSolution: You modify a network security group (NSG).\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A network security group works like a firewall. You can attach a network security group to a virtual network and/or individual subnets within the virtual network.\nYou can also attach a network security group to a network interface assigned to a virtual machine. You can use multiple network security groups within a virtual network to restrict traffic between resources such as virtual machines and subnets.\nYou can filter network traffic to and from Azure resources in an Azure virtual network with a network security group. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources.\nIn this question, we need to add a rule to the network security group to allow the connection to the virtual machine on port 80 (HTTP).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 260,
        "Question": "Your Azure environment contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP.\nSolution: You modify a DDoS protection plan.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "DDoS is a form of attack on a network resource. A DDoS protection plan is used to protect against DDoS attacks; it does not provide connectivity to a virtual machine.\nTo ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP, you need to modify a network security group or Azure Firewall.\nDDOS is protected attacks and NSG and Azure Firewall is for allowing HTTP. So, the answer is correct.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 261,
        "Question": "You need to collect and automatically analyze security events from Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\nWhat should you use?\nA. Microsoft Sentinel\nB. Azure Synapse Analytics\nC. Azure AD Connect\nD. Azure Key Vault",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Sentinel is a scalable, cloud-native, security information and event management (SIEM) and security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) solution.\nMicrosoft Sentinel delivers intelligent security analytics and threat intelligence across the enterprise, providing a single solution for attack detection, threat visibility, proactive hunting, and threat response.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 262,
        "Question": "Your Azure environment contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that a virtual machine named VM1 is accessible from the Internet over HTTP.\nSolution: You modify an Azure firewall.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "We can choose Azure Firewall or NSG. It's also working together. We also can create a VM without NSG. Almost the example they created the VM with NSG because it's free. Azure Firewall is not free. That's all.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 263,
        "Question": "Azure Germany can be used by legal residents of Germany only.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. no change is needed\nB. only enterprises that are registered in Germany\nC. only enterprises that purchase their azure licenses from a partner based in Germany\nD. any user or enterprise that requires its data to reside in Germany",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Germany is available to eligible customers and partners globally who intend to do business in the EU/EFTA, including the United Kingdom.\nAzure Germany offers a separate instance of Microsoft Azure services from within German datacenters. The datacenters are in two locations, Frankfurt/Main and\nMagdeburg. This placement ensures that customer data remains in Germany and that the datacenters connect to each other through a private network. All customer data is exclusively stored in those datacenters. A designated German company--the German data trustee--controls access to customer data and the systems and infrastructure that hold customer data.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 264,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- Identities stored in an on-premises Active Directory can be synchronized to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). (Y/N)\n- Identities stored in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD), third-party cloud services, and on-premises Active Directory can be used to access Azure resources. (Y/N)\n- Azure has built-in authentication and authorization services that provide secure access to Azure resources. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nThe tool you would use to sync the accounts is Azure AD Connect. The Azure Active Directory Connect synchronization services (Azure AD Connect sync) is a main component of Azure AD Connect. It takes care of all the operations that are related to synchronize identity data between your on-premises environment and\nAzure AD.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAs described above, third-party cloud services and on-premises Active Directory can be used to access Azure resources. This is known as 'federation'.\nFederation is a collection of domains that have established trust. The level of trust may vary, but typically includes authentication and almost always includes authorization. A typical federation might include a number of organizations that have established trust for shared access to a set of resources.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a centralized identity provider in the cloud. This is the primary built-in authentication and authorization service to provide secure access to Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 265,
        "Question": "You can view your company's regulatory compliance report from [\u2026]\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Analysis Services\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Security Center (Microsoft Defender for Cloud)",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Security Center renamed to Azure Defender for Cloud.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 266,
        "Question": "What should you use to evaluate whether your company's Azure environment meets regulatory requirements?\nA. Azure Service Health\nB. Azure Knowledge Center\nC. Azure Security Center (Microsoft Defender for Cloud)\nD. Azure Advisor",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The advanced monitoring capabilities in Security Center lets you track and manage compliance and governance over time. The overall compliance provides you with a measure of how much your subscriptions are compliant with policies associated with your workload.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 267,
        "Question": "Your company implements [\u2026] to automatically add a watermark to Microsoft Word documents that contain credit card information.\nA. Azure policies\nB. DDoS protection\nC. Azure Information Protection\nD. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) Identity Protection",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Information Protection is used to automatically add a watermark to Microsoft Word documents that contain credit card information.\nYou use Azure Information Protection labels to apply classification to documents and emails. When you do this, the classification is identifiable regardless of where the data is stored or with whom it's shared. The labels can include visual markings such as a header, footer, or watermark.\nLabels can be applied automatically by administrators who define rules and conditions, manually by users, or a combination where users are given recommendations. In this question, we would configure a label to be automatically applied to Microsoft Word documents that contain credit card information. The label would then add the watermark to the documents.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 268,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) requires the implementation of domain controllers on Azure virtual machines. (Y/N)\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) provides authentication services for resources hosted in Azure and Microsoft 365. (Y/N)\n- Each user account in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) can be assigned only one license. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a cloud-based service. It does not require domain controllers on virtual machines.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a centralized identity provider in the cloud. This is the primary built-in authentication and authorization service to provide secure access to Azure resources and Microsoft 365.\n\nBox 3: No -\nUser accounts in Azure Active Directory can be assigned multiple licenses for different Azure or Microsoft 365 services.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 269,
        "Question": "Which two types of customers are eligible to use Azure Government to develop a cloud solution? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a Canadian government contractor\nB. a European government contractor\nC. a United States government entity\nD. a United States government contractor\nE. a European government entity",
        "Answer": "CD",
        "Explanation": "Azure Government is a cloud environment specifically built to meet compliance and security requirements for US government. This mission-critical cloud delivers breakthrough innovation to U.S. government customers and their partners. Azure Government applies to government at any level \u05d2\u20ac\" from state and local governments to federal agencies including Department of Defense agencies.\nThe key difference between Microsoft Azure and Microsoft Azure Government is that Azure Government is a sovereign cloud. It's a physically separated instance of Azure, dedicated to U.S. government workloads only. It's built exclusively for government agencies and their solution providers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 270,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- To implement an Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) solution, you must sync on-premises identities to the cloud. (Y/N)\n- Two valid methods for Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) are picture identification and a passport number. (Y/N) \n- Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) can be required for administrative and non-administrative user accounts. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nIt is not true that you must deploy a federation solution or sync on-premises identities to the cloud. You can have a cloud-only environment and use MFA.\n\nBox 2: No -\nPicture identification and passport numbers are not valid MFA authentication methods. Valid methods include: Password, Microsoft Authenticator App, SMS and\nVoice call.\nBox 3:\nYou can configure MFA to be required for administrator accounts only or you can configure MFA for any user account.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 271,
        "Question": "You need to ensure that when Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) users connect to Azure AD from the Internet by using an anonymous IP address, the users are prompted automatically to change their password.\nWhich Azure service should you use?\nA. Azure AD Connect Health\nB. Azure AD Privileged Identity Management\nC. Azure Advanced Threat Protection (ATP)\nD. Azure AD Identity Protection",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure AD Identity Protection includes two risk policies: sign-in risk policy and user risk policy. A sign-in risk represents the probability that a given authentication request isn't authorized by the identity owner.\nThere are several types of risk detection. One of them is Anonymous IP Address. This risk detection type indicates sign-ins from an anonymous IP address (for example, Tor browser or anonymous VPN). These IP addresses are typically used by actors who want to hide their login telemetry (IP address, location, device, etc.) for potentially malicious intent.\nYou can configure the sign-in risk policy to require that users change their password.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 272,
        "Question": "A. Azure Government\nB. GDPR\nC. ISO\nD. NIST\n1. An organization that defines international standards across all industries.\n2. An organization that defines standards used by the United States government.\n3. A European policy that regulates data privacy and data protection.\n4. A dedicated public cloud for federal and state agencies in the United States.\n",
        "Answer": "A4B3C1D2",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: ISO -\nISO is the International Organization for Standardization. Companies can be certified to ISO standards, for example ISO 9001 or 27001 are commonly used in IT companies.\n\nBox 2: NIST -\nThe National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) is a physical sciences laboratory, and a non-regulatory agency of the United States Department of\nCommerce.\n\nBox 3: GDPR -\nGDPR is the General Data Protection Regulations. This standard was adopted across Europe in May 2018 and replaces the now deprecated Data Protection\nDirective.\nThe General Data Protection Regulation (EU) (GDPR) is a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy in the European Union (EU) and the European\nEconomic Area (EEA). It also addresses the transfer of personal data outside the EU and EEA areas. The GDPR aims primarily to give control to individuals over their personal data and to simplify the regulatory environment for international business by unifying the regulation within the EU.\n\nBox 4: Azure Government -\nUS government agencies or their partners interested in cloud services that meet government security and compliance requirements, can be confident that\nMicrosoft Azure Government provides world-class security, protection, and compliance services. Azure Government delivers a dedicated cloud enabling government agencies and their partners to transform mission-critical workloads to the cloud. Azure Government services handle data that is subject to certain government regulations and requirements, such as FedRAMP, NIST 800.171 (DIB), ITAR, IRS 1075, DoD L4, and CJIS. In order to provide you with the highest level of security and compliance, Azure Government uses physically isolated datacenters and networks (located in U.S. only).",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD1234"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 273,
        "Question": "To what should an application connect to retrieve security tokens?\nA. an Azure Storage account\nB. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nC. a certificate store\nD. an Azure key vault",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The Azure Key Vault store Keys. Azure AD give acces tokens.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 274,
        "Question": "Your network contains an Active Directory forest. The forest contains 5,000 user accounts.\nYour company plans to migrate all network resources to Azure and to decommission the on-premises data center.\nYou need to recommend a solution to minimize the impact on users after the planned migration.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Implement Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA)\nB. Sync all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nC. Instruct all users to change their password\nD. Create a guest user account in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) for each user",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "To migrate to Azure and decommission the on-premises data center, you would need to create the 5,000 user accounts in Azure Active Directory. The easy way to do this is to sync all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). You can even sync their passwords to further minimize the impact on users.\nThe tool you would use to sync the accounts is Azure AD Connect. The Azure Active Directory Connect synchronization services (Azure AD Connect sync) is a main component of Azure AD Connect. It takes care of all the operations that are related to synchronize identity data between your on-premises environment and Azure AD.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 275,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can configure the Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) activity logs to appear in Azure Monitor. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Monitor, you can monitor resources across multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Monitor, you can create alerts. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nYou can send Azure AD activity logs to Azure Monitor logs to enable rich visualizations, monitoring and alerting on the connected data.\nAll data collected by Azure Monitor fits into one of two fundamental types, metrics and logs (including Azure AD activity logs). Activity logs record when resources are created or modified. Metrics tell you how the resource is performing and the resources that it's consuming.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAzure Monitor can consolidate log entries from multiple Azure resources, subscriptions, and tenants into one location for analysis together.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nYou can create alerts in Azure Monitor.\nAlerts in Azure Monitor proactively notify you of critical conditions and potentially attempt to take corrective action. Alert rules based on metrics provide near real time alerting based on numeric values, while rules based on logs allow for complex logic across data from multiple sources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 276,
        "Question": "You create a resource group named RG1 in Azure Resource Manager.\nYou need to prevent the accidental deletion of the resources in RG1.\nWhich setting should you use? To answer, select the appropriate setting in the answer area.\nA. Quickstart\nB. Resource costs\nC. Deployments\nD. Policies\nE. Properties\nF. Locks\nG. Export template",
        "Answer": "F",
        "Explanation": "You can configure a lock on a resource group to prevent the accidental deletion.\nAs an administrator, you may need to lock a subscription, resource group, or resource to prevent other users in your organization from accidentally deleting or modifying critical resources. You can set the lock level to CanNotDelete or ReadOnly. In the portal, the locks are called Delete and Read-only respectively.\n- CanNotDelete means authorized users can still read and modify a resource, but they can't delete the resource.\n- ReadOnly means authorized users can read a resource, but they can't delete or update the resource. Applying this lock is similar to restricting all authorized users to the permissions granted by the Reader role.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFG"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 277,
        "Question": "You have a resource group named RG1.\nYou need to prevent the creation of virtual machines in RG1. The solution must ensure that other objects can be created in RG1.\nWhat should you use?\nA. a lock\nB. an Azure role\nC. a tag\nD. an Azure policy",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure policies can be used to define requirements for resource properties during deployment and for already existing resources. Azure Policy controls properties such as the types or locations of resources.\nAzure Policy is a service in Azure that you use to create, assign, and manage policies. These policies enforce different rules and effects over your resources, so those resources stay compliant with your corporate standards and service level agreements.\nIn this question, we would create an Azure policy assigned to the resource group that denies the creation of virtual machines in the resource group.\nYou could place a read-only lock on the resource group. However, that would prevent the creation of any resources in the resource group, not virtual machines only. Therefore, an Azure Policy is a better solution.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 278,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription and 100 Windows 10 devices.\nYou need to ensure that only users whose devices have the latest security patches installed can access Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)-integrated applications.\nWhat should you implement?\nA. a conditional access policy\nB. Azure Bastion\nC. Azure Firewall\nD. Azure Policy",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "A conditional access policy is a feature of Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) that enables you to control access to cloud applications based on a set of conditions. You can use a conditional access policy to restrict access to Azure AD-integrated applications to only those devices that meet certain security requirements, such as having the latest security patches installed.\n\nBy implementing a conditional access policy, you can ensure that only users whose devices have the latest security patches can access Azure AD-integrated applications, while blocking access for users with devices that do not meet the security requirements.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 279,
        "Question": "What can Azure Information Protection encrypt?\nA. network traffic\nB. documents and email messages\nC. an Azure Storage account\nD. an Azure SQL database",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Information Protection can encrypt documents and emails.\nAzure Information Protection is a cloud-based solution that helps an organization to classify and optionally, protect its documents and emails by applying labels.\nLabels can be applied automatically by administrators who define rules and conditions, manually by users, or a combination where users are given recommendations.\nThe protection technology uses Azure Rights Management (often abbreviated to Azure RMS). This technology is integrated with other Microsoft cloud services and applications, such as Office 365 and Azure Active Directory.\nThis protection technology uses encryption, identity, and authorization policies. Similarly to the labels that are applied, protection that is applied by using Rights\nManagement stays with the documents and emails, independently of the location \u05d2\u20ac\" inside or outside your organization, networks, file servers, and applications.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 280,
        "Question": "What should you use to evaluate whether your company's Azure environment meets regulatory requirements?\nA. the Knowledge Center website\nB. the Advisor blade from the Azure portal\nC. Compliance Manager from the Service Trust Portal\nD. the Solutions blade from the Azure portal",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Compliance Manager in the Service Trust Portal is a workflow-based risk assessment tool that helps you track, assign, and verify your organization's regulatory compliance activities related to Microsoft Cloud services, such as Microsoft 365, Dynamics 365, and Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 281,
        "Question": " [\u2026] enables users to authentificate to multiple applications by using sigle sign-on (SSO).\nA. Application security groups in Azure\nB. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\nC. Azure Key Vault\nD. Microsoft Defender for Cloud",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can enable single sign-on for an enterprise application through Azure Active Directory (Azure AD.\nIncorrect:\nApplication security groups enable you to configure network security as a natural extension of an application's structure, allowing you to group virtual machines and define network security policies based on those groups.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 282,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription.\nWhere will you find details on the personal data collected by Microsoft, how Microsoft uses the data, and what the data is used for?\nA. the Data Protection Addendum\nB. the Microsoft Online Services Terms\nC. the Microsoft Privacy Statement\nD. Azure Security Center",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The Microsoft Privacy Statement explains the personal data Microsoft processes, how Microsoft processes it, and for what purposes. Your applicable Services\nAgreement or the Preview Supplemental Terms may specify lesser or different privacy measures for some Preview services.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 283,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) can be used to manage access to on-premises applications. (Y/N)\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) provides single sign-on (SSO). (Y/N)\n- iOS devices can be registered in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "1. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) can be used to manage access to on-premises applications.\n   - **Yes**: Azure AD can be integrated with on-premises Active Directory to manage access to on-premises applications through features like Azure AD Application Proxy.\n\n2. Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) provides single sign-on (SSO).\n   - **Yes**: Azure AD offers SSO capabilities, allowing users to log in once and access multiple services without needing to re-authenticate.\n\n3. iOS devices can be registered in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\n   - **Yes**: iOS devices, along with other device types, can be registered with Azure AD for management and policy application within a corporate environment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 284,
        "Question": "You have an Azure virtual network named VNET1 in a resource group named RG1. You assign the Azure Policy definition of Not Allowed Resource Type and specify that virtual networks are not an allowed resource type in RG1. VNET1 [...].\nA. is deleted automatically.\nB. is moved automatically to another resource group.\nC. continues to function normally.\nD. is now a read-only object.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The VNet will be marked as 'Non-compliant' when the policy is assigned. However, it will not be deleted and will continue to function normally.\nAzure Policy is a service in Azure that you use to create, assign, and manage policies. These policies enforce different rules and effects over your resources, so those resources stay compliant with your corporate standards and service level agreements.\nIf there are any existing resources that aren't compliant with a new policy assignment, they appear under Non-compliant resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 285,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Trust Center is part of the Azure Security Center. (Y/N)\n- Trust Center can only be accessed by users that have an Azure subscription. (Y/N)\n- Trust Center provides information about the Azure compliance offerings. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Trust Center is part of the Azure Security Center.\nThis statement is about whether the Trust Center is a component or feature within the Azure Security Center. Azure Security Center is a tool that provides unified security management and advanced threat protection across hybrid cloud workloads.\n\nTrust Center can only be accessed by users that have an Azure subscription.\nThis is about the accessibility of the Trust Center and whether it's exclusive to users with an active Azure subscription.\n\nTrust Center provides information about the Azure compliance offerings.\nThis statement addresses whether the Trust Center serves as a source of information for compliance standards and regulations that Azure services adhere to.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 286,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can use Azure Policy to apply tags to resources. (Y/N)\n- You can add multiple tags to the same Azure resource. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource inherits tags from the resource group to which the resource is deployed. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "You use Azure Policy to enforce tagging rules and conventions. By creating a policy, you avoid the scenario of resources being deployed to your subscription that don't have the expected tags for your organization. Instead of manually applying tags or searching for resources that aren't compliant, you create a policy that automatically applies the needed tags during deployment. Tags can also now be applied to existing resources with the new Modify effect and a remediation task.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 287,
        "Question": "A. Data Protection Addendum\nB. Microsoft Privacy Statement\nC. Online Services Terms\n1. Describes which personal data is collected, how the data is used, and what the data is used for.\n2. A legal agreement that details the obligations between Microsoft and a customer regarding the processing and security of customer data and personal data.\n3. Defines the data processing and security terms for online services, including the disclosure of processed data and the transfer, retention, and deletion of data.",
        "Answer": "A2B1C3",
        "Explanation": "A. Data Protection Addendum - 2. A legal agreement that details the obligations between Microsoft and a customer regarding the processing and security of customer data and personal data.\nB. Microsoft Privacy Statement - 1. Describes which personal data is collected, how the data is used, and what the data is used for.\nC. Online Services Terms - 3. Defines the data processing and security terms for online services, including the disclosure of processed data and the transfer, retention, and deletion of data.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 288,
        "Question": "Requiring a user to enter a password and answer a security question when signing-in to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) is an example of [...].\nA. business-to-customer (B2C) identity services.\nB. managed identities.\nC. multi-factor authentication (MFA).\nD. role-based access control (RBAC).",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Something you know, typically a password.\nSomething you have, such as a trusted device that's not easily duplicated, like a phone or hardware key.\nSomething you are - biometrics like a fingerprint or face scan",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 289,
        "Question": "\nAzure China [\u2026].\nA. is operated by Microsoft.\nB. has feature parity with Azure global.\nC. services can be accessed from China only.\nD. is a distinct separate instance of Microsoft Azure.\n\n\n\n",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Azure operated by 21Vianet (Azure China) is a physically separated instance of cloud services located in China.\nMS gave in to the commies.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 290,
        "Question": "What should you use to evaluate whether your company's Azure environment meets regulatory requirements?\nA. Azure Service Health\nB. Azure Knowledge Center\nC. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nD. Azure Advisor",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Defender for Cloud continually compares the configuration of your resources with requirements in industry standards, regulations, and benchmarks. The regulatory compliance dashboard provides insights into your compliance posture based on how you're meeting specific compliance requirements.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 291,
        "Question": "You can review audit reports and compliance-related information for Azure Services from [\u2026].\nA. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nB. the Microsoft Defender for Identity admin center\nC. the Microsoft 365 Compliance center\nD. the Microsoft Service Trust Portal",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Service Trust Portal.\nThe Microsoft Service Trust Portal provides a variety of content, tools, and other resources about Microsoft security, privacy, and compliance practices.\n\nTrust Documents -\nProvides a wealth of security implementation and design information with the goal of making it easier for you to meet regulatory compliance objectives by understanding how Microsoft Cloud services keep your data secure. To review content, select one of the following options on the Trust Documents pull-down menu.\n* Audit Reports: A list of independent audit and assessment reports on Microsoft's Cloud services is displayed. These reports provide information about Microsoft\nCloud services compliance with data protection standards and regulatory requirements.\n* Data Protection: Contains a wealth of resources such as audited controls, white papers, FAQs, penetration tests, risk assessment tools, and compliance guides.\n* Azure Security and Compliance Blueprints: Resources that help you build secure and compliant cloud-based applications. This area contains blueprint-guidance for government, finance, healthcare, and retail verticals.\nIncorrect:\nNot: Microsoft Defender for Cloud.\nDefender for Cloud is a tool for security posture management and threat protection. It strengthens the security posture of your cloud resources, and with its integrated Microsoft Defender plans, Defender for Cloud protects workloads running in Azure, hybrid, and other cloud platforms.\nDefender for Cloud provides the tools needed to harden your resources, track your security posture, protect against cyber attacks, and streamline security management.\nNot: the Microsoft 365 Compliance center\nThe Security & Compliance Center lets you grant permissions to people who perform compliance tasks like device management, data loss prevention, eDiscovery, retention, and so on. These people can perform only the tasks that you explicitly grant them access to.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 292,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The Microsoft Service Trust Portal can be accessed by using a Microsoft cloud services account. (Y/N)\n- Compliance Manager can be used to track your company\u2019s regulatory compliance activities related to Microsoft cloud services. (Y/N)\n- The My Library feature can be used to save Microsoft Service Trust Portal documents and resources in a single location. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Purview Compliance Manager is a feature in the Microsoft Purview compliance portal that helps you manage your organization\u2019s multicloud compliance requirements with greater ease and convenience. Compliance Manager can help you throughout your compliance journey, from taking inventory of your data protection risks to managing the complexities of implementing controls, staying current with regulations and certifications, and reporting to auditors.\n\nThis section displays all available documents. Select the documents to save into your My Library section. Documents are sorted under the same categories shown under Certifications, Standards, Regulations, and Industry Resources. To view all resources for a particular cloud service use the Cloud Service filter.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 293,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains resources in several regions.\nYou need to create the Azure resource that must be used to meet the policy requirement.\nWhat should you create?\nA. a read-only lock\nB. an Azure policy\nC. a management group\nD. a reservation",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure policies can be used to define requirements for resource properties during deployment and for already existing resources. Azure Policy controls properties such as the types or locations of resources.\nAzure Policy is a service in Azure that you use to create, assign, and manage policies. These policies enforce different rules and effects over your resources, so those resources stay compliant with your corporate standards and service level agreements. Azure Policy meets this need by evaluating your resources for non- compliance with assigned policies. All data stored by Azure Policy is encrypted at rest.\nAzure Policy offers several built-in policies that are available by default. In this question, we would use the 'Allowed Locations' policy to define the locations where resources can be deployed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 294,
        "Question": "From Azure Cloud Shell, you can track your company's regulatory standards and regulations, such as ISO 27001.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed.` If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed.\nB. the Microsoft Cloud Partner Portal\nC. Compliance Manager\nD. the Trust Center",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Yes, a Compliance Manager can indeed help track and manage a company's adherence to regulatory standards and regulations, including ISO 27001\nCompliance Manager's assessment templates help to track compliance with over 300 industry and government regulations around the world. Start your free premium assessments trial today and we'll help you quickly set up assessments that matter most to your organization. Learn more about the premium assessments trial,",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 295,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can create Group Policies in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). (Y/N)\n- You can join Windows 10 devices to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). (Y/N)\n- You can join Android devices to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "Azure AD join only applies to Windows 10 devices.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 296,
        "Question": "The [\u2026] explains what data Microsoft processes, how Microsoft processes the data, and the purpose of processing the data.\nA. Microsoft Online Services Privacy Statement\nB. Microsoft Product Terms\nC. Microsoft Online Service Level Agreement\nD. Online Subscription Agreement for Microsoft Azure",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Microsoft Privacy Statement explains what personal data Microsoft processes, how Microsoft processes the data, and the purpose of processing the data",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 297,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is the process of verifying a user's credentials.\nA. Authorization\nB. Authentification\nC. Federation\nD. Ticketing",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Authentication, not authorization is the process of verifying a user's credentials.\nThe difference between authentication and authorization is:\n- Authentication is proving your identity, proving that you are who you say you are. The most common example of this is logging in to a system by providing credentials such as a username and password.\n- Authorization is what you're allowed to do once you've been authenticated. For example, what resources you're allowed to access and what you can do with those resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 298,
        "Question": "An Azure Policy initiative definition is a [\u2026].\nA. collection of policy definitions.\nB. collection of Azure Policy definition assignments.\nC. group of Azure Blueprints definitions.\nD. group of role-based access control (RBAC) role assignments.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "An initiative definition is a collection of policy definitions that are grouped towards achieving a singular overarching goal. Initiative definitions simplify managing and assigning policy definitions by grouping them as a single assignable object",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 299,
        "Question": "[\u2026] provide organizations with the ability to manage the compliance of Azure resources across multiple subscriptions.\nA. Resource groups\nB. Management groups\nC. Azure policies\nD. Azure App Service plans\n\n",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The key term in this context is \u201cAzure Resources.\u201d Management groups can be used to manage access, policies, and compliance for subscriptions at the subscription level. However, Azure Policy can be applied at the resource level, subscription level, and management group level. Therefore, since the question pertains to Azure resources specifically, Azure Policy would be the most appropriate choice.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 300,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) defines data protection and privacy rules. (Y/N)\n- General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) applies to companies that offer goods or services to individuals in the EU. (Y/N)\n- Azure can be used to build a General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)-compliant infrastructure. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) defines data protection and privacy rules: GDPR is a regulatory framework that sets guidelines for the collection and processing of personal information from individuals who live in the European Union (EU).\nGeneral Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) applies to companies that offer goods or services to individuals in the EU: GDPR not only applies to organizations based within the EU but also to those outside the EU if they provide goods or services to, or monitor the behavior of, EU data subjects.\nAzure can be used to build a General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)-compliant infrastructure: Microsoft Azure provides features and services that can help organizations meet GDPR requirements, such as data protection, access controls, and the ability to manage and monitor data compliance.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 301,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can add an Azure Resource Manager template to an Azure blueprint. (Y/N)\n- You can assign an Azure blueprint to a resource group. (Y/N)\n- You can use Azure Blueprints to grant permissions to a resource. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "1 : Blueprints are a declarative way to orchestrate the deployment of various resource templates and other artifacts such as: Azure Resource Manager templates (ARM templates)\n\n2 : Resource group can be a a part of Azure Blueprint deployment but itself can be part of MANAGEMENT GROUP\n\n3 : Yes, you can grant permission to resources",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 302,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure China is operated by Microsoft (Y/N)\n- Azure Government is operated by Microsoft (Y/N)\n- Azure Government is available only to US government agencies and their partners (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft Azure operated by 21Vianet (Azure China) is a physically separated instance of cloud services located in China. It's independently operated and transacted by Shanghai Blue Cloud Technology Co., Ltd. (\"21Vianet\"), a wholly owned subsidiary of Beijing 21Vianet Broadband Data Center Co., Ltd",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 303,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure resource can have multiple Delete locks. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource inherits locks from its resource group. (Y/N)\n- If an Azure resource has a Read-only lock, you can add a Delete lock to the resource. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "A - Can you have multiple delete locks on a resource? YES\nConfirmed, with screenshots in the below article.\n\nB - Are locks inherited from a resource group? YES\nWhen you apply a lock at a parent scope, all resources within that scope inherit the same lock. Even resources you add later inherit the lock from the parent. The most restrictive lock in the inheritance takes precedence.\nIf you want to create a lock at a parent level, select the parent. The currently selected resource inherits the lock from the parent. For example, you could lock the resource group to apply a lock to all its resources.\n\nC - If you have a read only lock, can you add a delete lock? YES\nConfirmed as possible by vasonic in a previous comment in lab.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 304,
        "Question": "Your company plans to migrate all on-premises data to Azure.\nYou need to identify whether Azure complies with the company's regional requirements.\nWhat should you use?\nA. the Knowledge Center\nB. Azure Marketplace\nC. the MyApps portal\nD. the Trust Center",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure has more than 90 compliance certifications, including over 50 specific to global regions and countries, such as the US, the European Union, Germany,\nJapan, the United Kingdom, India and China.\nYou can view a list of compliance certifications in the Trust Center to determine whether Azure meets your regional requirements.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 305,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Authorization to access Azure resources can be provided only to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) users. (Y/N)\n- Identities stored in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD), third-party cloud services, and on-premises Active Directory can be used to access Azure resources. (Y/N)\n- Azure has built-in authentication and authorization services that provide secure access to Azure resources. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAuthorization to access Azure resources can be provided by other identity providers by using federation. A commonly used example of this is to federate your on- premises Active Directory environment with Azure AD and use this federation for authentication and authorization.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAs described above, third-party cloud services and on-premises Active Directory can be used to access Azure resources. This is known as 'federation'.\nFederation is a collection of domains that have established trust. The level of trust may vary, but typically includes authentication and almost always includes authorization. A typical federation might include a number of organizations that have established trust for shared access to a set of resources.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a centralized identity provider in the cloud. This is the primary built-in authentication and authorization service to provide secure access to Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 306,
        "Question": "If a resource group named RG1 has a delete lock [...] can delete RG1.\nA. only a member of the global administrators group\nB. the delete lock must be removed before an administrator\nC. an Azure policy must be modified before an administrator\nD. an Azure tag must be added before an administrator ",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can configure a lock on a resource group to prevent the accidental deletion of the resource group. The lock applies to everyone, including global administrators. If you want to delete the resource group, the lock must be removed first.\nAs an administrator, you may need to lock a subscription, resource group, or resource to prevent other users in your organization from accidentally deleting or modifying critical resources. You can set the lock level to CanNotDelete or ReadOnly. In the portal, the locks are called Delete and Read-only respectively.\n- CanNotDelete means authorized users can still read and modify a resource, but they can't delete the resource.\nReadOnly means authorized users can read a resource, but they can't delete or update the resource. Applying this lock is similar to restricting all authorized\n users to the permissions granted by the Reader role.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 307,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is the process of establishing the identity of a user or service that wants to access a resource.\nA. Authentification\nB. Authorization\nC. Conditional Access\nD. Synchronization",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Authentication means are you who you say you are.\nAuthorization means do you have the required authority/permission to do what you want to do",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 308,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Single sign-on (SSO) requires that all users sign in by using the Microsoft Authenticator app. (Y/N)\n- Authentication is the process of establishing which level of access an authenticated user or service has. (Y/N)\n- Conditional Access uses signals collected from a user during the sign-in process to decide whether to allow or deny access requests. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Single sign-on is an authentication method that allows users to sign in using one set of credentials to login across applications. Single sign-on makes it easier to manage passwords and increases security capabilities.\nAuthorization is the process of establishing what level of access a legitimate user or service should have.\nDuring sign-in, Conditional Access collects signals from the user, makes decisions based on those signals, and then enforces that decision by allowing or denying the access request or challenging for a multifactor authentication response.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 309,
        "Question": "What is guaranteed in an Azure Service Level Agreement (SLA) for virtual machines?\nA. uptime\nB. feature availability\nC. bandwidth\nD. performance",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "RTO and RPO = uptime\n\nThe SLA for virtual machines guarantees 'uptime'. The amount of uptime guaranteed depends on factors such as whether the VMs are in an availability set or availability zone if there is more than one VM, the distribution of the VMs if there is more than one or the disk type if it is a single VM.\nThe SLA for Virtual Machines states:\n- For all Virtual Machines that have two or more instances deployed across two or more Availability Zones in the same Azure region, we guarantee you will have\nVirtual Machine Connectivity to at least one instance at least 99.99% of the time.\n- For all Virtual Machines that have two or more instances deployed in the same Availability Set or in the same Dedicated Host Group, we guarantee you will have Virtual Machine Connectivity to at least one instance at least 99.95% of the time.\n- For any Single Instance Virtual Machine using Premium SSD or Ultra Disk for all Operating System Disks and Data Disks, we guarantee you will have Virtual\nMachine Connectivity of at least 99.9%.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 310,
        "Question": "An Azure service is available to all Azure customers when it is in [\u2026],\nA. public preview\nB. private preview\nC. development\nD. an Enterprise Agreement (EA) subscription",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Public Preview means that the service is in public beta and can be tried out by anyone with an Azure subscription. Services in public preview are often offered at a discount price.\nPublic previews are excluded from SLAs and in some cases, no support is offered.\nIncorrect Answers:\nServices in private preview are available only to selected people who has signed up to the private preview program.\n- Services in development are not available to the public.\n- Services provided under an Enterprise Agreement (EA) subscription are available only to the subscription owner.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 311,
        "Question": "Your company plans to purchase an Azure subscription.\nThe company's support policy states that the Azure environment must provide an option to access support engineers by phone or email.\nYou need to recommend which support plan meets the support policy requirement.\nSolution: Recommend a Basic support plan.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "The Basic support plan does not have any technical support for engineers.\nAccess to Support Engineers via email or phone is available in the following support plans: Premier, Professional Direct and standard.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 312,
        "Question": "Your company plans to purchase an Azure subscription.\nThe company's support policy states that the Azure environment must provide an option to access support engineers by phone or email.\nYou need to recommend which support plan meets the support policy requirement.\nSolution: Recommend a Standard support plan.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Standard, Professional Direct, and Premier support plans have technical support for engineers via email and phone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 313,
        "Question": "Your company plans to purchase an Azure subscription.\nThe company's support policy states that the Azure environment must provide an option to access support engineers by phone or email.\nYou need to recommend which support plan meets the support policy requirement.\nSolution: Recommend a Premier support plan.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Standard, Professional Direct, and Premier support plans have technical support for engineers via email and phone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 314,
        "Question": "Your company plans to request an architectural review of an Azure environment from Microsoft.\nThe company currently has a Basic support plan.\nYou need to recommend a new support plan for the company. The solution must minimize costs.\nWhich support plan should you recommend?\nA. Premier\nB. Developer\nC. Professional Direct\nD. Standard",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "I\u2019m sorry, but there is no Premier support plan listed on the Azure Support Plans Comparison page 1. There are four support plans listed: Basic, Developer, Standard, and Professional Direct 1. To request an architectural review of an Azure environment from Microsoft and minimize costs, you should recommend the Professional Direct support plan. This plan provides architecture support with guidance from a pool of ProDirect delivery managers 1.\n\nSo the correct answer is C. Professional Direct.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 315,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Most Azure services are introduced in private preview before being introduced in public preview, and then in general availability. (Y/N)\n- Azure services in public preview can be managed only by using the Azure CLI. (Y/N)\n- The cost of an Azure service in private preview decreases when the service becomes generally available. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nMost services go to private preview then public preview before being released to general availability.\nThe private preview is only available to certain Azure customers for evaluation purposes. The public preview is available to all Azure customers.\n\nBox 2: No -\nAzure services in public preview can be managed using the regular management tools: Azure Portal, Azure CLI and PowerShell.\n\nBox 3: No -\nServices in private or public preview are usually offered at reduced costs. However, the costs increase, not decrease when the services are released to general availability.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 316,
        "Question": "What is required to use Azure Cost Management?\nA. a Dev/Test subscription\nB. Software Assurance\nC. an Enterprise Agreement (EA)\nD. a pay-as-you-go subscription",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "According to Microsoft, Azure Cost Management is enabled by default for Enterprise Agreement and Pay-As-You-Go customers, so there is no need to enable it separately. So, both C and D should be correct here",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 317,
        "Question": "You Azure trial account expired last week. You are now unable to [...].\nA. create additional Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) user accounts.\nB. start an existing Azure VM\nC. access your date stored in Azure\nD. access the Azure portal",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "A stopped (deallocated) VM is offline and not mounted on an Azure host server. Starting a VM mounts the VM on a host server before the VM starts. As soon as the VM is mounted, it becomes chargeable. For this reason, you are unable to start a VM after a trial has expired.\nIncorrect Answers:\n- You are not charged for Azure Active Directory user accounts so you can continue to create accounts.\n- You can access data that is already stored in Azure.\n- You can access the Azure Portal. You can also reactivate and upgrade the expired subscription in the portal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 318,
        "Question": "Your company plans to purchase an Azure subscription.\nThe company's support policy states that the Azure environment must provide an option to access support engineers by phone or email.\nYou need to recommend which support plan meets the support policy requirement.\nSolution: Recommend a Professional Direct support plan.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Basic support plan does not have any technical support for engineers.\nThe Developer support plan has only technical support for engineers via email.\nThe Standard, Professional Direct, and Premier support plans have technical support for engineers via email and phone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 319,
        "Question": "Your company has a Software Assurance agreement that includes Microsoft SQL Server licenses.\nYou plan to deploy SQL Server on Azure virtual machines.\nWhat should you do to minimize licensing costs for the deployment?\nA. Deallocate the virtual machines during off hours.\nB. Use Azure Hybrid Benefit.\nC. Configure Azure Cost Management budgets.\nD. Use Azure reservations.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Hybrid Benefit is a licensing benefit that helps you to significantly reduce the costs of running your workloads in the cloud. It works by letting you use your on-premises Software Assurance-enabled Windows Server and SQL Server licenses on Azure.\nReference:",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 320,
        "Question": "Your company has 10 departments.\nThe company plans to implement an Azure environment.\nYou need to ensure that each department can use a different payment option for the Azure services it consumes.\nWhat should you create for each department?\nA. a reservation\nB. a subscription\nC. a resource group\nD. a container instance",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "There are different payment options in Azure including pay-as-you-go (PAYG), Enterprise Agreement (EA), and Microsoft Customer Agreement (MCA) accounts.\nYour Azure costs are 'per subscription'. You are charged monthly for all resources in a subscription. Therefore, to use different payment options per department, you will need to create a separate subscription per department. You can create multiple subscriptions in a single Azure Active Directory tenant.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: A reservation is where you commit to a resource (for example a virtual machine) for one or three years. This gives you a discounted price on the resource for the reservation period. Reservations do not provide a way to use different payment options per department.\nC: A resource group is a logical container for Azure resources. You can view the total cost of all the resources in a resource group. However, resource groups do not provide a way to use different payment options per department.\nD: A container instance is an Azure resource used to run an application. Container instances do not provide a way to use different payment options per department.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 321,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure free account has a spending limit. (Yes/No)\n- An Azure free account has a limit of 2TB of data that can be uploaded to Azure. (Yes/No)\n- An Azure free account can contain an unlimited number of web apps. (Yes/No)",
        "Answer": "YNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nAn Azure free account has a spending limit. This is currently 200 USD or 150 GBP.\n\nBox 2: No -\nAzure free account has a 5 GB blob storage limit and a 5 GB file storage limit.\n\nBox 3: No -\nAzure free account has a limit of 10 web, mobile or API apps",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 322,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure service in private preview is released to all Azure customers. (Y/N)\n- An Azure service in public preview is released to all Azure customers. (Y/N)\n- An Azure service in general availability is released to a subset of Azure customers. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nMost services go to private preview then public preview before being released to general availability. The private preview is only available to certain Azure customers for evaluation purposes.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nPublic Preview means that the service is in public beta and can be tried out by anyone with an Azure subscription. Services in public preview are often offered at a discount price.\nPublic previews are excluded from SLAs and in some cases, no support is offered.\n\nBox 3: No -\nAn Azure service in general availability is available to all Azure customers, not just a subset of the customers.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 323,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Availability zones can be implemented in all Azure regions. (Y/N)\n- Only VM that run Windows Server can be created in availability zones. (Y/N)\n- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications to multiple regions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "CONSUMPTION MODEL: Users only pay for the resources that they use, no up-front costs. No need to purchase/manage costly infrastructure that not use fullest.\nAbility to pay/stop paying for additional resources when needed.\nNo fixed rate for all data sends because resources are metered/billed according they consume.\nSERVERLES COMPUTING: Highly scalable/event-driven, only resources when a specific function or trigger occurs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 324,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The cost of Azure resources can vary between regions. (Y/N)\n- An Azure reservation is used to reserve server capacity at a specific data center. (Y/N)\n- You can stop an Azure SQL Database instance to decrease costs. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "Azure reservations can be used to reserve capacity for Azure virtual machines (VMs) or other Azure resources, such as Azure SQL Database. When you make a reservation, you are committing to a certain level of usage over a period of time, usually one or three years. In return, you receive a discounted rate for the reserved capacity.\n\nIf you bought Azure Reserved Virtual Machine Instances, you can change the optimize setting for the reservation. The reservation discount can apply to VMs in the same series or you can reserve data center capacity for a specific VM size. You should try to optimize reservations so that they're fully used.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 325,
        "Question": "You have an application that is comprised of an Azure web app that has a Service Level Agreement (SLA) of 99.95 percent and an Azure SQL database that has an SLA of 99.99 percent. The composite SLA for the application is [...].\nA. the product of both SLAs, which equals 99.94 percent \nB. the lowest SLA associated to the application, which is 99.95 percent \nC. the highest SLA associated to the application, which is 99.99 percent \nD. the difference between the two SLAs, which is 0.05 percent",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Composite SLAs involve multiple services supporting an application, each with differing levels of availability. For example, consider an App Service web app that writes to Azure SQL Database. At the time of this writing, these Azure services have the following SLAs:\n- App Service web apps = 99.95%\n- SQL Database = 99.99%\nWhat is the maximum downtime you would expect for this application? If either service fails, the whole application fails. The probability of each service failing is independent, so the composite SLA for this application is 99.95% \u05b3\u2014 99.99% = 99.94%. That's lower than the individual SLAs, which isn't surprising because an application that relies on multiple services has more potential failure points.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 326,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The Service Level Agreement (SLA) guaranteed uptime for paid Azure services is at least 99.9 percent. (Y/N)\n- Companies can increase the Service Level Agreement (SLA) guaranteed uptime by adding Azure resources to multiple regions. (Y/N)\n- Companies can increase the Service Level Agreement (SLA) guaranteed uptime by purchasing multiple subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nSLA's vary based on the resource type and the location distribution of the resource. However, the minimum uptime for all Azure services is 99.9 percent.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nThe SLA guaranteed uptime is increased (usually to 99.95 percent) when resources are deployed across multiple regions.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThe number of subscriptions is unrelated to uptime SLA's. You can deploy resources to multiple regions under a single subscription or you can have multiple subscriptions with resources deployed to the same region.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 327,
        "Question": "Which statement accurately describes the Modern Lifecycle Policy for Azure services?\nA. Microsoft provides mainstream support for a service for five years.\nB. Microsoft provides a minimum of 12 months' notice before ending support for a service.\nC. After a service is made generally available, Microsoft provides support for the service for a minimum of four years.\nD. When a service is retired, you can purchase extended support for the service for up to five years.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "For products governed by the Modern Lifecycle Policy, Microsoft will provide a minimum of 12 months' notification prior to ending support if no successor product or service is offered \u05d2\u20ac\" excluding free services or preview releases.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 328,
        "Question": "You need to request that Microsoft increase a subscription quota limit for your company.\nWhich blade should you use from the Azure portal? To answer, select the appropriate blade in the answer area.\nHot Area:\nA. Dashboard\nB. All Services\nC. Monitor\nD. Advisor\nE. Security Center\nF. Help + Support",
        "Answer": "F",
        "Explanation": "Request a standard quota increase from Help + support",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEF"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 329,
        "Question": "You can use [\u2026] in Azure to send email alerts when the cost of the current billing period for an Azure subscription exceeds a specified limit.\nA. Advisor recommendations\nB. Access control (IAM)\nC. Budget alerts\nD. Compliance",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Budget alerts notify you when spending, based on usage or cost, reaches or exceeds the amount defined in the alert condition of the budget. Cost Management budgets are created using the Azure portal or the Azure Consumption API.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 330,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- From the Azure portal, you can distinguish between services that are generally available and services that are in public preview. (Y/N)\n- After an Azure service becomes generally available, the service is no longer updated with new features. (Y/N)\n- When you create Azure resources for a service in public preview, you must recreate the resources once the service becomes generally available. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNN",
        "Explanation": "That a product is in generally available does not mean it can't be updated with new and exciting features",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 331,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- When using an Azure ExpressRoute connection, inbound data traffic from an on-premises network to Azure is always free. (Y/N)\n- Outbound data traffic from Azure to an on-premises network is always free. (N)\n- Data traffic between Azure services within the same Azure region is always free. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nWith Azure ExpressRoute, all inbound data transfer is free of charge.\n\nBox 2: No -\nInbound data traffic is free but outbound data traffic is not.\n\nBox 3: Yes -",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 332,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains the following unused resources:\n- 20 user accounts in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\n- Five groups in Azure AD\n- 10 public IP addresses\n- 10 network interfaces\nYou need to reduce the Azure costs for the company.\nWhich unused resources should you remove?\nA. the network interfaces\nB. the public IP addresses\nC. the groups\nD. the user accounts",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You are charged for public IP addresses. Therefore, deleting unused public IP addresses will reduce the Azure costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 333,
        "Question": "If an Azure virtual machine has a status of Stopped (deallocated), you will continue to pay for [...] \nA. compute capacity \nB. I/O operations \nC. networking \nD. storage",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "When a virtual machine is stopped (deallocated), the virtual machine is unloaded/dismounted from the physical server in Azure. In this state, you are not charged for the virtual machine itself. However, you are still charged for the storage costs of the virtual hard disks attached to the virtual machine.\nIf the virtual machine is stopped but not deallocated (this happens if you shut down the virtual machine from the operating system of the virtual machine), the virtual machine is still mounted on the physical server in Azure and you are charged for the virtual machine itself as well as the storage costs. To ensure that a virtual machine is 'stopped (deallocated)', you need to stop the virtual machine in the Azure portal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 334,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Storing 1 TB of data in Azure Blob storage will always cost the same, regardless of the Azure region in which the data is located. (Y/N)\n- When you use a general-purpose v2 Azure Storage account, you are only charged for the amount of data that is stored. All read and write opoerations are free. (Y/N)\n- Transferring data between Azure Storage accounts in different Azure regions is free. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nThe price of Azure storage varies by region. If you use the Azure storage pricing page, you can select different regions and see how the price changes per region.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou are charged for read and write operations in general-purpose v2 storage accounts.\n\nBox 3: No -\nYou would be charge for the read operations of the source storage account and write operations in the destination storage account.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 335,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- In Azure Active Directory Premium P2, at least 99.9 percent availability is guaranteed. (Y/N)\n- The Service Level Agreement (SLA) for Azure Active Directory Premium P2 is the same as the SLA for Azure Active Directory Free. (Y/N)\n- All paying Azure customers receive a credit if their monthly uptime percentage is below the guaranteed amount in the Service Level Agreement (SLA). (Y/N)\n\n\n\n",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nMicrosoft guarantee at least 99.9% availability of the Azure Active Directory Premium edition services. The services are considered available in the following scenarios:\n- Users are able to login to the service, login to the Access Panel, access applications on the Access Panel and reset passwords.\n- IT administrators are able to create, read, write and delete entries in the directory or provision or de-provision users to applications in the directory.\n\nBox 2: No -\nNo SLA is provided for the Free tier of Azure Active Directory.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nYou can claim credit if the availability falls below the SLA. The amount of credit depends on the availability. For example: You can claim 25% credit if the availability is less than 99.9%, 50% credit for less than 99% and 100% for less than 95% availability.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 336,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Adding resource groups in an Azure subscription generates additional costs. (Y/N)\n- Copying 10 GB of data to Azure from an on- premises network over a VPN generates additional Azure data transfer costs. (Y/N)\n- Copying 10 GB of data from Azure to an on- premises network over a VPN generates additional Azure data transfer costs. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. You do not pay for resource groups.\n\nBox 2: No -\nData ingress over a VPN is data 'coming in' to Azure over the VPN. You are not charged data transfer costs for data ingress.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nData egress over a VPN is data 'going out' of Azure over the VPN. You are charged for data egress.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 337,
        "Question": "Who can use the Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator?\nA. billing readers for an Azure subscription only\nB. owners for an Azure subscription only\nC. anyone\nD. all users who have an account in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) that is linked to an Azure subscription only",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "You don't need an Azure subscription to work with the TCO Calculator. Who can use the Azure TCO calculator?\nAzure TCO Calculator: What Is it Used For? For users wishing to adopt cloud services, Azure provides a web-based TCO Calculator. You can use this calculator to estimate the costs of migrating your data and applications to Azure and predict potential savings.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 338,
        "Question": "You deploy an Azure resource. The resource becomes unavailable for an extended period due to a service outage. Microsoft will [...].\nA. refund your bank account.\nB. migrate the resource to another subscription.\nC. credit your Azure account.\nD. send you a coupon code that you can redeem for Azure credits.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "If the SLA for an Azure service is not met, you receive credits for that service and that service only. The credits are deducted from your monthly bill for that service.\nIf you stopped using the service where the SLA was not met, your account would remain in credit for that service. The credits would not be applied to any other services that you may be using.\nService Credits apply only to fees paid for the particular Service, Service Resource, or Service tier for which a Service Level has not been met. In cases where\nService Levels apply to individual Service Resources or to separate Service tiers, Service Credits apply only to fees paid for the affected Service Resource or\nService tier, as applicable. The Service Credits awarded in any billing month for a particular Service or Service Resource will not, under any circumstance, exceed your monthly service fees for that Service or Service Resource, as applicable, in the billing month.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 339,
        "Question": "Which task can you perform by using Azure Advisor?\nA. Integrate Active Directory and Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\nB. Estimate the costs of an Azure solution.\nC. Confirm that Azure subscription security follows best practices.\nD. Evaluate which on-premises resources can be migrated to Azure.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Price estimation is provided by pricing calculator",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 340,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- If your company uses an Azure free account, you will only be able to use a subset of Azure services. (Y/N)\n- All Azure free accounts expire after a specific period. (Y/N)\n- You can create up to 10 Azure free accounts by using the same Microsoft account. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Free Account gives you 12 months access to the most popular free services. It also gives you a credit (150 GBP or 200 USD) to use on any Azure service for up to 30 days.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAll free accounts expire after 12 months.\n\nBox 3: No -\nYou can only create one free Azure account per Microsoft account.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 341,
        "Question": "How should you calculate the composite SLA for the application?\nA. 0.999 * 0.9999 = 0.9989001 = 99.89001%\nB. 0.999 / 0.9999 = 0.9991 = 99.91%\nC. Max(0.999, 0.9999) = 0.9999 = 99.99%\nD. Min(0.999, 0.9999) = 0.999 = 99.9%",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Composite SLAs involve multiple services supporting an application, each with differing levels of availability. For example, consider an App Service web app that writes to Azure SQL Database. At the time of this writing, these Azure services have the following SLAs:\n- App Service web apps = 99.95%\n- SQL Database = 99.99%\nWhat is the maximum downtime you would expect for this application? If either service fails, the whole application fails. The probability of each service failing is independent, so the composite SLA for this application is 99.95% \u05b3\u2014 99.99% = 99.94%. That's lower than the individual SLAs, which isn't surprising because an application that relies on multiple services has more potential failure points.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 342,
        "Question": "[\u2026] provide access to unused Azure compute capacity at deep discounts.\nA. Azure Container Instances\nB. Azure Reserved Virtual Machine Instances\nC. Azure Spot virtual machine instances\nD. Azure virtual machine scale sets\n",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Using Azure Spot Virtual Machines allows you to take advantage of our unused capacity at a significant cost savings. At any point in time when Azure needs the capacity back, the Azure infrastructure will evict Azure Spot Virtual Machines. Therefore, Azure Spot Virtual Machines are great for workloads that can handle interruptions like batch processing jobs, dev/test environments, large compute workloads, and more.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 343,
        "Question": "To save on the costs of an unused Azure virtual machine that runs Windows 10, you should [...].\nA. disconnect the virtual machine during a Remote Desktop session \nB. put the virtual machine in sleep mode from a Remote Desktop session select \nC. stop for the virtual machine from the Azure portal\nD. shut down the virtual machine from a Remote Desktop session",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "In the answers to these tests I have always placed myself in this vision: there is a right answer and a more right one. Shutting down the VM saves money, but using stop in Azure Portal deallocates resources (public IP for example) and saves more. Here I take the stop in the portal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 344,
        "Question": "All Azure services that are in public preview are [\u2026].\nA. provided without any documentation. \nB. only configurable from Azure CLI. \nC. excluded from the Service Level Agreements. \nD. only configurable from the Azure portal.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "During this phase we allow any customer with the proper Azure AD license to evaluate the new feature. Microsoft Customer Support Services will supply support services during this phase, but normal service level agreements do not apply.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABICD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 345,
        "Question": "If an Azure virtual machine has a status of Stopped (deallocated), you will continue to pay for [\u2026].\nA. compute capacity\nB.  I/O operations\nC. networking\nD. storage",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure doesn't charge for the VM core hours while it is Stopped (Deallocated). However, you continue to accrue charges for the Azure storage needed for the VM's\nOS disk and any attached data disks.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 346,
        "Question": "The [\u2026] explains what data Microsoft processes, how Microsoft processes the data, and the purpose of processing the data.\nA. Microsoft Online Services Privacy Statement\nB. Microsoft Product Terms\nC. Microsoft Online Service Level Agreement\nD. Online Subscription Agreement for Microsoft Azure",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Microsoft Privacy Statement explains what personal data Microsoft processes, how Microsoft processes the data, and the purpose of processing the data",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 347,
        "Question": "You can access Compliance Manager from the [\u2026].\nA. Azure Active Directory admin center\nB. Azure portal\nC. Microsoft 365 admin center\nD. Microsoft Service Trust portal",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Box: Microsoft 365 admin center -\n1. Go to the Microsoft 365 compliance center and sign in with your Microsoft 365 global administrator account.\n2. Select Compliance Manager on the left navigation pane. You'll arrive at your Compliance Manager dashboard.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 348,
        "Question": "You have 1,000 virtual machines hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou plan to migrate all the virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription.\nYou need to identify which expenditure model to use for the planned Azure solution.\nWhich expenditure model should you identify?\nA. scalable\nB. operational\nC. elastic\nD. capital",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "One of the major changes that you will face when you move from on-premises cloud to the public cloud is the switch from capital expenditure (buying hardware) to operating expenditure (paying for service as you use it). This switch also requires more careful management of your costs. The benefit of the cloud is that you can fundamentally and positively affect the cost of a service you use by merely shutting down or resizing it when it's not needed.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 349,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is an Apache Spark-based analytics service.\nA. Azure Databricks\nB. Azure Data Factory\nC. Azure DevOps\nD. Azure Synapse Analytics",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based big data analytics service designed for data science and data engineering.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 350,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A company has complete control of the resources and security for its private cloud. (Y/N)\n- A hybrid cloud solution enables a company to control whether its applications run on-premises or in the cloud. (Y/N)\n- Companies are responsible for capital expenditure when they scale up a virtual machine hosted in a public cloud. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "A company has complete control of the resources and security for its private cloud - Yes\nA Hybrid Cloud solution enables a company to control whether its applications run on-premises or in the cloud - Yes\nExplanation: Hybrid cloud computing enables an enterprise to deploy its most sensitive workloads in an on-premises cloud and to host less-critical resources on a third-party public cloud provider. This approach allows organizations to get the best of both private and public cloud models.\nCompanies are responsible for capital expenditure when they scale up a virtual machine hosted in a public cloud - No\nExplanation: With the public cloud, you get pay-as-you-go pricing \u2013 you pay only for what you use, no CapEx costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 351,
        "Question": "Which Service Level Agreement (SLA) is provided for Azure services in public preview?\nA. Each service defines its own SLA\nB. The SLA will be 99%\nC. The SLA will be 1% less than the general availability (GA) SLA\nD. The SLA will be 99.95%",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Public preview \u2013 During this phase we allow any customer with the proper Azure AD license to evaluate the new feature. Microsoft Customer Support Services will supply support services during this phase, but normal service level agreements do not apply. For new features exposed in the Azure AD Portal, customer can expect to see information banners in the user interface that draw attention to the new experience available during the preview. By clicking on the information banner customers then opt-in to the preview experience.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 352,
        "Question": "[\u2026] in Azure Firewall enables users on the internet to access a server on a virtual network :\nA. Application rules\nB. Network Address Translation (NAT) rules\nC. Network rules\nD. Service tags",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "DNAT rules allow or deny inbound traffic through the firewall public IP address(es). You can use a DNAT rule when you want a public IP address to be translated into a private IP address. The Azure Firewall public IP addresses can be used to listen to inbound traffic from the Internet, filter the traffic and translate this traffic to internal resources in Azure.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 353,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The cost of outbound traffic from Azure is the same for all Azure regions. (Y/N)\n- Purchasing Azure services through an Enterprise Agreement (EA) requires you to spend a predetermined amount. (Y/N)\n- Microsoft defines the pricing structure of all third-party services sold through Azure Marketplace. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nWithin most of the areas, there are clearly more expensive regions and less expensive regions.\nThe least expensive regions, on average across these instance types are us-west-2, us-west-central, and korea-south.\nThe most expensive regions are asia-pacific-east, japan-east, and australia-east.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nMany organizations with Microsoft Enterprise Agreements (EA) are adding Azure to their EA to enjoy the benefits it offers, such as:\nMinimizing Azure upfront costs by locking in pricing with consumption pre-commitment\nUsing Azure EA Portal to manage Azure Subscriptions easily and organize them under a single billing account\n\nBox 3: No - \nThe pricing structure of 3rd party services sold through the Azure Marketplace is determined by the individual vendors who offer the services. Azure provides a platform for vendors to sell their services, but the pricing and the structure of the pricing is determined by the vendors themselves.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 354,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Pay-As-You-Go (PAYG) is a consumption-based model. (Y/N)\n- Payments to cloud service providers are considered capital expenditures (CapEx). (Y/N)\n- The services provided through a consumption-based model are considered operational expenditures (OpEx). (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nThe Pay as You Go model is billed on a per second basis and you can start or stop the service at any time \u05d2\u20ac\" paying only for what you use.\n\nBox 2: No -\nNo, it is OpEx (Operational Expenditures).\nOpEx: The business can achieve ROI immediately in many cases because the infrastructure is managed by the cloud provider.\nCapEx: ROI is not usually realized until a long time after the purchase was made because the infrastructure needs to be set up and employees need to be trained.\nComputers, servers, and other hardware needed for on-premises data centers are all examples of CapEx.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nOperational Expenditures (OpEx) are the ongoing costs related to day-to-day operations. A subscription fee for cloud services is considered OpEx\u05d2\u20ac\"the cloud provider is making the infrastructure investment upfront, and you only pay for the resources you need as you need them.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 355,
        "Question": "What is the longest term you can purchase for Azure Reserved VM instances?\nA. one year\nB. five years\nC. four years\nD. three years",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Reservations help you save money by committing to one-year or three-year plans for multiple products. Committing allows you to get a discount on the resources you use. Reservations can significantly reduce your resource costs by up to 72% from pay-as-you-go prices.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 356,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- All Azure services in private preview must be accessed by using a separate Azure portal. (Y/N)\n- Azure services in public preview can be used in production environments. (Y/N)\n- Azure services in public preview are subject to a Service Level Agreement (SLA). (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Public Preview means that the service is in public beta and can be tried out by anyone with an Azure subscription. Services in public preview are often offered at a discount price.\n\nBox 1: No -\nServices in private preview can be viewed in the regular Azure portal. However, you need to be signed up for the feature in private preview before you can view it.\nAccess to private preview features is usually by invitation only.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nYou can use services in public preview in production environments. However, you should be aware that the service may have faults, is not subject to an SLA and may be withdrawn without notice.\n\nBox 3: No -\nPublic previews are excluded from SLAs and in some cases, no support is offered.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 357,
        "Question": "Your company has 10 offices. You plan to generate several billing reports from the Azure portal. Each report will contain the Azure resource utilization of each office.\nWhich Azure Resource Manager feature should you use before you generate the reports?\nA. tags\nB. templates\nC. locks\nD. policies",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "You can use resource tags to 'label' Azure resources. Tags are metadata elements attached to resources. Tags consist of pairs of key/value strings. In this question, we would tag each resource with a tag to identify each office. For example: Location = Office1. When all Azure resources are tagged, you can generate reports to list all resources based on the value of the tag. For example: All resources used by Office1.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 358,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A Standard support plan is included in an Azure free account. (Y/N)\n- A Premier support plan can only be purchased by companies that have an Enterprise Agreement (EA). (Y/N)\n- Support from MSDN forums is only provided to companies that have a pay-as-you-go subscription. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAn Azure free account comes with a 'basic' support plan, not a 'standard' support plan.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nYou can purchase the Professional Direct, Standard, and Developer support plans with the Microsoft Customer Agreement. You can also purchase the\nProfessional and Standard support plans with the Enterprise Agreement.\n\nBox 3: No -\nUsers with any type of Azure subscription (pay-as-you-go, Enterprise Agreement, Microsoft Customer Agreement etc.) can get support from the MSDN forums.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 359,
        "Question": "If Microsoft plans to end support for an Azure service that does NOT have a successor service, Microsoft will provide notification at least 12 months before.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed.\nB. 6 months\nC. 90 days\nD. 30 days",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Modern Lifecycle Policy covers products and services that are serviced and supported continuously. For products governed by the Modern Lifecycle Policy,\nMicrosoft will provide a minimum of 12 months' notification prior to ending support if no successor product or service is offered, excluding free services or preview releases.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 360,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A user who is assigned the Owner role can transfer ownership of an Azure subscription. (Y/N)\n- You can convert the Azure subscription of your company from Free Trial to Pay-As-You-Go. (Y/N)\n- The Azure spending limit is fixed and cannot be increased or decreased. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou need to be an administrator of the billing account that has the subscription to be able to transfer the subscription. This could be a Billing Administrator or\nGlobal Administrator. A subscription owner can manage all resources and permissions within the subscription but cannot transfer ownership of the subscription.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nYou can convert a free trial subscription to Pay-As-You-Go. This is common practice for people who wish to continue using the Azure services when the free trial period expires.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nYou can remove the spending limit, but you can't increase or decrease it.\nThe spending limit in Azure prevents spending over your credit amount. All new customers who sign up for an Azure free account or subscription types that include credits over multiple months have the spending limit turned on by default. The spending limit is equal to the amount of credit and it can't be changed. For example, if you signed up for Azure free account, your spending limit is $200 and you can't change it to $500. However, you can remove the spending limit. So, you either have no limit, or you have a limit equal to the amount of credit.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 361,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- With Azure Reservations, you pay less for virtual machines than with pay-as-you-go pricing. (Y/N)\n- Two Azure virtual machines that use the B2S size have the same monthly costs. (Y/N)\n- When an Azure virtual machine is stopped, you continue to pay storage costs for the virtual machine. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nA reservation is where you commit to pay for a resource (for example a virtual machine) for one or three years. This gives you a discounted price on the resource for the reservation period.\n\nBox 2: No -\nThere are other factors that influence the cost of a virtual machine such as the virtual hard disks attached to the virtual machine. You could have multiple virtual machines with the same 'size' (B2S in this case) but with different virtual hard disk configurations.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nWhen a virtual machine is stopped (deallocated), the virtual machine is unloaded/dismounted from the physical server in Azure. In this state, you are not charged for the virtual machine itself. However, you are still charged for the storage costs of the virtual hard disks attached to the virtual machine.\nIf the virtual machine is stopped but not deallocated (this happens if you shut down the virtual machine from the operating system of the virtual machine), the virtual machine is still mounted on the physical server in Azure and you are charged for the virtual machine itself as well as the storage costs. To ensure that a virtual machine is 'stopped (deallocated)', you need to stop the virtual machine in the Azure portal.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 362,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains the following unused resources:\n- 20 user accounts in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\n- Five groups in Azure AD\n- 10 public IP addresses\n- 10 network interfaces\nYou need to reduce the Azure costs for the company.\nSolution: You remove the unused network interfaces.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "N",
        "Explanation": "You are not charged for unused network interfaces. Therefore, deleting unused network interfaces will not reduce the Azure costs for the company.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 363,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains the following unused resources:\n- 20 user accounts in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\n- Five groups in Azure AD \n- 10 public IP addresses\n- 10 network interfaces\nYou need to reduce the Azure costs for the company.\nSolution: You remove the unused public IP addresses.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "Y",
        "Explanation": "You are charged for public IP addresses. Therefore, deleting unused public IP addresses will reduce the Azure costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 364,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains the following unused resources:\n- 20 user accounts in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\n- Five groups in Azure AD\n- 10 public IP addresses\n- 10 network interfaces\nYou need to reduce the Azure costs for the company.\nSolution: You remove the unused user accounts.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "N",
        "Explanation": "You are not charged for user accounts. Therefore, deleting unused user accounts will not reduce the Azure costs for the company.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 365,
        "Question": "How should you calculate the monthly uptime percentage? To answer, select the appropriate options in the answer area.\nA. (Downtime in Minutes / Maximum Available Minutes) * 100\nB. (Maximum Available Minutes / Maximum Available Minutes) * 100\nC. (Maximum Available Minutes - Downtime in Minutes) / Maximum Available Minutes) * 100",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "\"Maximum Available Minutes\" is the total accumulated minutes during a billing month .\n\"Downtime\" is the total accumulated minutes that are part of Maximum Available Minutes where a system is unavailable.\n\"Monthly Uptime Percentage\" for a service is calculated as Maximum Available Minutes less Downtime divided by Maximum Available Minutes x 100.\nMonthly Uptime Percentage is represented by the following formula:\nMonthly Uptime % = (Maximum Available Minutes-Downtime) / Maximum Available Minutes x 100.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 366,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- By creating additional resource groups in an Azure subscription, additional costs are incurred. (Y/N)\n- By copying several gigabits of data to Azure from an on-premises network over a VPN, additional data transfer costs are incurred. (Y/N)\n- By copying several GB of data from Azure to an on-premises network over a VPN, additional data transfer costs are incurred. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Box 1: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. You do not pay for resource groups.\n\nBox 2: No -\nData ingress over a VPN is data 'coming in' to Azure over the VPN. You are not charged data transfer costs for data ingress.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nData egress over a VPN is data 'going out' of Azure over the VPN. You are charged for data egress.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 367,
        "Question": "A support plan solution that gives you best practice information, health status and notifications, and 24/7 access to billing information at the lowest possible cost is a Standard support plan.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. Developer\nC. Basic\nD. Premier",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "A basic support plan provides:\n- 24x7 access to billing and subscription support, online self-help, documentation, whitepapers, and support forums\n- Best practices: Access to full set of Azure Advisor recommendations\n- Health Status and Notifications: Access to personalized Service Health Dashboard & Health API",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 368,
        "Question": "In which Azure support plans can you open a new support request?\nA. Premier and Professional Direct only\nB. Premier, Professional Direct, and Standard only\nC. Premier, Professional Direct, Standard, and Developer only\nD. Premier, Professional Direct, Standard, Developer, and Basic",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "You can submit support request tickets in the following plans: Premier, Professional Direct, Standard, Developer, and Basic.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 369,
        "Question": "You can create an Azure support request from support.microsoft.com.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed.` If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed.\nB. the Azure portal\nC. the Knowledge Center\nD. the Security & Compliance admin center",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can create an Azure support request from the Help and Support blade in the Azure portal or from the context menu of an Azure resource in the Support +\nTroubleshooting section.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 370,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains the following unused resources:\n- 20 user accounts in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD)\n- Five groups in Azure AD\n- 10 public IP addresses\n- 10 network interfaces\nYou need to reduce the Azure costs for the company.\nSolution: You remove the unused groups.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You are not charged for Azure Active Directory Groups. Therefore, deleting unused groups will not reduce your Azure costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "yesno",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 371,
        "Question": "The Azure Standard support plan is the lowest cost option to receive 24x7 access to support engineers by phone.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. Developer\nC. Basic\nD. Professional Direct",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Basic support plan is free so is therefore the cheapest. The Developer support plan is the cheapest paid-for support plan. The order of support plans in terms of cost ranging from the cheapest to most expensive is: Basic, Developer, Standard, Professional Direct, Premier.\nHowever, 24/7 access to technical support by email and phone is only available for Standard, Professional Direct, Premier plans.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 372,
        "Question": "All Azure services that are in public preview are [\u2026].\nA. provided without any documentation. \nB. only configurable from Azure CLI\nC. excluded from the Service Level Agreements. \nD. only configurable from the Azure portal.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "During this phase we allow any customer with the proper Azure AD license to evaluate the new feature. Microsoft Customer Support Services will supply support services during this phase, but normal service level agreements do not apply.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 373,
        "Question": "[\u2026] can calculate cost savings due to reduced electricity consumption as a result of migrating on-premises Microsoft SQL servers to Azure.\nA. The Azure Migrate: Server Assessment tool\nB. The Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator \nC. The Database Migration Assistant \nD. The pricing calculator in Azure",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "migrating = TCO",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 374,
        "Question": "You need to compare a company's cloud usage to industry standard best practices.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Monitor\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Application Insights in Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Advisor",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Keyword ''Best practices\" - Azure Advisor",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 375,
        "Question": "You need to start Azure Cloud Shell.\nWhat should you use?\nA. the Azure portal\nB. Azure Command-Line Interface (CLI)\nC. Azure PowerShell\nD. an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) template",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Azure Cloud Shell is an interactive, authenticated, browser-accessible shell for managing Azure resources. It provides the flexibility of choosing the shell experience that best suits the way you work, either Bash or PowerShell.\n\nYou can access Cloud Shell in three ways:\n- Direct link: Open a browser to https://shell.azure.com.\n- Azure portal: Select the Cloud Shell icon on the Azure portal\n- Code samples: In Microsoft technical documentation and training resources, select the Try It button that appears with Azure CLI and Azure PowerShell code snippets",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 376,
        "Question": "How many copies of data are maintained by an Azure Storage account that uses locally-redundant storage (LRS)?\nA. 3\nB. 4\nC. 6\nD. 9",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Locally redundant storage (LRS) replicates your storage account three times within a single data center in the primary region. LRS provides at least 99.999999999% (11 nines) durability of objects over a given year.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 377,
        "Question": "What enables a cloud service to adapt quickly to changing requirements?\nA. high availability\nB. predictability\nC. manageability\nD. agility",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Agility: The ability to react quickly. Cloud services can allocate and deallocate resources quickly. They are provided on-demand via self-service, so vast amounts of computing resources can be provisioned in minutes. There is no manual intervention in provisioning or deprovisioning services.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 378,
        "Question": "What is an example of vertical scaling in a cloud environment?\nA. adding an additional CPU to an existing Azure virtual machine\nB. adding an additional Azure virtual machine\nC. adding an additional Azure Virtual Desktop session host\nD. adding an additional Azure App Service instance automatically",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Vertical scaling is adding more power or memory ie CPU or RAM to an existing machine.Whereas horizontal scaling is scaling by adding more machines to your pool",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 379,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Microsoft Defender for Cloud can monitor Azure resources and on-premises resources. (Y/N)\n- All Microsoft Defender for Cloud features are free. (Y/N)\n- For Microsoft Defender for Cloud, you can download a Regulatory Compliance report. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Yes, Microsoft Defender for Cloud can monitor Azure resources and on-premises resources.\n\nNo, not all Microsoft Defender for Cloud features are free. Some features may require additional licensing or subscription.\n\nYes, you can download a Regulatory Compliance report for Microsoft Defender for Cloud. The report includes information about compliance with various regulations and standards, such as GDPR, ISO 27001, and HIPAA.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 380,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Cloud computing offers lower capital expenditure (CAPEX) costs than on-premises deployments. (Y/N)\n- Cloud computing provides the same configuration options as on-premises deployments. (Y/N)\n- Cloud computing can scale when a business requires change. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Capital expenditures (CapEx) are funds used by a company to acquire, upgrade, and maintain physical assets such as property, plants, buildings, technology, or equipment. These costs are lower in cloud computing than in on-premises deployments.\n\nCloud computing in general provides the same configuration options as on-premises deployments. If you compare a specific product such as Exchange Online vs. Exchange Server or Azure SQL vs. SQL Server this might not be true. But, you could install Exchange Server on a virtual machine in the cloud to get the same configuration options.\n\nCloud computing allows to increase or decrease IT resources as needed to meet changing demand. Scalability is one of the hallmarks of the cloud and the primary driver of its exploding popularity with businesses.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 381,
        "Question": "What additional resource is required by an Azure virtual machine?\nA. a virtual network\nB. a service endpoint\nC. Azure Firewall\nD. a public IP address",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "To determine which additional resource is typically required by an Azure Virtual Machine (VM), let's look at each option:\nA. A virtual network - An Azure VM must be connected to a virtual network (VNet) to communicate with other resources within Azure or to connect to the internet, unless it's an isolated or private scenario where no external connectivity is needed.\n\nB. A service endpoint - Service endpoints provide secure and direct connectivity to Azure services over the Azure backbone network. They are not mandatory for a VM to function, but they are used to restrict access to Azure service resources to only your virtual network.\n\nC. Azure Firewall - This is a managed, cloud-based network security service that protects your Azure Virtual Network resources. It is not a mandatory resource for a VM to operate.\n\nD. A public IP address - A public IP address is not strictly required unless you need to access the VM from the internet. For internal communication within the same Azure VNet or between VNets, a public IP is not necessary.\n\nBased on this information, the resource that is typically required for a VM to operate within Azure's environment is A. a virtual network. Without a VNet, the VM would not be able to establish any network connectivity, which is fundamental for most use cases.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 382,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Functions is an example of a platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service model. (Y/N)\n- Microsoft 365 is an example of a software as a service (SaaS) cloud service model. (Y/N)\n- An Azure virtual machine is an example of an infrastructure as a service (laaS) cloud service model. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Yes, Azure Functions is an example of a cloud service that can be classified as both a Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) and a Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) model.\n\nAs a PaaS model, Azure Functions provides a platform for developers to deploy and manage their serverless applications without having to worry about the underlying infrastructure. Azure Functions abstracts away the underlying servers, storage, and networking, and allows developers to focus on their code and business logic.\n\nAs a FaaS model, Azure Functions allows developers to write and deploy small, event-driven functions that automatically scale and run in response to incoming events or triggers. These functions are billed based on their execution time and the resources used during that time.\n\nTherefore, Azure Functions is an example of a cloud service that can be classified as both a PaaS and a FaaS model, depending on the context in which it is being used.\n\nSo the answer is Y Y Y.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 383,
        "Question": "How many copies of data are maintained by an Azure Storage account that uses geo-redundant storage (GRS)?\nA. 3\nB. 4\nC. 6\nD. 9",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "6 data copies. GRS is replicating in two regions, and in each region a physical location which replicates 3 times each. 2x3 = 6.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 384,
        "Question": "What is used to grant permission to Azure Virtual Desktop resources?\nA. tags\nB. role-based access control (RBAC) roles\nC. resource groups\nD. application security groups",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Virtual Desktop uses Azure role-based access control (RBAC) to control access to resources. There are a number of built-in roles for use with Azure Virtual Desktop which is a collection of permissions. You assign roles to users and admins and these roles give permission to carry out certain tasks.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 385,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure virtual networks deployed to the same Azure region are connected by default. (Y/N)\n- Virtual networks created in the same resource group must have unique names. (Y/N)\n- The Azure virtual network's address space must be unique within a subscription. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Azure virtual networks deployed to the same Azure region are connected by default. No, Azure virtual networks are not connected by default, even if they are in the same region. You must explicitly connect them using VNet peering or another connectivity solution.\n\nVirtual networks created in the same resource group must have unique names. Yes, within the same resource group, all resources, including virtual networks, must have unique names. This is a general Azure resource management requirement.\n\nThe Azure virtual network's address space must be unique within a subscription. No, the address space for Azure virtual networks does not need to be unique within a subscription. However, if you plan to connect VNets, the address spaces should not overlap to avoid routing issues.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 386,
        "Question": "A. Disaster recovery\nB. Geo-Distribution\nC. High Availability\nD. Scalability \n1. Provide a continuous user experience in the event of a resource failure.\n2. Deploy apps and data to regional data centers that are located close to users.\n3. Compute capacity can be increased dynamically by adding RAM or CPU to a virtual machine.",
        "Answer": "B2C1D3",
        "Explanation": "High availability\nWhen you\u2019re deploying an application, a service, or any IT resources, it\u2019s important the resources are available when needed. High availability focuses on ensuring maximum availability, regardless of disruptions or events that may occur.\n\nScalability\nAnother major benefit of cloud computing is the scalability of cloud resources. Scalability refers to the ability to adjust resources to meet demand. If you suddenly experience peak traffic and your systems are overwhelmed, the ability to scale means you can add more resources to better handle the increased demand.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 387,
        "Question": "A. ExpressRoute\nB. Virtual Network peering\nC. VPN gateway\n1. Extends on-premises networks to the Microsoft cloud via a private connection\n2. Combines two or more Azure virtual networks into a single logical virtual network\n3. Provides an encrypted connection from on-premises networks to Azure via a public network",
        "Answer": "A1B2C3",
        "Explanation": "Remember that, since ExpressRoute is a dedicated connection between on-premises and Azure, that does not use the public Internet and the traffic is not encrypted.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 388,
        "Question": "[\u2026] ensures thant you cdan calculate how much a cloud service will cost.\nA. agility\nB. elasticity\nC. geo-distribution\nD. predictability",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Predictability in the cloud lets you move forward with confidence. Predictability can be focused on performance predictability or cost predictability. Both performance and cost predictability are heavily influenced by the Microsoft Azure Well-Architected Framework. Deploy a solution that\u2019s built around this framework and you have a solution that\u2019s cost and performance are predictable.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 389,
        "Question": "Which cloud service model minimizes the management responsibility of a customer?\nA. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nB. platform as a service (PaaS)\nC. software as a service (SaaS)",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The shared responsibility model applies to all the cloud service types. SaaS is the model that places the most responsibility with the cloud provider and the least responsibility with the user. In a SaaS environment you\u2019re responsible for the data that you put into the system, the devices that you allow to connect to the system, and the users that have access. Nearly everything else falls to the cloud provider. The cloud provider is responsible for physical security of the datacenters, power, network connectivity, and application development and patching.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 390,
        "Question": "You need to identify a customer\u2019s level of shared responsibility based on the cloud service model.\nIn which order should you list each model from most customer responsibility to least customer responsibility? To answer, move all models from the list of models to the answer area and arrange them in the correct order.\nA. PaaS\nB. SaaS\nC. IaaS",
        "Answer": "CAB",
        "Explanation": "Answer is correct: IaaS - customer has most responsibility for compute resources management (VMs, OS, SW installations, etc); PaaS - somewhere in the middle - configure e.g. AppService and deploy code there. SaaS - configure already deployed service, so customer provides only data. This is least responsibility.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 391,
        "Question": "An organization that hosts its own infrastructure [\u2026] no longer requires a data center.\n- in a private cloud \n- in a hybrid cloud \n- in the public cloud \n- on a Hyper-V host",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "The answer is Public Cloud. It's a tricky question but once it owns its infrastructure in the cloud, it no longer needs a data center (as on-premises), so the answer should be Public cloud. The key is \"no longer requires a data center\".",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": null
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 392,
        "Question": "An organization that hosts its own infrastructure [\u2026].\n- elasticity\n- governance\n- high availability\n- predictibility\n- reliability",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Elastic computing is the ability to quickly expand or decrease computer processing, memory, and storage resources to meet changing demands without worrying about capacity planning and engineering for peak usage. Typically controlled by system monitoring tools, elastic computing matches the amount of resources allocated to the amount of resources actually needed without disrupting operations. With cloud elasticity, a company avoids paying for unused capacity or idle resources and doesn\u2019t have to worry about investing in the purchase or maintenance of additional resources and equipment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": null
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 393,
        "Question": "[\u2026] runs application code in Azure without requiring a server.\nA. An Azure DevOps pipeline\nB. An Azure Resource Manager template \nC. Azure Application Gateway\nD. Azure Functions",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure function = serverless",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 394,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The Archive access tier for Azure Storage can be set at the account level. (Y/N)\n- The Cool access tier offers the lowest costs for storing blobs in Azure Storage. (Y/N)\n- After blobs are uploaded to an Azure Storage container, the access tier of the storage account can be changed. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "No, the Archive access tier for Azure storage cannot be set at the account level. It can only be set at the container or blob level. Each blob within a container can have its own access tier, so you have the flexibility to set different access tiers for different blobs within the same container.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 395,
        "Question": "A. Azure Blob Storage\nB. Azure Disk Storage\nC. Azure Files\nD. Azure Queue Storage\n1. Used for reliable messaging between applications\n2. Can be accessed as a network share from a Windows device\n3. Can be configured to use the Archive access tier",
        "Answer": "A3C2D1",
        "Explanation": "I think the answer is correct\nAzure Queue Storage is a service for storing large numbers of messages. You access messages from anywhere in the world via authenticated calls using HTTP or HTTPS. A queue message can be up to 64 KB in size. A queue may contain millions of messages, up to the total capacity limit of a storage account. Queues are commonly used to create a backlog of work to process asynchronously",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 396,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Premium storage accounts can be configured as Azure file shares. (Y/N)\n- Premium storage accounts can be configured as block blobs storage. (Y/N)\n- Premium storage accounts can be configured as StorageV2 storage. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "1: True.\nPremium storage accounts provide high-performance storage for Azure virtual machines. Using premium storage accounts to create file shares can provide better performance and increased reliability compared to standard storage accounts.\n\n2:True.\nBlock blobs are used to store unstructured data, such as text and images, and can be up to 4.75 TB in size. Using premium storage accounts for block blobs can provide better performance and increased reliability compared to standard storage accounts.\n\n3: False.\nPremium storage accounts cannot be configured as a storageV2 storage accounts. StorageV2 storage account is a new version of General purpose storage accounts, that provide all the features of the General purpose v1 and additional features and capabilities such as larger file shares, higher IOPS and throughput, and archive storage tier.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 397,
        "Question": "Premium block blobs storage accounts only support [\u2026] redundancy.\nA. geo-redundant storage (GRS) \nB. geo-zone-redundant storage (GZRS) \nC. locally-redundant storage (LRS) \nD. zone-redundant storage (ZRS)\n",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Premium Disk Storage currently supports only locally redundant storage (LRS). Block blob storage accounts support locally redundant storage (LRS) and zone redundant storage (ZRS) in certain regions\n\nAs an example if you select the region \"Canada Central\", LRS is the only redundancy option available for all the premium options page blobs, block blobs and file shares.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 398,
        "Question": "You have an Azure web app.\n\nYou need to manage the settings of the web app from an iPhone.\nWhat are two Azure management tools that you can use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Windows PowerShell\nB. Azure Cloud Shell\nC. the Azure portal\nD. Azure Storage Explorer",
        "Answer": "BC",
        "Explanation": "The Azure portal is the web-based portal for managing Azure. Being web-based, you can use the Azure portal on an iPhone.\nAzure Cloud Shell is a web-based command line for managing Azure. You access the Azure Cloud Shell from the Azure portal. Being web-based, you can use the\nAzure Cloud Shell on an iPhone.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: Azure CLI can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.\nD: Windows PowerShell can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 399,
        "Question": "You need to create a new Azure file share.\nWhat should you use? To answer, select the service in the answer area.\nA. Resource groups\nB. Quickstart Center\nC. App Services\nD. Function App\nE. SQL Databases\nF. Azure Cosmos DB\nG. Virtual machines\nH. Load balancers\nI. Storage accounts\nJ. Virtual networks\nK. Azure Active Directory\nL. Monitor\nM. Advisor\nN. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nO. Help + support\nP. Cost Management + Billing",
        "Answer": "I",
        "Explanation": "Azure file shares are deployed into storage accounts",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOP"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 400,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can deploy Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates by using the Azure portal. (Y/N)\n- Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates can define infrastructure by using code. (Y/N)\n- Each Azure resource to be deployed requires a separate Azure Resource Manager (ARM) template. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "It is not necessary to use a separate template for each resource. For example, an ARM template can define a virtual machine, a storage account, and a virtual network altogether in a single template.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 401,
        "Question": "What should you use to prevent traffic from an Azure virtual network from being routed to an Azure Storage account via the internet?\nA. a network security group (NSG)\nB. a public endpoint\nC. Azure VPN Gateway\nD. a service endpoint",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Network Security Groups (NSGs) control inbound and outbound traffic within a virtual network and don't prevent internet routing to Azure Storage.\nPublic endpoints are not used to prevent internet access to Azure Storage, but rather provide private access from a virtual network.\nAzure VPN Gateways create secure tunnels to on-premises networks, not directly related to controlling internet access to Azure Storage.\nService endpoints route traffic between a virtual network and an Azure service (like Storage) through the Microsoft backbone instead of the internet, ensuring data stays within Microsoft's secure network.\nTherefore, service endpoints are the most suitable option for preventing internet routing to an Azure Storage account from a virtual network.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 402,
        "Question": "Which service can replace a resource lock automatically if the lock is removed?\nA. Azure Information Protection (AIP)\nB. Azure Blueprints\nC. Azure Backup\nD. Azure Advisor",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Blueprints can replace a resource lock automatically if the lock is removed. A resource lock is a setting that you apply to a resource to prevent accidental deletion or modification of the resource. When a lock is applied to a resource, it blocks any operations that would modify or delete the resource.\n\nIf a resource lock is removed, it can leave the resource vulnerable to accidental deletion or modification. However, if the resource is associated with an Azure Blueprint, the Blueprint can automatically replace the lock to help protect the resource. This is because Azure Blueprints enforce compliance with policies and standards across multiple subscriptions, environments, and regions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 403,
        "Question": "You need to create a new user for an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use? To answer, select the service in the answer area.\nA. Create a resource\nB. Virtual machines\nC. Cost Management...\nD. Subscriptions\nE. Azure Active Directory\nF. Virtual machines...\nG. All resources\nH. App Services\nI. Resource groups\nJ. All services",
        "Answer": "E",
        "Explanation": "The answer is E. Azure Active Directory. Here's a short explanation:\n\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) is Microsoft's cloud-based identity and access management solution. It's designed to:\nManage user accounts and their permissions\nControl access to applications and resources within Azure\nEnable secure authentication and authorization\nWhy not the other options:\n\nCreate a resource: This is a generic Azure portal action, not specific to user creation.\nVirtual machines, Cost Management, Subscriptions, etc.: These deal with different Azure resources, not user management.\nLet me know if you'd like a more in-depth explanation of Azure AD!",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDEFGHIJ"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 404,
        "Question": "Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates use the [\u2026].\nA. CSV format.\nB. HTML format.\nC. JSON format.\nD. XML format.",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "To implement infrastructure as code for your Azure solutions, use Azure Resource Manager templates (ARM templates). The template is a JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) file that defines the infrastructure and configuration for your project. The template uses declarative syntax, which lets you state what you intend to deploy without having to write the sequence of programming commands to create it. In the template, you specify the resources to deploy and the properties for those resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 405,
        "Question": "You plan to collect and analyze event details for five Azure virtual machines.\n\nYou need to run queries to compare the event details collected from all the virtual machines.\n\nWhich two tools should you use? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nA. Azure Service Health\nB. Azure Service Bus\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Advisor\nE. Log Analytics",
        "Answer": "AE",
        "Explanation": "Azure Monitor is a comprehensive monitoring solution for Azure services that includes several monitoring tools and services. It provides a unified view of all your Azure resources, including virtual machines, and enables you to collect, analyze, and act on telemetry data from those resources.\n\nLog Analytics is a tool within Azure Monitor that enables you to collect and analyze log data from your virtual machines and other Azure resources. You can use Log Analytics to run queries and create visualizations based on the log data, and to set up alerts and notifications based on specific events or conditions.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 406,
        "Question": "An Azure SLA is a formal agreement between Microsoft and a customer that defines:\nA. a commitment to deliver the features on a technology roadmap.\nB. a commitment to performance standards.\nC. the maximum scalability limits of an available infrastructure.\nD. the minimum scalability limits of an available infrastructure.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "An Azure Service Level Agreement (SLA) is a formal agreement between Microsoft and a customer that defines the level of service and availability that Microsoft will provide for a specific Azure service.\nThe SLA typically includes metrics such as uptime, availability, and responsiveness, and specifies the guarantees that Microsoft will make in terms of meeting those metrics.\n\nIn more detail, an Azure SLA outlines the service level targets and credit system for Azure service, ensuring that customer will receive a credit towards their bill if they don't meet the agreed-upon service level. It guarantees a certain level of uptime (i.e. availability) for a given Azure service, and if that service falls below that level, customer may be eligible for a service credit to be applied to their account.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 407,
        "Question": "What should you use to track the costs of Azure resources?\nA. Azure Quickstart templates\nB. tags\nC. budgets\nD. usage and quotas",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Here's a short explanation:\n\nAzure Quickstart templates are used to deploy infrastructure resources, not track costs.\nTags are useful for categorizing resources, but they don't inherently track costs.\nBudgets help set spending limits and alerts, but don't directly track ongoing costs.\nUsage and quotas provide detailed information on resource consumption and associated costs, making them the primary tool for tracking Azure resource costs.\nTherefore, D. usage and quotas is the best option for tracking Azure resource costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 408,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription.\nYou plan to create a virtual machine.\nWhere will the virtual machine be placed in Azure?\nA. In a storage account\nB. In a resource group\nC. In an administrative unit\nD. In an application group",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "in \"Resource Group\". All other options are irrelevant to the context of the Q.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 409,
        "Question": "When planning to migrate a public website to Azure, you must plan to:\nA. Deploy a VPN\nB. Pay monthly usage costs\nC. Pay to transfer all the website data to Azure\nD. Reduce the number of connections to the website",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "A. deploy a VPN: Depending on your organization's security requirements and the nature of your website, you may or may not need to deploy a VPN to secure your connection between your on-premises network and Azure.\n\nB. pay monthly usage costs: Azure is a pay-as-you-go service, which means that you will be charged based on your usage. You must plan to pay monthly usage costs for the Azure services and resources you use to host your website.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 410,
        "Question": "[\u2026] provides a global view of the status of Azure services, regions, and specific resources.\nA. Application Insights\nB. Azure Advisor\nC. Azure Service Health",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Service Health: Provides a global view of the health status of Azure services, regions, and resources, with information about incidents and planned maintenance.\n\nAzure Advisor: Provides personalized recommendations to optimize the efficiency of your Azure resources based on best practices.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 411,
        "Question": "You plan to reduce ongoing Azure expenditures.\nYou need to identify which factors affect the costs of a resource.\nWhich three factors should you identify? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nA. the volume of outbound data\nB. the volume of inbound data\nC. the service tier\nD. the Azure region\nE. the type of processed data",
        "Answer": "ACE",
        "Explanation": "ACD. The type of the processed data is none of Microsoft's business, as it's ours.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 412,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains several resources.\nYou need to identify which department is responsible for the cost of each resource.\nWhat should you use?\nA. budgets\nB. alerts\nC. tags",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Tags can be used for drilling down into costs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 413,
        "Question": "Azure Cosmos DB is an example of a [\u2026] offering.\nA. platform as a service (PaaS)\nB. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nC. content as a service (CaaS)\nD. software as a service (SaaS)",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Correct PaaS ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 414,
        "Question": "Data that is stored in the Archive access tier of an Azure Storage account:\nA. can be accessed at any time by using azcopy.exe.\nB. can only be read by using Azure Backup.\nC. must be restored before the data can be accessed.\nD. must be rehydrated before the data can be accessed.",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Answer is \"must be rehydrated before the data can be accessed.\"",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 415,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure Virtual Desktop session host can run Windows 10 or Windows 11 only. (Y/N)\n- An Azure Virtual Desktop host pool that includes 20 session hosts supports maximum of 20 simultaneous user connections. (Y/N)\n- Azure Virtual Desktop supports desktop and app virtualization. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "YES - Not only\n\nNO -  While a pool with 20 session hosts can potentially accommodate 20 users, factors like licensing and session settings can limit the actual number of concurrent connections.\n\nYES - Azure Virtual Desktop allows users to access both virtualized desktops and individual applications streamed to their devices.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 416,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- In an Azure virtual machine scale set, the virtual machines are configured identically. (Y/N)\n- The number of Azure virtual machines in a virtual machine scale set can increase automatically. (Y/N)\n- The number of Azure virtual machines in a virtual machine scale set can decrease automatically. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Allows your application to automatically scale as resource demand changes:\nCustomer demand for your application may change throughout the day or week. To match customer demand, scale sets can automatically increase the number of VM instances as application demand increases, then reduce the number of VM instances as demand decreases.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 417,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can have two Azure Storage accounts that have the same name in the same Azure subscription. (Y/N)\n- You can have two Azure Storage accounts that have the same name in different Azure regions. (Y/N)\n- You can have two Azure Storage accounts that have the same name in two different Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNN",
        "Explanation": "In Azure, storage account names must be globally unique within Azure. This means that across all Azure subscriptions, no two storage accounts can have the same name. Each storage account name forms part of a unique URL, and this uniqueness requirement is enforced to ensure that the URL for each storage account is unique and can be resolved without ambiguity.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 418,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor provides personalized recommendations. (Y/N)\n- Azure Advisor can provide cost recommendations for virtual machines. (Y/N)\n- Azure Advisor can provide recommendations across multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Azure Advisor provides personalized recommendations to help optimize your Azure resources and improve the performance, security, and reliability of your workloads.\nThe recommendations provided by Azure Advisor are personalized to your specific usage patterns and resource configurations, taking into account factors such as the size and complexity of your environment, your usage patterns, and your business goals. This ensures that the recommendations are relevant and actionable, and can help you improve the efficiency and effectiveness of your Azure deployments.\n\nSome examples of the recommendations provided by Azure Advisor include optimizing virtual machine sizes to reduce costs, enabling security features such as Azure Security Center, improving network performance by optimizing network security groups, and reducing downtime by setting up automated backups.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 419,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can assign an Azure policy to a virtual machine. (Y/N)\n- If an Azure policy is assigned to a resource group, noncompliant resources are removed from the group. (Y/N)\n- If an Azure policy is assigned to a resource group, only compliant resources can be deployed to the group. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "1. Yes. \"Azure Policies can be set at each level, enabling you to set policies on a specific resource, resource group, subscription, and so on\".\n\n2. No. \"In some cases, Azure Policy can automatically remediate noncompliant resources and configurations to ensure the integrity of the state of the resources. [...] However, you still retain full control of your environment.\"\n\n3. Yes. \"For example, if you define a policy that allows only a certain size for the virtual machines (VMs) to be used in your environment, that policy is invoked when you create a new VM and whenever you resize existing VMs.\"",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 420,
        "Question": "You have on-premises servers that run Windows Server.\nWhat should you implement to manage the servers by using the Azure portal?\nA. Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)\nB. Azure Arc\nC. Docker\nD. role-based access control (RBAC)",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Arc allows us to extend Azure management and governance capabilities to your on-premises and multi-cloud environments. By implementing Azure Arc, we can connect your Windows Server machines to Azure and manage them centrally through the Azure portal, alongside your other Azure resources.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 421,
        "Question": "You can use [\u2026] in Azure to send email alerts when the cost of the current billing period for an Azure subscription exceeds a specified limit.\nA. Advisor recommendations\nB. Access control (IAM)\nC. Budget alerts\nD. Compliance",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Indeed, budget alerts",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 422,
        "Question": "If Windows Server or Microsoft SQL Server licenses are covered by [\u2026] you can repurpose the licenses.\nA. an End User License Agreement (EULA) on Azure virtual machines.\nB. Microsoft Lifecycle Policy\nC. Software Assurance",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "For customers with Software Assurance or subscription licenses, Azure Hybrid Benefit for Windows Server allows you to use your on-premises Windows Server licenses to get Windows virtual machines on Azure at a reduced cost. You can use Azure Hybrid Benefit for Windows Server to deploy new virtual machines with Windows OS. ",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 423,
        "Question": "You have a web app that runs in Azure.\nYou need to identify the amount of time it takes for web pages to load in a user's browser.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Monitor alerts\nB. Application Insights in Azure Monitor\nC. Log Analytics\nD. Azure Network Watcher",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Application Insights is a feature of Azure Monitor that allows to monitor running applications, automatically detect performance anomalies, and use built-in analytics tools to see what users do on an app.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 424,
        "Question": "[\u2026] ensures access to cloud resources in the event of a service failure.\nA. High availability\nB. Predictability\nC. Reliability\nD. Scalability",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "'High Availability' is correct.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 425,
        "Question": "What should a desktop application use to interact with Azure and manage resources?\nA. APIs\nB. Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates\nC. Azure Command-Line Interface (CLI)\nD. Azure Cloud Shell",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Key is Desktop Applications which need to interact with Azure resources in a programmatical way, so APIs.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 426,
        "Question": "A. Agility\nB. Elasticity\nC. Disaster recovery\n1. The ability to dynamically scale the resources available to a cloud app\n2. The ability to use cloud-based backup services to restore resources in the event of an outage\n3. The ability to quickly deploy and configure cloud-based resources as app requirements change",
        "Answer": "A3C2B1",
        "Explanation": "Agility: Refers to the ability to quickly adapt and respond to changes. In cloud computing, this translates to rapidly deploying and scaling resources based on application needs.\nElasticity : Specifically refers to the ability to dynamically adjust resources (like processing power or storage) up or down as demand fluctuates.\nDisaster recovery: Focuses on recovering resources and data after an outage or disaster. While crucial, it doesn't directly address dynamic scaling or rapid deployment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 427,
        "Question": "A. MFA\nB. Software updates an patches\nC. Surveillance camera\n1. Compute\n2. Identity and access\n3. Physical security",
        "Answer": "B1A2C3",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B1A2C3.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABC123"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 428,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The Hot access tier is available for blob data that uses standard storage. (Y/N)\n- The Cool access tier is available for file shares in premium storage. (Y/N)\n- The Cool access tier can be configured at the storage account level. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is YNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 429,
        "Question": "Which two features or services can be integrated with Azure Monitor? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nA. Azure status\nB. Application Insights\nC. Azure Advisor\nD. Log Analytics\nE. Azure Service Health",
        "Answer": "BD",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft combined three unique services\u2014Azure Monitor, Log Analytics, and Application Insights\u2014under the umbrella of Azure Monitor to provide powerful end-to-end monitoring of your applications and the components they rely on. Log Analytics and Application Insights are now features of Azure Monitor.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 430,
        "Question": "What provides a unified way to project and manage non-Azure resources in Azure Resource Manager (ARM)?\n\nA. Azure Migrate\nB. Azure AD Connect\nC. Azure Arc\nD. Azure Front Door",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Key word: Unified",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 431,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- AzCopy is a command-line utility used to copy blobs or files to or from a storage account. (Y/N)\n- Azure Storage Explorer is a cloud-hosted migration service used to transfer large amounts of data. (Y/N)\n- Azure File Sync syncs files and folders between Azure Files and Windows file servers. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "AzCopy is a command-line utility that you can use to copy blobs or files to or from a storage account.\n\nMicrosoft Azure Storage Explorer is a standalone app that makes it easy to work with Azure Storage data on Windows, macOS, and Linux.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 432,
        "Question": "[\u2026] is a physical migration service used to transfer large amounts of data in a quick, temporary, and reliable way?\nA. Azure Data Box\nB. Azure Databricks\nC. Azure File Sync\nD. Azure Migrate",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "The Microsoft Azure Data Box cloud solution lets you send terabytes of data into and out of Azure in a quick, inexpensive, and reliable way.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 433,
        "Question": "Your company has an Azure subscription and three business units.\nYou plan to deploy new resources for each business unit.\nYou need to ensure that the new resources are deployed by using a repeatable and reliable method that applies the same configurations to each resource.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Policy\nB. Azure Arc\nC. a resource group\nD. Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "D. Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 434,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- ExpressRoute uses Border Gateway Protocol (BGP). (Y/N)\n- ExpressRoute uses the internet to connect an on-premises network to Azure. (Y/N)\n- You can configure multiple ExpressRoute circuits to connect an on-premises datacenter to Azure. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Dynamic routing between your network and Microsoft via BGP.\nYes, it is possible. You can link a single virtual network with up to four ExpressRoute circuits in the same location or up to 16 ExpressRoute circuits in different peering locations.\nExpressRoutes don't go over the internet, hence ExpressRoute.\nRather, it is strongly recommended that customers setup at least two ExpressRoute circuits to avoid single points of failure",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 435,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Arc can manage physical servers that run Linux. (Y/N)\n- Azure Arc can manage Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) clusters at scale. (Y/N)\n- Azure Arc can manage a third-party database solution hosted outside of Azure. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNN",
        "Explanation": "1. Azure Arc can manage physical servers that run Linux. Yes (Y)\n2. Azure Arc can manage Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) clusters at scale. No (N)\n3. Azure Arc can manage a third-party database solution hosted outside of Azure. No (N)",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 436,
        "Question": "[\u2026] extends Azure compliance and monitoring to hybrid and multicloud configurations.\nA. Azure AD Connect \nB. Azure Arc\nC. Azure Front Door \nD. Azure Policy",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Azure Arc is the answer",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 437,
        "Question": "In the software as a service (SaaS) cloud service, which responsibility is shared between Microsoft and the customer?\nA. identity and directory infrastructure management\nB. application management\nC. information and data management\nD. operating system updates",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "If you check shared responsibility model, you can see that for SaaS:\nIdentity and Directory Infrastructure Management = responsibility SHARED between Microsoft and customer\nInformation and Data = only Customer responsiblity!",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 438,
        "Question": "Where does Azure Monitor store event data?\nA. an Azure Blob Storage account\nB. Azure Storage Queue\nC. Azure SQL Database\nD. a Log Analytics workspace",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Azure Monitor stores event data in a Log Analytics workspace. This is a unique environment for Azure Monitor log data, where you can use Log Analytics to analyze collected data across sources. Each workspace has its own data repository and configuration, and data sources and solutions are configured to store their data in a workspace.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 439,
        "Question": "You deploy an Azure resource. The resource becomes unavailable for an extended period due to a service outage. Microsoft will [...].\nA. refund your bank account.\nB. migrate the resource to another subscription.\nC. credit your Azure account.\nD. send you a coupon code that you can redeem for Azure credits",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Microsoft will credit your Azure account, but not automatically. You must ask for it. Still C is the best option.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 440,
        "Question": "When planning to migrate a public website to Azure, you must plan to [\u2026].\nA. deploy a VPN. \nB. pay monthly usage costs.\nC. pay to transfer all the website data to Azure.\nD. reduce the number of connections to the website.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ANBCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 441,
        "Question": "If a resource group named RG1 has a delete lock [...] can delete RG1.\nA. only a member of the global administrators group\nB. the delete lock must be removed before an administrator\nC. an Azure policy must be modified before an administrator\nD. an Azure tag must be added before an administrator ",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "You can configure a lock on a resource group to prevent the accidental deletion of the resource group. The lock applies to everyone, including global administrators. If you want to delete the resource group, the lock must be removed first.\nAs an administrator, you may need to lock a subscription, resource group, or resource to prevent other users in your organization from accidentally deleting or modifying critical resources. You can set the lock level to CanNotDelete or ReadOnly. In the portal, the locks are called Delete and Read-only respectively.\n- CanNotDelete means authorized users can still read and modify a resource, but they can't delete the resource.\nReadOnly means authorized users can read a resource, but they can't delete or update the resource. Applying this lock is similar to restricting all authorized\n users to the permissions granted by the Reader role.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 442,
        "Question": "[\u2026] a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the Azure environment.\nA. Azure policies provide\nB. Resource groups provide\nC. Azure Resource Manager templates provide \nD. Management groups provide",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure policies provide a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the Azure environment.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 443,
        "Question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nWhich three computers can run the script? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a computer that runs Windows 11 and has the Azure CLI tools installed\nB. a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure CLI tools installed\nC. a computer that runs macOS and has PowerShell Core 6.0 installed\nD. a computer that runs Chrome OS and uses Azure Cloud Shell\nE. a computer that runs Windows 10 and has the Azure PowerShell module installed",
        "Answer": "ADE",
        "Explanation": "A: Windows PC has already powershell installed + Azure tools > valid\nD: Azure cloud shell supports both powershell and bash scripts > valid\nE: Windows PC already has powershell + azure module for powershell is installed > valid\nnot B: Linux computer has azure modules installed but for CLI not for powershell > invalid\nnot C: MacOS has powershell installed but azure modules for powershell is not > invalid",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 444,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure AD requires domain controllers on Azure virtual machines. (Y/N)\n- Azure AD provides authentication services for Azure and Microsoft 365. (Y/N)\n- Each user account in Azure AD can be assigned only one Microsoft 365 license. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NYN.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 445,
        "Question": "In the infrastructure as a service (IaaS) cloud service model, which two components are the responsibility of the cloud service provider? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. the configuration and maintenance of storage\nB. the installation and configuration of the operating system\nC. maintaining the hardware\nD. the network configuration\nE. physical security of the datacenter infrastructure",
        "Answer": "CE",
        "Explanation": "C. maintaining the hardware\nE. physical security of the datacenter infrastructure",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCDE"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 446,
        "Question": "The Cool access tier is optimized [...].\nA. for data that is accessed infrequently and stored for at least 30 days. \nB. for data that is accessed rarely, is stored for at least 180 days, and has flexible latency requirements.\nC. for storing data that is accessed frequently.",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Cool tier - An online tier optimized for storing data that is infrequently accessed or modified. Data in the cool tier should be stored for a minimum of 30 days. The cool tier has lower storage costs and higher access costs compared to the hot tier.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 447,
        "Question": "[\u2026] provides a health overview of Azure services and regions.\nA. Azure Monitor.\nB. Azure Resource Health\nC. Azure Service Health \nD. Azure status",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "Azure Service Health should be correct answer, because:\nAzure Status = status of Azure globally\nAzure Service Health = View of Azure services and regions you are using [services and regions keywords!]\nResource Health = Tailored view of your actual Azure resources",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 448,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- For the platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service, updating the operating system is the responsibility of the customer. (Y/N)\n- For the infrastructure as a service (laaS) cloud service, network control is the responsibility of Microsoft. (Y/N)\n- For the software as a service (SaaS) cloud service, identity management is a shared responsibility between the customer and Microsoft. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 449,
        "Question": "When using [\u2026] you can group VM into an update domain or a fault domain.\nA. availability sets\nB. availability zones\nC. Azure Load Balancer\nD. Azure VM scale sets",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "Availability sets are logical groupings of VMs that reduce the chance of correlated failures bringing down related VMs at the same time. Availability sets place VMs in different fault domains for better reliability, especially beneficial if a region doesn't support availability zones.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 450,
        "Question": "You have an Azure Storage account named storage1.\nYou need to ensure that containers can be created in, but not deleted from, storage1.\nWhat should you do?\nA. Create a ReadOnly lock for storage1.\nB. Create a delete lock for storage1.\nC. Enable container soft delete.\nD. Enable blob soft delete.",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "B. Create a delete lock for storage1.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 451,
        "Question": "You have an Azure subscription.\nYou need to use Azure Cloud Shell to run a deployment script.\nWhat should you use to access Cloud Shell?\nA. Azure Resource Manager (ARM)\nB. Microsoft Visual Studio\nC. a Windows command prompt\nD. a web browser",
        "Answer": "D",
        "Explanation": "Web browser",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABCD"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 452,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Adding more RAM to a virtual machine is an example of Horizontal scaling. (Y/N)\n- Adding an additional virtual machine based upon demand is an example of Vertical scaling. (Y/N)\n- Horizontal scaling can occur automatically or manually. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 453,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Creating and configuring a virtual network is part of the platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service model. (Y/N)\n- In the platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service model, updating code for an Azure web app is the customer's responsibility. (Y/N)\n- Configuring user access to a platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service model is the customer's responsibility. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 454,
        "Question": "You need to migrate an on-premises server by using a lift-and-shift migration.\nTo which type of cloud service should you migrate?\nA. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nB. software as a service (SaaS)\nC. platform as a service (PaaS)",
        "Answer": "A",
        "Explanation": "IaaS",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 455,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Only one tag can be assigned to an Azure resource. (Y/N)\n- Tags can be assigned to Azure resources by using Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. (Y/N)\n- Tags can be used to enforce naming standards for Azure resources. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NYN",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NYN.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 456,
        "Question": "evaluates signals to allow or deny sign-ins to Azure AD.[\u2026].\nA. A managed identity\nB. Conditional Access\nC. Microsoft Intune",
        "Answer": "B",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 457,
        "Question": "A. Azure App Service\nB. Azure Container\nC. Azure Functions\nD. Azure Virtual Machine Scale Sets\n1. Provides software emulation of a physical computer.\n2. Provides operating system virtualization.",
        "Answer": "B1D2",
        "Explanation": "Answer is B1D2.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "draganddrop",
        "Choices": "ABCD12"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 458,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor supports alerts. (Y/N)\n- Azure Advisor recommendations can be filtered by Administrative unit. (Y/N)\n- Azure Advisor provides recommendations on improving the performance of resources. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is YNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 459,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You must install Azure Cloud Shell on your computer before you can use it. (Y/N)\n- The Azure Command-Line Interface (CLI) is installed by default in Windows 11. (Y/N)\n- Azure PowerShell can be used on computers that run Windows, Linux, or macOS. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "NNY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 460,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- The Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) Calculator displays the cost of running workloads in a datacenter. (Y/N)\n- The Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) Calculator displays the cost of running workloads in Azure. (Y/N)\n- The Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) Calculator generates graphical reports. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYY",
        "Explanation": "Answer is YYY.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 461,
        "Question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Network security groups (NSGs) can contain multiple inbound and outbound security rules. (Y/N)\n- A VM that performs a particular function such as running a firewall is also called a Network virtual appliance. (Y/N)\n- A user-defined route (UDR) can only control network traffic between subnets of a single virtual network. (Y/N)",
        "Answer": "YYN",
        "Explanation": "Answer is YYN.",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "hotspot",
        "Choices": "YN"
    },
    {
        "QuestionID": 462,
        "Question": "Microsoft 365 is an example of which cloud service model?\nA. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nB. platform as a service (PaaS)\nC. software as a service (SaaS)",
        "Answer": "C",
        "Explanation": "SaaS",
        "Counter": 0,
        "CertifCode": "az-900",
        "QuestionType": "multiplechoice",
        "Choices": "ABC"
    }
]